<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral</align>
  <description>Бог благословенной мудрости</description>
  <ethos></ethos>
  <flags>cult</flags>
  <help id="982" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <text l="en">{CAhuramazda{x is the all-knowing creator dwelling in endless light, and the giver of all that is good. Ahuramazda is depicted in the image of the Faravahar -- a winged guardian angel in a tall hat with a full beard. In his infinite wisdom he inspires the righteous and punishes the wicked. Followers of the cult of Ahuramazda believe that daily struggle against evil in this world is not enough -- the day of the Last Judgment, Frashkard, will come, when the Great One shall transform the world and cleanse it of corruption once and for all.

%A% =Paths:= {WLight{x, {BReason{x
%A% =Gifts:= in battle the mark of Ahuramazda grants you {hh711inspiration{x, {hh758banishes evil{x
and {hh794dispels{x demons and undead.
%A% =Restrictions:= only the {hh33non-evil{x 
%A% =Sacrifices:= Ahuramazda prefers magical items with spells
  of healing and blessing. Will be pleased by the corpse of a non-good creature.

After the fall of {hh1837Thalos{x the cult of Ahuramazda gained special power -- his prophets can be found in {hh1838New Thalos{x to this day.

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CАхурамазда{x -- всеведущий творец, пребывающий в бесконечном свете, и податель всего благого. Ахурамазду изображают в образе Фаравахара -- крылатого ангела-хранителя в высокой шапке и с окладистой бородой. В своей бесконечной мудрости он вдохновляет праведников и карает нечестивцев. Последователи культа Ахурамазды верят, что ежедневной борьбы со злом в этом мире недостаточно -- наступит день Страшного Суда, Фрашкард, когда Великий преобразит мир и окончательно очистит его от скверны.

%A% =Пути:= {WСвет{x, {BРазум{x
%A% =Дары:= в бою знак Ахурамазды дарует тебе {hh711воодушевление{x, {hh758изгоняет зло{x
и {hh794развоплощает{x демонов и нежить.
%A% =Ограничения:= только {hh33не-злые{x 
%A% =Жертвоприношения:= Ахурамазда предпочитает волшебные предметы с заклинаниями
  излечения и благословения. Обрадуется трупу не-доброго существа.

После гибели {hh1837Талоса{x культ Ахурамазды обрел особую силу -- его пророков можно найти в {hh1838Новом Талосе{x и по сей день.

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CАхурамазда{x -- всезнаючий творець, що перебуває в нескінченному світлі, і подавець усього доброго. Ахурамазду зображують в образі Фаравахара -- крилатого ангела-охоронця у високому капелюсі з окладистою бородою. У своїй нескінченній мудрості він надихає праведників і карає нечестивців. Послідовники культу Ахурамазди вірять, що щоденної боротьби зі злом у цьому світі недостатньо -- настане день Страшного Суду, Фрашкард, коли Великий перетворить світ і остаточно очистить його від скверни.

%A% =Шляхи:= {WСвітло{x, {BРозум{x
%A% =Дари:= у бою знак Ахурамазди дарує тобі {hh711наснагу{x, {hh758виганяє зло{x
та {hh794розвіює{x демонів і нежить.
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки {hh33не-злі{x 
%A% =Жертвоприношення:= Ахурамазда надає перевагу чарівним предметам із заклинаннями
  зцілення та благословення. Зрадіє трупу не-доброї істоти.

Після загибелі {hh1837Талосу{x культ Ахурамазди набув особливої сили -- його пророків можна знайти в {hh1838Новому Талосі{x і досі.

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
    <skillGroups registry="skillGroup">healing benedictions</skillGroups>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Ахурамазд|а|ы|е|у|ой|е</nameRus>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Ahuramazda</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27302</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
