<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <clans registry="clan">none flowers lion battlerager knight chaos ruler invader ghost hunter</clans>
  <description>Богиня оглушающего боевого клича</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <flags>cult</flags>
  <help id="1575" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <keyword l="en">alala</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">алала</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CAlala{x is the goddess of the deafening battle cry that inspires warriors to courage and great deeds in combat. Alala keeps her distance from her mad uncle {hh966Ares{x, god of war and bloodshed -- his companions repel her, and her chief mission is to help warriors across the world find bravery and overcome fear. Alala is depicted as a young female warrior with an encouraging smile on her lips, and the followers of her cult wander the expanse of Thera teaching the art of the battle cry.

%A% =Paths:= {RFury{x
%A% =Gifts:= in battle Alala's tattoo will let out a particularly mighty {hh860battle cry{x, which
can sometimes {hh606stun{x your enemies
%A% =Sacrifices:= Alala will be pleased by any weapon.
  
Alala's companions were last seen beyond the northern plains, in a small town called {hh1860Ofcol{x.

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CАлала{x -- богиня оглушительного боевого клича, вдохновляющего воинов на храбрость и подвиги в сражении. Алала держится в стороне от своего безумного дяди {hh966Ареса{x, бога войны и кровопролития, ей отвратительны его спутники, и ее главная миссия -- помочь воинам по всему миру обрести отвагу и победить страх. Алалу изображают в виде молодой воительницы с ободряющей улыбкой на устах, а последователи ее культа странствуют по просторам Тэры, обучая искусству боевого клича.

%A% =Пути:= {RЯрость{x
%A% =Дары:= в бою татуировка Алалы издаст особо мощный {hh860боевой клич{x, который
иногда способен {hh606оглушать{x твоих противников
%A% =Жертвоприношения:= Алала обрадуется любому оружию.
  
Последний раз спутников Алалы видели за равнинами Севера, в маленьком городке под названием {hh1860Офкол{x.

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CАлала{x -- богиня оглушливого бойового кличу, що надихає воїнів на хоробрість і подвиги в битві. Алала тримається осторонь від свого шаленого дядька {hh966Ареса{x, бога війни та кровопролиття -- його супутники їй огидні, і її головна місія -- допомогти воїнам по всьому світу знайти відвагу та здолати страх. Алалу зображують у вигляді молодої воїтельки з підбадьорливою усмішкою на вустах, а послідовники її культу мандрують просторами Тери, навчаючи мистецтву бойового кличу.

%A% =Шляхи:= {RЯрість{x
%A% =Дари:= у бою татуювання Алали видасть особливо потужний {hh860бойовий клич{x, який
іноді здатен {hh606оглушити{x твоїх противників
%A% =Жертвоприношення:= Алала зрадіє будь-якій зброї.
  
Останнього разу супутників Алали бачили за рівнинами Півночі, у маленькому містечку під назвою {hh1860Офкол{x.

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items>weapon recipe</items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Алал|а|ы|е|у|ой|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Алал|а|и|і|у|ою|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <sex>female</sex>
  <shortDescr>Alala</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27319</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
