<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes registry="profession">thief samurai warrior necromancer ranger cleric witch anti-paladin ninja paladin warlock vampire</classes>
  <description>Верховный бог Общества, покровитель следопытов</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <help id="1582" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <keyword l="en">allanon</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">алланон</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CAllanon{x -- god-ranger, the legendary leader of the ancient {hh1494Mercenaries{x. He is usually depicted as a slender youth bent over the ground, carefully studying tracks invisible to others. It is said that Allanon was so captivated by the process of {hh640tracking{x that he did not care much about the Mercenaries' material well-being and often forgot to demand payment for his services. Fortunately, subsequent generations of Mercenaries corrected his regrettable oversight. Allanon is patron of the {hh140ranger{x class and the shaggy race of born trackers, the {hh167dogboys{x. 

%A% =Paths:= {YSociety{x (supreme god)
%A% =Gifts:= Allanon's mark will let you instantly {hh925return{x to your mortal
{x body upon death, sometimes accelerate the {hh640tracking{x process by transporting you to the target, {x and in battle will briefly {hh1108sharpen your vision{x and grant the ability of {hh590woodland combat{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x, {hh80epochs{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CАлланон{x -- бог-следопыт, легендарный лидер {hh1494Наемников{x древности. Его обычно изображают в виде субтильного юноши, склонившегося над землей и тщательно изучающего незримые прочим следы. Говорят, что Алланона настолько захватывал процесс {hh640следопытства{x, что он не очень заботился о материальном благополучии Наемников и частенько забывал потребовать плату за свои услуги. К счастью, последующие поколения Наемников исправили его досадное упущение. Алланон покровительствует сословию {hh140рейнджеров{x и мохнатой расе прирожденных следопытов, {hh167челобак{x. 

%A% =Пути:= {YОбщество{x (верховный бог)
%A% =Дары:= знак Алланона позволит тебе мгновенно {hh925перенестись{x к своему бренному
{x телу в случае смерти, иногда ускорит процесс {hh640слежки{x, перенося тебя к цели, {x а в бою ненадолго {hh1108обострит твое зрение{x и дарует способность {hh590лесного боя{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x, {hh80эпохи{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CАлланон{x -- бог-слідопит, легендарний лідер {hh1494Найманців{x давнини. Його зазвичай зображують у вигляді субтильного юнака, що схилився над землею і уважно вивчає сліди, незримі для інших. Кажуть, що Алланона настільки захоплював процес {hh640слідопитства{x, що він не дуже дбав про матеріальне благополуччя Найманців і часто забував вимагати плату за свої послуги. На щастя, наступні покоління Найманців виправили його прикре упущення. Алланон покровительствує стану {hh140рейнджерів{x і мохнатій расі природжених слідопитів, {hh167чолобак{x. 

%A% =Шляхи:= {YСуспільство{x (верховний бог)
%A% =Дари:= знак Алланона дозволить тобі миттєво {hh925повернутися{x до свого бренного
{x тіла у разі смерті, іноді прискорить процес {hh640слідкування{x, переносячи тебе до цілі, {x а у бою ненадовго {hh1108загострить твій зір{x і дарує здатність {hh590лісового бою{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x, {hh80епохи{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Алланон||а|у|а|ом|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Алланон||а|у|а|ом|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsClans registry="clan">hunter</patronsClans>
  <patronsClasses registry="profession">ranger</patronsClasses>
  <patronsRaces registry="race">mawg</patronsRaces>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Allanon</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27334</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
