<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <clans registry="clan">none flowers lion battlerager knight chaos ruler invader ghost hunter</clans>
  <description>Неистовый бог войны и кровопролития</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <flags>cult</flags>
  <help id="966" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <text l="en">{CAres{x is the fierce god of the chaos of war and mad bloodshed, the avatar of battle fury and might. Unlike his sister {hh965Athena,{x goddess of clever warfare, Ares prefers war that is treacherous and bloody -- war for its own sake. In the battles of Ares he is often accompanied by his associates, the gods {hh978Phobos{x and {hh986Deimos,{x fear and dread. Followers of his cult depict Ares as a huge half-naked warrior with eyes burning with fury and a bloodied spear in his mighty hands. Ares is patron of the fierce race of {hh163urukhai{x.

%A% =Paths:= {RFury{x
%A% =Gifts:= in battle the mark of Ares will send you into a state of {hh829battle fury{x, and will also
  briefly increase damage at the cost of defensive skills
%A% =Restrictions:= only the {hh39strongest{x
%A% =Sacrifices:= Ares likes to receive good weapons as sacrifice.
  Of drinks, prefers wines.

By tradition, adepts of Ares make pilgrimages to Mount {hh1864Olympus{x, where the god of war was last seen.

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CАрес{x -- неистовый бог хаоса войны и безумного кровопролития, аватар боевой ярости и мощи. В отличие от своей сестры {hh965Афины,{x богини умной войны, Арес предпочитает войну коварную и кровавую, войну ради самой войны. В битвах Ареса часто сопровождают его сообщники, боги {hh978Фобос{x и {hh986Деймос,{x страх и ужас. Последователи его культа изображают Ареса в виде огромного полуобнаженного воина с горящими от ярости очами и окровавленным копьем в могучих руках. Покровительствует Арес неистовой расе {hh163урукхаев{x.

%A% =Пути:= {RЯрость{x
%A% =Дары:= в бою знак Ареса введет тебя в состояние {hh829боевой ярости{x, а также
  ненадолго усилит повреждения в ущерб навыкам обороны
%A% =Ограничения:= только самые {hh39сильные{x
%A% =Жертвоприношения:= Арес любит, когда ему в жертву приносят хорошее оружие.
  Из напитков предпочитает вина.

По традиции, адепты Ареса совершают паломничества на гору {hh1864Олимп{x, где бога войны видели в последний раз.

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CАрес{x -- шалений бог хаосу війни та безумного кровопролиття, аватар бойової ярості та потужі. На відміну від своєї сестри {hh965Афіни,{x богині розумної війни, Арес надає перевагу війні підступній і кривавій -- війні заради самої війни. У битвах Ареса часто супроводжують його спільники, боги {hh978Фобос{x та {hh986Деймос,{x страх і жах. Послідовники його культу зображують Ареса у вигляді величезного напівголого воїна з палаючими від ярості очима та закривавленим списом у могутніх руках. Арес покровительствує шаленій расі {hh163урукхаїв{x.

%A% =Шляхи:= {RЯрість{x
%A% =Дари:= у бою знак Ареса введе тебе в стан {hh829бойової ярості{x, а також
  ненадовго посилить пошкодження на шкоду вмінням оборони
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки найбільш {hh39сильні{x
%A% =Жертвоприношення:= Арес любить, коли йому в жертву приносять хорошу зброю.
  З напоїв надає перевагу винам.

За традицією, адепти Ареса здійснюють паломництва на гору {hh1864Олімп{x, де бога війни бачили востаннє.

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items>weapon recipe</items>
    <liquidFlags>wine</liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <minstat>
    <str>22</str>
  </minstat>
  <nameRus>Арес||а|у|а|ом|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Арес||а|у|а|ом|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsRaces registry="race">urukhai</patronsRaces>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Ares</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27318</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
