<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes registry="profession">thief samurai warrior necromancer ranger cleric witch druid anti-paladin ninja paladin warlock vampire</classes>
  <description>Верховная богиня фауны и тварей бессловесных</description>
  <ethos>neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <help id="1580" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <keyword l="en">cradya</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">крадя</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CKradya{x -- supreme goddess of fauna and all mute creatures, patron of {hh151centaurs{x, the {hh1456Lion Pride{x, and the {hh2097Circle of Chaos{x all at once. Here is what the legends say of her birth and life: &quot;One warm winter morning a {hh159satyr{x was born. Her mother didn't make it to the satyr maternity ward, so the satyr had to be born in a puddle of beer. And the taste of mother's milk was improved by the puddle. She grew up a very obedient horned girl, excelling at biology and brewing. And on quiet moonlit nights she would go to the zoo. On the way she encountered {hh144vampires{x. She would whack them over the head with plastic bottles. They would yelp and not bite her. Because she had no blood in her. Only beer. When she arrived at the zoo, she would leap on the hippos and pour beer down the elephants. Then the elephants would make a ruckus in the morning. And the keepers would wonder. What's gotten into them. Life passed her by, merrily. And she died as she had always dreamed -- in a single day. From cirrhosis of the liver. Like a true satyr worthy of her life. And ended up in the satyr paradise-{hh92wishlist{x.&quot;

%A% =Paths:= {gNature{x (supreme goddess), {MChaos{x
%A% =Gifts:= Kradya's mark will teach you to heal yourself with beer and wine, and in battle will lend
{x extra strength to your {hh15pet{x and cause {hh909tongues to stumble{x {x -- your foe's or your own, however it turns out!
%A% =Restrictions:= only {hh30non-lawful{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x, {hh80epochs{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CКрадя{x -- верховная богиня фауны и тварей бессловесных, покровительница {hh151кентавров{x, {hh1456Прайда Львов{x и {hh2097Круга Хаоса{x одновременно. Вот что говорят о ее рождении и жизни легенды: &quot;Однажды теплым зимним утром родилась {hh159сатира{x. Ее мама не добежала до сатирского роддома, и поэтому сатире пришлось родиться в луже пива. И вкус материнского молока был улучшен лужей. Она росла очень послушной рогатой девочкой, успевала в предметах биологии и пивоварения. А тихими лунными ночами она ходила в зоопарк. По дороге она встречала {hh144вампиров{x. Она огревала их пластиковыми бутылками по голове. Они ойкали и не кусали ее. Потому что в ней не было крови. Только пиво. Когда она приходила в зоопарк, она прыгала на бегемотах и поила слонов пивом. Потом слоны поутру буянили. А смотрители удивлялись. Чего это они. Жизнь ее проходила мимо и весело. И умерла она как мечтала -- в один день. От цирроза печени. Как настоящая и достойная своей жизни сатира. И попала в сатирский рай-{hh92визлист{x.&quot;

%A% =Пути:= {gПрирода{x (верховная богиня), {MХаос{x
%A% =Дары:= знак Кради научит тебя лечиться пивом и вином, а в бою придаст
{x дополнительную силу твоему {hh15домашнему любимцу{x и заставит {hh909заплетаться языки{x {x -- противника или твой собственный, тут уж как получится!
%A% =Ограничения:= только {hh30не-законопослушные{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x, {hh80эпохи{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CКрадя{x -- верховна богиня фауни та безсловесних тварин, покровителька {hh151кентаврів{x, {hh1456Прайду Левів{x та {hh2097Кола Хаосу{x водночас. Ось що кажуть про її народження і життя легенди: &quot;Одного теплого зимового ранку народилася {hh159сатира{x. Її мама не добігла до сатирського пологового будинку, і тому сатирі довелось народитися в калюжі пива. І смак материнського молока був поліпшений калюжею. Вона росла дуже слухняною рогатою дівчинкою, встигала з біології та пивоваріння. А тихими місячними ночами ходила до зоопарку. По дорозі вона зустрічала {hh144вампірів{x. Вона гатила їх пластиковими пляшками по голові. Вони ойкали і не кусали її. Бо в ній не було крові. Тільки пиво. Коли вона приходила до зоопарку, вона стрибала на бегемотах і поїла слонів пивом. Потім слони вранці буянили. А доглядачі дивувались. Що це вони. Життя проходило повз неї і весело. І померла вона, як мріяла, -- за один день. Від цирозу печінки. Як справжня і гідна свого життя сатира. І потрапила до сатирського раю-{hh92вішліст{x.&quot;

%A% =Шляхи:= {gПрирода{x (верховна богиня), {MХаос{x
%A% =Дари:= знак Краді навчить тебе лікуватися пивом і вином, а у бою додасть
{x додаткової сили твоєму {hh15домашньому улюбленцю{x і змусить {hh909заплутуватись язики{x {x -- ворога або твій власний, як вже вийде!
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки {hh30не-законослухняні{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x, {hh80епохи{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Крад|я|и|е|ю|ей|е</nameRus>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsClans registry="clan">lion chaos</patronsClans>
  <patronsRaces registry="race">centaur</patronsRaces>
  <sex>female</sex>
  <shortDescr>Cradya</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27329</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
