<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>evil</align>
  <classes registry="profession">thief samurai warrior necromancer ranger cleric witch anti-paladin ninja paladin warlock vampire</classes>
  <description>Злобное божество демонов иных измерений</description>
  <ethos>chaotic</ethos>
  <flags>cult</flags>
  <help id="980" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <extra l="en">&apos;lesser demon&apos;</extra>
    <extra l="ru">&apos;клан демонов&apos; &apos;малый демон&apos;</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <keyword l="en">ehrumen</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">демоны эхрумен</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CEhrumen{x -- a malevolent deity of demons from other dimensions, existing in the eternal Void beyond the Gates of Chaos. Ehrumen is the embodiment of entropy striving to annihilate all that exists, and followers of his demonic cult sow chaos and make bloody sacrifices in the hope of one day reuniting with their Lord. The magic of demon summoning is incredibly difficult to master. Throughout the history of the world, a handful of demons were summoned and tamed only by the ancient archmages of {hh1479Shalafi{x and, of course, the great {hh1578Tananda{x.

%A% =Paths:= {MChaos{x, {DEvil{x
%A% =Gifts:= in battle Ehrumen's mark will scorch your enemies with the bloodthirsty fire
  of {hh642demons{x and summon you a mighty demon as a
  {hh15companion{x. The demon will not obey your {hh1091commands{x, but will shower
  your foes with combat spells of its own accord.
%A% =Restrictions:= {hh33chaotic evil{x only
%A% =Sacrifices:= Ehrumen prefers magical items with combat magic or 
  necromancy. Ehrumen likes when you sacrifice good weapons.
  A non-evil creature's corpse will please him.

They say that in the depths of {hh1854the Underdark{x there hides an enclave of Ehrumen's worshippers, still hatching terrible plans to conquer our world.

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CЭхрумен{x -- злобное божество демонов иных измерений, существующее в вечной Пустоте за Вратами Хаоса. Эхрумен -- воплощение энтропии, стремящейся изничтожить все сущее, и последователи его демонического культа сеют хаос и приносят кровавые жертвоприношения в надежде когда-нибудь воссоединиться со своим Господином. Магия призыва демонов неимоверно сложна для постижения. За всю историю мира горстку демонов удалось призвать и приручить лишь древним архимагам {hh1479Шалафи{x и, конечно же, Великой {hh1578Тананде{x.

%A% =Пути:= {MХаос{x, {DЗло{x
%A% =Дары:= в бою знак Эхрумена опалит твоих противников кровожадным огнем
  {hh642демонов{x и призовет тебе могучего демона в качестве
  {hh15помощника{x. Демон не послушается твоих {hh1091приказов{x, но зато сможет осыпать
  противников боевыми заклинаниями по собственному желанию.
%A% =Ограничения:= только {hh33хаотичные злые{x
%A% =Жертвоприношения:= Эхрумен предпочитает волшебные предметы с боевой магией или 
  некромантией. Эхрумену нравится, когда ему в жертву приносят хорошее оружие.
  Обрадуется трупу не-злого существа.

Говорят, что в глубинах {hh1854Подземья{x скрывается анклав поклонников Эхрумена, которые до сих пор вынашивают ужасные планы по завоеванию нашего мира.

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CЕхрумен{x -- злобне божество демонів інших вимірів, що існує у вічній Порожнечі за Брамою Хаосу. Ехрумен -- втілення ентропії, що прагне знищити все суще, а послідовники його демонічного культу сіють хаос і приносять криваві жертви у надії колись возз'єднатися зі своїм Господом. Магія виклику демонів неймовірно складна для опанування. За всю історію світу жменьку демонів вдалося викликати і приручити лише давнім архімагам {hh1479Шалафі{x і, звісно, великій {hh1578Тананді{x.

%A% =Шляхи:= {MХаос{x, {DЗло{x
%A% =Дари:= у бою знак Ехрумена опалить твоїх противників кровожерним вогнем
  {hh642демонів{x і покличе тобі могутнього демона в якості
  {hh15помічника{x. Демон не послухається твоїх {hh1091наказів{x, але зате зможе засипати
  противників бойовими заклинаннями за власним бажанням.
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки {hh33хаотичні злі{x
%A% =Жертвоприношення:= Ехрумен надає перевагу чарівним предметам із бойовою магією або 
  некромантією. Ехрумену подобається, коли йому в жертву приносять гарну зброю.
  Зрадіє трупу незлої істоти.

Кажуть, що в глибинах {hh1854Підземʼя{x ховається анклав поклонників Ехрумена, які досі виношують жахливі плани по завоюванню нашого світу.

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items>weapon recipe</items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
    <skillGroups registry="skillGroup">combat necromancy</skillGroups>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Эхрумен||а|у|а|ом|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Ехрумен||а|у|а|ом|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <sex>neutral</sex>
  <shortDescr>Ehrumen</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27327</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
