<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <description>Бог плотской любви и размножения</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <flags>cult</flags>
  <help id="972" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <text l="en">{CEros{x is the playful and flirtatious god of love and {hh1348sex,{x the embodiment of spring, renewal, and the exuberant procreation of all living things. Love knows no bounds -- Eros inspires men and women, goats and centaurs, brutish trolls and bearded dwarf ladies. In the Dreamland this god often accompanies many other gods and goddesses of the pantheon -- all those open to the call of spring and the body. His cult's devotees indulge in carnal pleasures wherever they please, and Eros is usually depicted as a smirking little angel with rosy cheeks and a plump bottom. 

%A% =Paths:= {gNature{x, {MChaos{x
%A% =Gifts:= in battle the mark of Eros will {hh657heal{x your wounds, and outside battle grants
  accelerated life regeneration -- and, incidentally, vulnerability to {hh729charm{x.
  And of course, Eros will strengthen your love {hh2025potions{x and {hh687charms{x.
%A% =Restrictions:= only the {hh35most charming{x {M&lt;3{x
%A% =Sacrifices:= Eros prefers magical items with spells
  of the wound-healing group. Of drinks, loves wines most of all.

Devotees of Eros's cult can be found everywhere -- love for one's neighbor even holds sway over {hh1866smurfs{x! 

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CЭрос{x -- игривый и кокетливый бог любви и {hh1348секса,{x воплощение весны, обновления и бурного размножения всего живого. Любовь не знает границ -- Эрос вдохновляет мужчин и женщин, козлов и кентавров, брутальных троллей и бородатых дварфинь. В Мире Мечты этот бог часто сопутствует многим другим богам и богиням пантеона -- всем, кто открыт зову весны и тела. Поклонники его культа предаются плотским утехам где попало, а изображают Эроса обычно в виде ехидного ангелочка с розовыми щечками и пухлой попкой. 

%A% =Пути:= {gПрирода{x, {MХаос{x
%A% =Дары:= в бою знак Эроса {hh657залечит{x твои раны, а вне боя дарует
  ускоренное восстановление жизни -- и, заодно, уязвимость к {hh729очарованию{x.
  И, разумеется, Эрос усилит твои любовные {hh2025зелья{x и {hh687чары{x.
%A% =Ограничения:= только самые {hh35симпатишные{x {M&lt;3{x
%A% =Жертвоприношения:= Эрос предпочитает волшебные предметы с заклинаниями
  группы лечения ран. Из напитков больше всего любит вина.

Поклонников культа Эроса можно найти повсюду -- любви к ближнему своему подвластны даже {hh1866смурфы{x! 

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CЕрос{x -- грайливий і кокетливий бог кохання та {hh1348сексу,{x втілення весни, оновлення та бурхливого розмноження всього живого. Любов не знає меж -- Ерос надихає чоловіків і жінок, кізок і кентаврів, брутальних тролів і бородатих дварфинь. У Світі Мрії цей бог часто супроводжує багатьох інших богів і богинь пантеону -- усіх, хто відкритий поклику весни та тіла. Поклонники його культу віддаються тілесним насолодам де попало, а Еросу зазвичай надають образу єхидного янголяти з рожевими щічками та пухлою сідницею. 

%A% =Шляхи:= {gПрирода{x, {MХаос{x
%A% =Дари:= у бою знак Еросу {hh657залікує{x твої рани, а поза боєм дарує
  прискорене відновлення життя -- і, до того ж, вразливість до {hh729зачарування{x.
  І, звісно, Ерос посилить твої любовні {hh2025зілля{x та {hh687чари{x.
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки найбільш {hh35симпатичні{x {M&lt;3{x
%A% =Жертвоприношення:= Ерос надає перевагу чарівним предметам із заклинаннями
  групи зцілення ран. З напоїв найбільше любить вина.

Поклонників культу Еросу можна знайти скрізь -- любов до ближнього підвладна навіть {hh1866смурфам{x! 

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags>wine</liquidFlags>
    <skillGroups registry="skillGroup">healing</skillGroups>
  </likes>
  <minstat>
    <cha>19</cha>
  </minstat>
  <nameRus>Эрос||а|у|а|ом|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Ерос||а|у|а|ом|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Eros</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27331</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
