<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes registry="profession">thief samurai warrior necromancer ranger cleric witch anti-paladin ninja warlock vampire</classes>
  <description>Жадный бог наживы и прибыли</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <help id="1583" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <keyword l="en">fili</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">фили</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CFili{x -- greedy god of {hh13money{x, profit, and gain, patron of {hh1056trade{x and the {hh146dwarf{x race. During the Third Epoch Fili served as treasurer and leader of the {hh1494Mercenaries{x Clan, multiplying their wealth and power beyond measure. Fili reformed the {hh1086banking system{x and created a single stable currency in use across all of Thera. He also launched a small and medium business lending program, allowing merchants across the world to run their trade better and avoid bankruptcy.

%A% =Paths:= {YSociety{x
%A% =Gifts:= Fili's mark will improve your {hh694trading skills{x, greatly reduce
{x the cost of healer services, double gold rewards from {hh125questors{x, triple the profit
{x from {hh1375sacrifices{x, and increase the chance and quality of {hh122random drops{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x, {hh80epochs{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CФили{x -- жадный бог {hh13денег{x, наживы и прибыли, покровитель {hh1056торговли{x и расы {hh146дварфов{x. Во времена Третьей Эпохи Фили служил казначеем и главой Клана {hh1494Наемников{x, вне всякой меры умножив их богатство и могущество. Фили изменил {hh1086банковскую систему{x и создал единую устойчивую валюту, действующую по всему простору Тэры. Также он запустил программу кредитования мелкого и среднего бизнеса, позволив торговцам по всему миру лучше вести бизнес и предотвращать банкротство.

%A% =Пути:= {YОбщество{x
%A% =Дары:= знак Фили улучшит твои {hh694навыки торговли{x, сильно удешевит
{x платные услуги лекарей, удвоит денежные награды от {hh125квесторов{x, утроит прибыль {x от {hh1375жертвоприношения{x, а также увеличит шанс и качество выпадающих {hh122рандомов{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x, {hh80эпохи{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CФілі{x -- жадібний бог {hh13грошей{x, наживи та прибутку, покровитель {hh1056торгівлі{x і раси {hh146дварфів{x. За часів Третьої Епохи Філі служив скарбником і головою Клану {hh1494Найманців{x, примноживши їхнє багатство і могутність понад міру. Філі реформував {hh1086банківську систему{x і створив єдину стійку валюту, що діє по всьому простору Тери. Також він запустив програму кредитування малого і середнього бізнесу, дозволивши торговцям по всьому світу краще вести справи і запобігати банкрутству.

%A% =Шляхи:= {YСуспільство{x
%A% =Дари:= знак Філі покращить твої {hh694навички торгівлі{x, значно здешевить
{x платні послуги лікарів, подвоїть грошові нагороди від {hh125кветорів{x, потроїть прибуток
{x від {hh1375жертвоприношення{x, а також збільшить шанс і якість {hh122рандомних випадань{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x, {hh80епохи{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Фили</nameRus>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsClans registry="clan">hunter</patronsClans>
  <patronsRaces registry="race">dwarf</patronsRaces>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Fili</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27335</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
