<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>evil</align>
  <classes registry="profession">ranger anti-paladin necromancer thief vampire witch warlock ninja paladin samurai warrior cleric</classes>
  <description>Бог всепоглощающей Тьмы</description>
  <ethos>lawful</ethos>
  <help id="1568" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <keyword l="en">hauzer</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">хаузер</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CHauser{x is the Prince of eternal and all-consuming Darkness, keeper of the dark law of Power, and patron of {hh138anti-paladins{x. At the dawn of this world he was among the first to lead the armies of Evil in the struggle against Light, and he remains to this day one of the patrons of the {hh1485Cabal of Conquerors.{x Hauser is usually depicted as a grim black knight with an enormous two-handed flamberge blade.

%A% =Paths:= {DDarkness{x, {wOrder{x
%A% =Gifts:= in battle the mark of Hauser will {hh606stun{x your enemies and bind
{x them in tough {hh852webbing{x
%A% =Restrictions:= only the {hh33lawful evil{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x, {hh80epochs{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CХаузер{x -- Князь извечной и всепоглощающей Тьмы, хранитель темного права Силы и покровитель {hh138анти-паладинов{x. На заре этого мира он одним из первых повел армии Зла на борьбу со Светом, и до сих пор остается одним из покровителей {hh1485Кабала Захватчиков.{x Хаузера обычно изображают в виде мрачного черного рыцаря с огромным двуручным клинком-фламбергом.

%A% =Пути:= {DТьма{x, {wПорядок{x
%A% =Дары:= в бою знак Хаузера {hh606оглушит{x твоих противников и скует
{x их крепкой {hh852паутиной{x
%A% =Ограничения:= только {hh33законопослушные злые{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x, {hh80эпохи{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CХаузер{x -- Князь вічної та всепоглинаючої Пітьми, охоронець темного права Сили та покровитель {hh138анти-паладинів{x. На зорі цього світу він одним із перших повів армії Зла в боротьбу зі Світлом, і досі залишається одним із покровителів {hh1485Кабалу Загарбників.{x Хаузера зазвичай зображують у вигляді похмурого чорного лицаря з величезним дворучним клинком-фламберком.

%A% =Шляхи:= {DПітьма{x, {wПорядок{x
%A% =Дари:= у бою знак Хаузера {hh606оглушить{x твоїх противників і скує
{x їх міцною {hh852павутиною{x
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки {hh33законослухняні злі{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x, {hh80епохи{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Хаузер||а|у|а|ом|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Хаузер||а|у|а|ом|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsClasses registry="profession">anti-paladin</patronsClasses>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Hauzer</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27305</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
