<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align></align>
  <classes registry="profession">vampire</classes>
  <description>Кровожадная богиня-покровительница вампиров</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <help id="1585" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <keyword l="en">karmina</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">кармина</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CKarmina{x is the bloodthirsty goddess-patron of the ancient order of {hh144vampires{x. Few mortals have survived an encounter with her; only one description from an ancient chronicle survives: "I see a skinny, flat-nosed, bald girl with a strange expression on her face. Clear blue eyes peer from under a high forehead adorned with a strange scar. She smiles, and I catch a glint on her even, slightly pointed fangs. The tattered shroud she is wrapped in is stained with dirt and blood all mixed together. And then she suddenly stretches out her arm, gives me the fig and runs off laughing. Or rather rides off... on skis?!?!"

%A% =Gifts:= the mark of Karmina will increase damage in vampire {hh836form{x, sate the {hh539thirst for blood{x and
  increase damage from the {hh552bone dagger{x, and will also allow
  you to sometimes drain blood for pure pleasure
%A% =Restrictions:= only {hh144vampires{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x, {hh80epochs{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CКармина{x -- кровожадная богиня-покровительница древнего сословия {hh144вампиров{x. Мало кто из смертных выжил после встречи с ней, сохранилось лишь одно описание из древней летописи: &quot;Я вижу худенькую, плосконосую и лысую девочку со странным выражением лица. Ясные голубые глаза глядят из-под высокого лба, на котором красуется странный шрам. Она улыбается, и я замечаю блик на ее ровных, слегка заостренных клыках. Рваный саван, в который она замотана, испачкан грязью и кровью вперемешку. И тут она внезапно вытягивает руку, показывает мне фигу и хохоча убегает. Точнее уезжает... на лыжах?!?!&quot;

%A% =Дары:= знак Кармины усилит урон в {hh836форме{x вампира, утолит {hh539жажду крови{x и
  увеличит повреждения от {hh552костяного кинжала{x, а также позволит
  иногда сосать кровь ради чистого удовольствия
%A% =Ограничения:= только {hh144вампиры{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x, {hh80эпохи{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CКарміна{x -- кровожерлива богиня-покровителька давнього стану {hh144вампірів{x. Мало хто зі смертних вижив після зустрічі з нею; збереглося лише один опис із давнього літопису: "Я бачу худеньку, плосконосу і лису дівчинку зі дивним виразом обличчя. Ясні блакитні очі дивляться з-під високого чола, на якому красується дивний шрам. Вона посміхається, і я помічаю відблиск на її рівних, злегка загострених іклах. Драний саван, у який вона загорнута, заплямований брудом і кровʼю вперемішку. І тут вона раптово простягає руку, показує мені дулю та реготом тікає. Точніше відʼїжджає... на лижах?!?!"

%A% =Дари:= знак Карміни посилить шкоду в {hh836формі{x вампіра, вгамує {hh539спрагу крові{x та
  збільшить пошкодження від {hh552кістяного кинджала{x, а також дозволить
  іноді ссати кров заради чистого задоволення
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки {hh144вампіри{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x, {hh80епохи{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Кармин|а|ы|е|у|ой|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Кармін|а|и|і|у|ою|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsClasses registry="profession">vampire</patronsClasses>
  <sex>female</sex>
  <shortDescr>Karmina</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27339</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
