<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes registry="profession">necromancer cleric witch anti-paladin warlock</classes>
  <description>Бог волшебного могущества и магического усиления</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral</ethos>
  <help id="1573" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <keyword l="en">mihail</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">михаил</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CMikhail{x -- god of magical might and arcane enhancement. Legend holds that Mikhail was the master of magic and leader of the {hh1479Shalafi{x Order during the Second Epoch of this world. In those times mages wielded enormous power, using magic solely to advance their own authority and well-being, bringing death and destruction to all living things. This exhausted the patience of the god {hh1584Tirna{x, who cast down the Tower of Shalafi and reduced it to ash. Yet in the memory of mortals Mikhail remained a truly awe-inspiring archmage. He is remembered as the creator of many powerful enchantments and spells that enhance the physical abilities of wizards. Mikhail is patron of {hh134sorcerers{x and the magical race of {hh155faeries.{x

%A% =Paths:= {BMind{x
%A% =Gifts:= Mikhail's mark will raise the level of your {hh1126teleportation magic{x and
{x {hh1111enhancement{x spells, and in battle will occasionally {hh918transform{x your body
%A% =Restrictions:= {hh30non-chaotic{x {hh134sorcerers{x, {hh139witches{x, {hh143necromancers{x, {hh133clerics{x and
{x {hh138anti-paladins{x only

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x, {hh80epochs{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CМихаил{x -- бог волшебного могущества и магического усиления. По легенде, Михаил был повелителем магии и лидером Ордена {hh1479Шалафи{x во Вторую Эпоху этого мира. В те времена маги обладали огромной силой, используя магию только для достижения собственной власти и благополучия, неся смерть и разрушение всему живому. Это переполнило чашу терпения бога {hh1584Тирны{x, и он низверг Башню Шалафи, обратив ее в пепел. Но в памяти смертных Михаил остался наводящим трепет архимагом. Его запомнили как создателя множества могущественных чар и заклятий, усиливающих телесные способности волшебников. Покровительствует Михаил {hh134колдунам{x и волшебной расе {hh155фей.{x

%A% =Пути:= {BРазум{x
%A% =Дары:= знак Михаила поднимет уровень твоей {hh1126транспортной магии{x и заклинаний
{x {hh1111усиления{x, а в бою изредка {hh918преобразит{x твое тело
%A% =Ограничения:= только {hh30не-хаотичные{x {hh134колдуны{x, {hh139ведьмы{x, {hh143некроманты{x, {hh133клерики{x и
{x {hh138анти-паладины{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x, {hh80эпохи{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CМихаїл{x -- бог чарівної могутності і магічного посилення. За легендою, Михаїл був повелителем магії і лідером Ордену {hh1479Шалафі{x в Другу Епоху цього світу. У ті часи маги мали величезну силу, використовуючи магію виключно для досягнення власної влади і добробуту, несучи смерть і руйнування всьому живому. Це переповнило чашу терпіння бога {hh1584Тирни{x, і він скинув Вежу Шалафі, перетворивши її на попіл. Але в памʼяті смертних Михаїл залишився справді грізним архімагом. Його памʼятають як творця безлічі могутніх чарів і заклинань, що посилюють тілесні здібності чаклунів. Покровительствує Михаїл {hh134чаклунам{x і чарівній расі {hh155фей.{x

%A% =Шляхи:= {BРозум{x
%A% =Дари:= знак Михаїла підніме рівень твоєї {hh1126транспортної магії{x і заклинань
{x {hh1111посилення{x, а у бою зрідка {hh918перетворить{x твоє тіло
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки {hh30нехаотичні{x {hh134чаклуни{x, {hh139відьми{x, {hh143некроманти{x, {hh133клерики{x і
{x {hh138анти-паладіни{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x, {hh80епохи{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Михаил||а|у|а|ом|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Михаїл||а|у|а|ом|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsClasses registry="profession">warlock</patronsClasses>
  <patronsRaces registry="race">faery</patronsRaces>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Mihail</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27313</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
