<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes registry="profession">ranger anti-paladin necromancer thief vampire witch warlock ninja paladin samurai warrior cleric</classes>
  <description>Бог огня и ремесел</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <flags>cult</flags>
  <help id="971" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <text l="en">{CPrometheus{x is the blacksmith god, giver of fire, and creator of the crafts. After the Supreme Goddess {hh1565Varda{x brought elves into our world, it was he who helped Father {hh1576Leo{x mold the second mortal race, humans, from clay and endow them with reason. Prometheus stands apart from the great confrontation of the Eight Principles; helping people concerns him far more than divine intrigues. Because of this the other gods dislike him and sometimes visit punishments upon him.

%A% =Gifts:= the mark of Prometheus will periodically {hh273repair{x and clean your
  armor of {hh2168corrosion{x, and in battle will fire a {hh625fireball{x at your enemy.
  The mark of Prometheus also helps with {hh273repairs{x and crafting items by {hh195artisans{x.
%A% =Sacrifices:= Prometheus prefers magical items with spells
  of item magic. Prometheus likes to receive books,
  scrolls, textbooks and spellbooks as sacrifice, as well as good weapons.

According to legend, the old gods of {hh1864Olympus{x imprisoned Prometheus, but one of his followers helped his patron escape and took his place in the prison cell.

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CПрометей{x -- бог-кузнец, даритель огня и создатель ремесел. После того как Верховная Богиня {hh1565Варда{x привела в наш мир эльфов, именно он помог Отцу {hh1576Лео{x создать из глины вторую смертную расу, людей, и наделить их разумом. Прометей стоит в стороне от великого противоборства Восьми Начал, помощь людям заботит его гораздо больше, чем божественные перипетии. Поэтому остальные боги недолюбливают его и иногда насылают на него кары.

%A% =Дары:= знак Прометея будет периодически {hh273чинить{x и чистить от {hh2168коррозии{x твои
  доспехи, а в бою выстрелит в твоего противника {hh625огненным шаром{x.
  Также знак Прометея помогает при {hh273починке{x и создании вещей {hh195ремесленниками{x.
%A% =Жертвоприношения:= Прометей предпочитает волшебные предметы с заклинаниями
  предметной магии. Прометею нравится, когда ему в жертву приносят книги,
  свитки, учебники и книги заклинаний. а также хорошее оружие.

По легенде, старые боги {hh1864Олимпа{x заточили Прометея в темнице, но один из его последователей помог своему патрону бежать и занял его место в тюремной камере.

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CПрометей{x -- бог-коваль, дарувальник вогню та творець ремесел. Після того як Верховна Богиня {hh1565Варда{x привела до нашого світу ельфів, саме він допоміг Батькові {hh1576Лео{x створити з глини другу смертну расу, людей, і наділити їх розумом. Прометей стоїть осторонь великого протистояння Восьми Начал -- допомога людям цікавить його набагато більше, ніж божественні перипетії. Тому решта богів недолюблює його і іноді насилає на нього кари.

%A% =Дари:= знак Прометея буде час від часу {hh273лагодити{x і чистити від {hh2168корозії{x твої
  обладунки, а в бою вистрілить у твого противника {hh625вогняною кулею{x.
  Також знак Прометея допомагає при {hh273ремонті{x та виготовленні речей {hh195ремісниками{x.
%A% =Жертвоприношення:= Прометей надає перевагу чарівним предметам із заклинаннями
  предметної магії. Прометею подобається, коли йому в жертву приносять книги,
  сувої, підручники та книги заклинань, а також хорошу зброю.

За легендою, старі боги {hh1864Олімпу{x ув'язнили Прометея, але один із його послідовників допоміг своєму патрону втекти та зайняв його місце у тюремній камері.

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items>scroll weapon furniture spellbook recipe parchment</items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
    <skillGroups registry="skillGroup">enchantment</skillGroups>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Промете|й|я|ю|я|ем|е</nameRus>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Prometheus</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27316</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
