<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good</align>
  <description>Бог обжигающего света, испепеляющего тьму</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <help id="1566" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <keyword l="en">razer</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">разер</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CRazer{x -- god of furious, scorching light that burns away darkness, the legendary King of {hh1466Knights{x who united the armies of Light and the warriors of {hh1471Fury{x for war against the hordes of the Invaders during the First and Second Epochs of this world. Razer is usually depicted as a mature man in a crown and gleaming golden armor, poised for hand-to-hand combat. Razer's first commandment: &quot;Good must have fists.&quot; He is patron of the Order of Knights and all who are willing to sacrifice themselves in the eternal and irreconcilable struggle against Evil.

%A% =Paths:= {WLight{x, {RFury{x
%A% =Gifts:= in battle Razer's mark will incinerate your foes with {hh761a ray of truth{x
%A% =Restrictions:= {hh33good{x only

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x, {hh80epochs{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CРазер{x -- бог яростного, обжигающего света, испепеляющего тьму, легендарный Король {hh1466Рыцарей{x, объединивший армии Света и воинов {hh1471Ярости{x на войну с полчищами Захватчиков во времена Первой и Второй Эпох этого мира. Разера обычно изображают в виде зрелого мужчины в короне и сияющих золотых доспехах, в стойке рукопашного боя. Первая заповедь Разера: &quot;Добро должно быть с кулаками.&quot; Он покровительствует Ордену Рыцарей и всем, кто готов пожертвовать собой в извечной и непримиримой борьбе со Злом.

%A% =Пути:= {WСвет{x, {RЯрость{x
%A% =Дары:= в бою знак Разера испепелит твоих противников {hh761лучом истины{x
%A% =Ограничения:= только {hh33добрые{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x, {hh80эпохи{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CРазер{x -- бог лютого, випалюючого світла, що нищить пітьму, легендарний Король {hh1466Лицарів{x, який обʼєднав армії Світла і воїнів {hh1471Ярості{x на війну з полчищами Загарбників у часи Першої і Другої Епох цього світу. Разера зазвичай зображують у вигляді зрілого чоловіка в короні та виблискуючих золотих обладунках, у стійці рукопашного бою. Перша заповідь Разера: &quot;Добро має бути з кулаками.&quot; Він покровительствує Ордену Лицарів і всім, хто готовий пожертвувати собою у вічній і непримиренній боротьбі зі Злом.

%A% =Шляхи:= {WСвітло{x, {RЯрість{x
%A% =Дари:= у бою знак Разера спопелить твоїх противників {hh761променем істини{x
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки {hh33добрі{x

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x, {hh80епохи{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Разер||а|у|а|ом|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Разер||а|у|а|ом|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsClans registry="clan">knight</patronsClans>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Razer</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27301</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
