<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>neutral evil</align>
  <classes registry="profession">thief samurai warrior necromancer ranger cleric witch anti-paladin ninja paladin warlock vampire</classes>
  <description>Бог-дракон, сеющий войну и разрушения</description>
  <ethos>neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <flags>cult</flags>
  <help id="967" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <extra l="en"></extra>
    <extra l="ru">сэт</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <text l="en">{CSeth{x -- god of rage, sandstorms, war and death, destruction and chaos, the Scourge of All That Is, who razes cities and peoples to ash. Legend holds that Seth bred the race of dragons to command them and lead their armies to the ruin of all living things. But {hh1576Leo{x granted dragons reason and free will, and {hh974Enki{x breathed magic into them, and since then the dragons decide for themselves which side to fight on. Followers of the Seth cult depict him as a black dragon with the head of a donkey, a red mane, and bloodshot eyes.

%A% =Paths:= {MChaos{x, {DEvil{x
%A% =Gifts:= in battle the mark of Seth will sear your foes with {hh658fire{x or {hh664lightning{x
  breath (depending on the number of foes) and grant you {hh565the strength of a dragon{x,
  increasing your damage, strength, and accuracy.
%A% =Restrictions:= only {hh30non-lawful{x {hh33non-good{x
%A% =Sacrifices:= Seth prefers magical items with spells
  from the school of battle magic.

Driven from Dragon Peak and stripped of dominion over the draconian race, the last priests of the Seth cult took refuge in the darkness of {hh1856the Underdark{x.

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CСет{x -- бог ярости, песчаных бурь, войны и смерти, разрушения и хаоса, Бич Сущего, испепеляющий города и народы. По легенде, Сет вывел расу драконов, чтобы повелевать ими и вести их армии на погибель всему живому. Но {hh1576Лео{x даровал драконам разум и свободу воли, а {hh974Энки{x вдохнул в них магию, и с тех пор драконы сами решают, на чьей стороне сражаться. Поклонники культа Сета изображают его в виде черного дракона с головой осла, красной гривой и кровавыми буркалами.

%A% =Пути:= {MХаос{x, {DЗло{x
%A% =Дары:= в бою знак Сета опалит твоих противников {hh658огненным{x или {hh664электрическим{x
  дыханием (в зависимости от количества противников) и дарует тебе {hh565силу дракона{x,
  увеличивая урон, силу и точность.
%A% =Ограничения:= только {hh30не-законопослушные{x {hh33не-добрые{x
%A% =Жертвоприношения:= Сет предпочитает волшебные предметы с заклинаниями
  группы боевой магии. 

Изгнанные с Пика Драконов и лишенные власти над расой драконидов, последние священники культа Сета укрылись во мраке {hh1856Подземья{x.

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CСет{x -- бог люті, піщаних бур, війни і смерті, руйнування і хаосу, Бич Сущого, що спалює міста і народи. За легендою, Сет вивів расу драконів, щоб владарювати ними і вести їхні армії на загибель усьому живому. Але {hh1576Лео{x дарував драконам розум і вільну волю, а {hh974Енкі{x вдихнув у них магію, і відтоді дракони самі вирішують, на чиєму боці битися. Поклонники культу Сета зображують його у вигляді чорного дракона з головою осла, червоною гривою і кривавими баньками.

%A% =Шляхи:= {MХаос{x, {DЗло{x
%A% =Дари:= у бою знак Сета обпалить твоїх противників {hh658вогняним{x або {hh664електричним{x
  диханням (залежно від кількості противників) і дарує тобі {hh565силу дракона{x,
  збільшуючи шкоду, силу і точність.
%A% =Обмеження:= тільки {hh30не-законослухняні{x {hh33не-добрі{x
%A% =Жертвоприношення:= Сет надає перевагу чарівним предметам із заклинаннями
  групи бойової магії.

Вигнані з Піку Драконів і позбавлені влади над расою дракоників, останні жерці культу Сета сховалися у пітьмі {hh1856Підземʼя{x.

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
    <skillGroups registry="skillGroup">combat</skillGroups>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Сет||а|у|а|ом|е</nameRus>
  <nameUa>Сет||а|у|а|ом|і</nameUa>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Seth</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27328</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
