<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align></align>
  <description>Богиня буйства природы и ее грозной силы</description>
  <ethos></ethos>
  <flags>cult</flags>
  <help id="983" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <keyword l="en">kibela</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">сибель</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CSiebele{x -- goddess of nature's wild fury and its fearsome power. Siebele is revered as the embodiment of the Great Mother Nature, and she often serves as a symbol of the feminine principle.

The priests and priestesses of Siebele's cult despise human anthill societies; they offer their Mother terrifying sacrifices, begging her to send floods and earthquakes upon cities so that new forests may grow in their place. Siebele is depicted as a stern queen in a turreted crown, hurtling madly on a golden chariot drawn by lions. Naturally, Siebele is the patron of {hh192druids{x.

%A% =Paths:= {gNature{x
%A% =Gifts:= in a forest fight, Siebele's mark will ensnare the foe with {hh835tree roots{x;
  near water -- {hh553drown{x them; against multiple foes
  it will unleash a {hh796hurricane{x upon them, and in all other cases -- strike
  with the power of Earth, hitting men with particular force
%A% =Sacrifices:= Siebele prefers magical items enchanted with spells of
  nature and enhancement. She will rejoice at the corpse of a non-neutral creature.

Siebele's shrines can be found in the depths of Thera's ancient forests -- for instance, in {hh1862Haon Dor{x.

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CКибела{x -- богиня буйства природы и ее грозной силы. Кибелу почитают как олицетворение Великой Матери-Природы, и она часто выступает символом женского начала.

Жрецам и жрицам культа Кибелы ненавистны людские общества-муравейники, они приносят своей Матери ужасающие жертвоприношения, прося наслать на города потопы и землетрясения, дабы вырастить на их месте новые леса. Кибелу изображают суровой царицей в зубчатой короне, бешено несущейся на золотой колеснице, запряженной львами. Разумеется, Кибела покровительствует {hh192друидам{x.

%A% =Пути:= {gПрирода{x
%A% =Дары:= в лесном бою знак Кибелы оплетет врага {hh835древесными корнями{x,
  в бою у воды -- {hh553утопит{x, в бою против нескольких противников
  нашлет на них {hh796ураган{x, а во всех остальных случаях -- ударит
  силой Земли, с особенной силой поражая мужчин
%A% =Жертвоприношения:= Кибела предпочитает волшебные предметы с заклинаниями
  природы и усиления. Обрадуется трупу не-нейтрального существа.

Капища Кибелы можно найти в глубинах древних лесов Тэры -- например, в {hh1862Хаон Доре{x.

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CСіебела{x -- богиня буйства природи та її грізної сили. Сіебелу шанують як уособлення Великої Матері-Природи, і вона часто виступає символом жіночого начала.

Жреці та жриці культу Сіебели ненавидять людські суспільства-мурашники, вони приносять своїй Матері жахливі жертвоприношення, просячи наслати на міста повені й землетруси, щоб на їхньому місці виросли нові ліси. Сіебелу зображають суворою царицею в зубчастій короні, що несамовито мчить на золотій колісниці, запряженій левами. Звісно, Сіебела покровительствує {hh192друїдам{x.

%A% =Шляхи:= {gПрирода{x
%A% =Дари:= у лісовому бою знак Сіебели обплете ворога {hh835деревʼяним корінням{x;
  у бою біля води -- {hh553потопить{x його; проти кількох ворогів
  нашле на них {hh796ураган{x, а в усіх інших випадках -- вдарить
  силою Землі, з особливою потугою вражаючи чоловіків
%A% =Жертвоприношення:= Сіебела віддає перевагу чарівним предметам із закляттями
  природи та підсилення. Зрадіє трупу не-нейтральної істоти.

Капища Сіебели можна знайти у глибинах стародавніх лісів Тери -- наприклад, у {hh1862Хаон Дорі{x.

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
    <skillGroups registry="skillGroup">nature enhancement</skillGroups>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Кибел|а|ы|е|у|ой|е</nameRus>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsClasses registry="profession">druid</patronsClasses>
  <sex>female</sex>
  <shortDescr>Siebele</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27332</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
