<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Religion type="DefaultReligion">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <clans registry="clan">none</clans>
  <description>Бог-покровитель тех, кто идет иными путями</description>
  <ethos>lawful neutral chaotic</ethos>
  <help id="1584" level="-1" type="ReligionHelp">
    <extra l="en"></extra>
    <extra l="ru">&apos;одиночество тирны&apos;</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <keyword l="en">teelak tirna</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">тилак тирна</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CTirna{x -- patron god of those who walk their own paths without joining any clan. During the Second Epoch he was known under the name Tilak, and for many centuries helped {hh1577Dwarkin{x and other gods develop and build our world from the void. Tirna is a patient shepherd of the sentient races, a teacher of civilizations and architect of cities. Mortals remember with gratitude many of his gifts and innovations -- especially in the development of our society, the {hh3clans and orders{x of this world. Tirna is patron of the race of half-bloods and outcasts, the {hh162half-elves{x.

%A% =Gifts:= in battle Tirna's mark may briefly teach you one of the secret
{x clan skills
%A% =Restrictions:= only a clanless character can become a follower of Tirna

%SA% %H% {hh81Eight Paths{x, {hh80epochs{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CТирна{x -- бог-покровитель тех, кто идет иными путями, не вступая ни в какой клан. Во времена Второй Эпохи он был известен под именем Тилака, и много столетий помогал {hh1577Дворкину{x и другим богам развивать и строить наш мир из пустоты. Тирна -- терпеливый пастырь разумных рас, учитель цивилизаций и архитектор городов. Смертные с благодарностью вспоминают многие его дары и нововведения -- особенно в области развития нашего общества, {hh3кланов и орденов{x этого мира. Тирна покровительствует расе полукровок и изгоев, {hh162полуэльфов{x.

%A% =Дары:= в бою знак Тирны может ненадолго обучить тебя одному из тайных
{x клановых умений
%A% =Ограничения:= стать последователем Тирны сможет только внеклановый

%SA% %H% {hh81Восемь Путей{x, {hh80эпохи{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CТирна{x -- бог-покровитель тих, хто іде своїми шляхами, не вступаючи до жодного клану. За часів Другої Епохи він був відомий під іменем Тілака, і багато століть допомагав {hh1577Дворкіну{x та іншим богам розвивати і будувати наш світ із порожнечі. Тирна -- терплячий пастир розумних рас, учитель цивілізацій і архітектор міст. Смертні з вдячністю згадують багато його дарів і нововведень -- особливо в галузі розвитку нашого суспільства, {hh3кланів і орденів{x цього світу. Тирна покровительствує расі напівкровок і вигнанців, {hh162напівельфів{x.

%A% =Дари:= у бою знак Тирни може ненадовго навчити тебе одному з таємних
{x кланових умінь
%A% =Обмеження:= стати послідовником Тирни зможе тільки позаклановий

%SA% %H% {hh81Вісім Шляхів{x, {hh80епохи{x
</text>
  </help>
  <likes>
    <items></items>
    <liquidFlags></liquidFlags>
  </likes>
  <nameRus>Тирн|а|ы|е|у|ой|е</nameRus>
  <nameRusFemale></nameRusFemale>
  <patronsRaces registry="race">half-elf</patronsRaces>
  <sex>male</sex>
  <shortDescr>Tirna</shortDescr>
  <tattooVnum>27337</tattooVnum>
</Religion>
