<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<SkillGroup type="DefaultSkillGroup">
  <autoHelp>false</autoHelp>
  <help id="234" labels="language" level="0" type="SkillGroupHelp">
    <extra l="en">ahenn arcadi forget khuzdul list quenia words</extra>
    <extra l="ru">ахэнн аркади блуждающий &apos;блуждающий монах&apos; бродячий кхуздул квенья монах слова слово список забыть</extra>
    <extra l="ua">ахенн аркади блукаючий &apos;блукаючий монах&apos; мандрівний кхуздул квенья монах слова слово список забути</extra>
    <keyword l="en">ancient languages</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">древние языки</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">давні мови</keyword>
    <text l="en">Many dialects of antiquity still retain their power to this day. Even if there are no longer
anyone who can somehow communicate in the language of their ancestors, fragments of
ancient knowledge continue to live in individual words. Currently, the peoples of
Terra are aware of four ancient languages: {hh2044quenia{x, {hh2040ahenn{x, {hh2043khuzdul{x and {hh2041arcadi{x.

{CHOW IT WORKS{x
First, you need to learn the skills of ancient languages. The teacher of ancient languages is
{gthe wandering monk{x. She travels all over the world, so you can accidentally
meet her anywhere.

After learning the language, you can start memorizing words in this language and
use their ancient power. To use a word, you need to utter it.
Words are said like this: &lt;language name&gt; &lt;word&gt;, for example:
{x      {yahenn{x {Dword{x
Some words can be spoken to a target, animate or not:
{x      {yquenia{x {Dword{x Gregory
{x      {yarcadi{x {Dword{x barrel
Words with negative effects, spoken without a target, will turn on you in peaceful times,
and on your opponent in battle.

{CHOW TO LEARN WORDS{x
Anyone can learn to pronounce words somehow, but only those races whose ancestors
once spoke this dialect, as well as their distant relatives, can improve this skill and even (in the case of particularly close
relations) gradually learn to understand the meaning of individual words.
For example, {hh149drow{x will be able to understand the meaning of the words ah'enn, and {hh154duergar{x - to understand what
other words in khuzdul mean. To understand the meaning, you need to learn the language
well enough (more than 75%). For example:
{x      {yquenia meaning{x {Dword{x

Words can be learned as a reward for completing quests. Anyone can use such words,
and it is possible that the same word was received as a reward by someone else, so there is a reason to hurry. You can inform these words to others,
and they will also be able to use them.

Modern descendants of ancient races sometimes dream unusual dreams - the memory of ancestors
resurrects individual words from oblivion. Unlike the words obtained as a reward,
only those who dreamed of them can use them.

You can eavesdrop and remember the word someone else is saying, or remember the word someone told you:
{x      {yquenia remember{x {Dword{x

You can see a list of all the dreamed and remembered words like this:
{x      {ykhuzdul list{x

Forget all words or a specific one:
{x      {ykhuzdul forget all{x
{x      {yarcadi forget{x {Dword{x

The help will tell you more about each of the languages.
</text>
    <text l="ru">Многие наречия древности по сей день сохраняют свою силу. Пусть даже не осталось
никого, способного хоть как-то объясниться на языке предков, все равно обломки
древних знаний продолжают жить в отдельных словах. На текущий момент народам
Тэры известны четыре древних языка: {hh2044квенья{x, {hh2040ахэнн{x, {hh2043кхуздул{x и {hh2041аркади{x.

{CКАК ЭТО РАБОТАЕТ{x
Сначала нужно обучиться навыкам древних языков. Учительница древних языков --
{gблуждающий монах{x. Она путешествует по всему миру, поэтому ее можно случайно
встретить где угодно.

После изучения языка ты сможешь начать запоминать слова на этом языке и
использовать их древнюю силу. Чтобы использовать слово, его нужно изречь.
Произносят слова так: &lt;название языка&gt; &lt;слово&gt;, например:
{x      {yахэнн{x {Dслово{x
Некоторые слова можно произносить на цель, как {hh2142одушевленную{x, так и нет:
{x      {yквенья{x {Dслово{x григорий
{x      {yаркади{x {Dслово{x бочонок
Слова с отрицательными воздействиями, произнесенные без цели, в мирное время
обратятся на тебя, а в бою -- на твоего противника.

{CКАК НАУЧИТЬСЯ СЛОВАМ{x
Научиться кое-как выговаривать слова может каждый, но лишь расы, чьи предки
когда-то говорили на этом наречии, а так же их дальние родственники, в 
состоянии усовершенствовать этот навык и даже (в случае особо близкого
родства) постепенно научиться понимать смысл отдельных слов. 
Например, {hh149дроу{x смогут разобрать смысл слов ах&apos;энн, а {hh154дуэргары{x - понять, что
означают иные слова на кхуздуле. Для понимания смысла необходимо изучить язык
достаточно хорошо (больше 75%). Например:
{x      {yквенья смысл{x {Dслово{x

Слова можно узнать в награду за выполнения квестов. Пользоваться такими словами
сможет каждый, и не исключено, что то же самое слово досталось в награду 
кому-то еще, потому есть смысл поторопиться. Можно сообщить эти слова другим,
и они тоже смогут ими воспользоваться.

Современным потомкам древних рас иногда снятся необычные сны - память предков
воскрешает из небытия отдельные слова. В отличие от слов, полученных в награду,
такими словами может воспользоваться лишь тот, кому они приснились. 

Можно подслушать и запомнить слово, которое произносит кто-то еще, или же
запомнить слово, сообщенное тебе кем-то:
{x      {yквенья запомнить{x {Dслово{x

Посмотреть список всех приснившихся и запомненных слов можно так:
{x      {yкхуздул список{x

Забыть все слова или какое-то конкретное:
{x      {yкхуздул забыть все{x
{x      {yаркади забыть{x {Dслово{x

Подробнее о каждом из языков расскажет справка.
</text>
    <text l="ua">Багато діалектів давнини й досі зберігають свою силу. Нехай навіть не залишилося
нікого, хто міг би хоч якось порозумітися мовою предків, все одно уламки
давніх знань продовжують жити у окремих словах. На сьогодні народи
Тери знають чотири давні мови: {hh2044квенья{x, {hh2040ахенн{x, {hh2043кхуздул{x і {hh2041аркади{x.

{CЯК ЦЕ ПРАЦЮЄ{x
Спочатку потрібно навчитися навичкам давніх мов. Викладачка давніх мов --
{gблукаючий монах{x. Вона подорожує по всьому світу, тому її можна випадково
зустріти будь-де.

Після вивчення мови ти зможеш почати запам'ятовувати слова на цій мові та
використовувати їхню давню силу. Щоб використовувати слово, його потрібно озвучити.
Слова виголошують так: &lt;назва мови&gt; &lt;слово&gt;, наприклад:
{x      {yахенн{x {Dслово{x
Деякі слова можна виголошувати на ціль, як {hh2142одушевлену{x, так і ні:
{x      {yквенья{x {Dслово{x григорій
{x      {yаркади{x {Dслово{x барильце
Слова з негативними впливами, виголошені без цілі, в мирний час
обернуться на тебе, а в бою -- на твого противника.

{CЯК НАВЧИТИСЯ СЛІВ{x
Навчитися якось вимовляти слова може кожен, але лише раси, чиї предки
колись говорили на цьому діалекті, а також їхні далекі родичі, у 
стані вдосконалити цю навичку і навіть (у разі особливо тісного
родства) поступово навчитися розуміти сенс окремих слів. 
Наприклад, {hh149дроу{x зможуть розібрати сенс слів ах'енн, а {hh154дуергари{x - зрозуміти, що
означають інші слова на кхуздулі. Для розуміння змісту необхідно вивчити мову
достатньо добре (більше 75%). Наприклад:
{x      {yквенья сенс{x {Dслово{x

Слова можна дізнатися в нагороду за виконання квестів. Використовувати такі слова
зможе кожен, і не виключено, що те ж саме слово дісталося в нагороду 
комусь ще, тому є сенс поспішити. Можна повідомити ці слова іншим,
і вони теж зможуть ними скористатися.

Сучасним нащадкам давніх рас іноді сняться незвичайні сни - пам'ять предків
воскрешає з небуття окремі слова. На відміну від слів, отриманих у нагороду,
такими словами може скористатися лише той, кому вони наснилися. 

Можна підслухати і запам'ятати слово, яке промовляє хтось інший, або ж
запам'ятати слово, повідомлене тобі кимось:
{x      {yквенья запам'ятати{x {Dслово{x

Подивитися список всіх приснилих і запам'ятованих слів можна так:
{x      {yкхуздул список{x

Забути всі слова або якесь конкретне:
{x      {yкхуздул забути все{x
{x      {yаркади забути{x {Dслово{x

Докладніше про кожну з мов розповість довідка.
</text>
  </help>
  <hidden>false</hidden>
  <name l="en">ancient languages</name>
  <name l="ru">древние языки</name>
  <name l="ua">давні мови</name>
  <practicer>28004</practicer>
</SkillGroup>