<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Command>
  <aliases l="en">junk</aliases>
  <aliases l="ru">прибрать</aliases>
  <aliases l="ua">прибрати</aliases>
  <cat>item religion</cat>
  <help id="1375" labels="religion" level="-1" type="CommandHelp">
    <extra l="en">altar 'sacrifice altar'</extra>
    <extra l="ru">алтари алтарь пожертвование пожертвовать жертва 'жертвоприношение на алтаре' жертвоприношения</extra>
    <extra l="ua">вівтарі вівтар пожертвування жертвувати жертва 'жертвоприношення на вівтарі' жертвоприношення</extra>
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%CMD%* all
%FMT% *%CMD%* _item_

Sacrifices an item (or all items) on the ground to the gods -- the gods grant a bit of silver.
Some things (like player corpses) cannot be sacrificed. Anti-paladins can gain
{hh695magical{x energy from sacrifices.

Altars can be constructed for the gods of ancient cults -- the gods and goddesses of the {hh1official
pantheon{x do not accept sacrifices.

%FMT% *altar*

Build an altar to fill it with pious content. On the altar, you can
{hh1024place{x items, money, corpses, jewels, weapons, and so on, hoping to please
the deity and receive a reward in return.

%A% Do not sacrifice worthless junk -- this can anger the deity.
%A% The Gods of Light will not appreciate the sacrifice of a good creature's corpse, and vice versa.
%A% You can sacrifice money, but you won't be able to pay off completely with money:
  a hundred or two gold and the god will lose interest.
%A% Similarly, with jewels and other items -- more is not always better.
%A% Among all {hh121magical items{x (potions, staffs), gods prefer those whose
  effects are close to their sign.
%A% A typical sacrifice can consist of a hundred coins, a couple of corpses,
  drinks, magical items, weapons, or books, food.

%FMT% *%CMD%* _altar_ *experience*|*mana*|*learnability*

Having gathered a worthy offering, you can perform a sacrifice with this command. In return, you can
ask for a certain advantage: more experience from kills, spend less
mana, learn faster (this request is unavailable to {hh145humans{x -- they learn quickly anyway).
These bonuses, in case of a successful sacrifice, last for several days and can be seen
with the commands *calendar*, *time*, and *score*.

%SA% %H% {hh1religion{x, {hh1027calendar{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%CMD%* все 
%FMT% *%CMD%* _предмет_  

Приносит предмет (или все) на земле в жертву богам -- боги дадут чуток серебра.
Некоторые вещи (например, трупы игроков) жертвовать нельзя. Анти-паладины могут
получать {hh695магическую{x энергию от жертв.

Божествам древних культов можно соорудить =алтарь= -- Боги и богини {hh1официального
пантеона{x жертвоприношений не приемлют.

%FMT% *алтарь*

Построить алтарь, чтобы наполнить его богоугодным содержимым. На алтарь можно
{hh1024класть{x предметы, деньги, трупы, драгоценности, оружие и так далее в надежде
угодить божеству и получить от него в награду плюшку.

%A% Не приноси в жертву бесполезное барахло -- этим можно прогневать божество.
%A% Боги Света не оценят принесенный в жертву труп доброго существа, и наоборот.
%A% Можно жертвовать деньги, однако полностью откупиться деньгами не получится:
  сотня-другая золота и бог потеряет интерес.
%A% Аналогично дело обстоит с драгоценностями и другими предметами -- много не
  всегда значит хорошо.
%A% Из всех {hh121волшебных предметов{x (зелий, посохов) боги предпочитают те, которые
  близки по действию к их знаку.
%A% Типичное жертвоприношение может состоять из сотни монет, пары-тройки трупов,
  напитков, волшебных предметов, оружия или книг, еды.
  
%FMT% *%CMD%* _алтарь_ *опыт*|*мана*|*обучаемость*

Собрав достойную жертву, можно совершить приношение этой командой. В обмен можно
попросить о том или ином преимуществе: больше опыта за убийства, тратить меньше
маны, быстрее учиться (эта просьба недоступна {hh145людям{x -- они и так быстро учатся).
Такие бонусы в случае удачного жертвоприношения даются на несколько дней и видны
по команде *календарь*, *время* и *счет*.

%SA% %H% {hh1религия{x, {hh1027календарь{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%CMD%* все 
%FMT% *%CMD%* _предмет_  

Приносить предмет (або все) на землі в жертву богам -- боги дадуть трохи срібла.
Деякі речі (наприклад, трупи гравців) жертвувати не можна. Анти-паладини можуть
отримувати {hh695магічну{x енергію від жертв.

Божествам стародавніх культів можна спорудити =вівтар= -- Боги і богині {hh1офіційного
пантеону{x жертвоприношень не приймають.

%FMT% *вівтар*

Побудувати вівтар, щоб наповнити його благочестивим змістом. На вівтар можна
{hh1024класти{x предмети, гроші, трупи, коштовності, зброю тощо, сподіваючись
вгодити божеству та отримати від нього в винагороду.

%A% Не принось у жертву непотрібне барахло -- це може роздратувати божество.
%A% Боги Світла не оцінять принесеного в жертву трупа доброго істоти, і навпаки.
%A% Можна жертвувати гроші, але повністю відкупитися грошима не вдасться:
  сотня-дві золота і бог втратить інтерес.
%A% Аналогічно є з коштовностями та іншими предметами -- багато не
  завжди означає добре.
%A% З усіх {hh121магічних предметів{x (зілля, палиці) боги надають перевагу тим, що
  близькі за дією до їх знаку.
%A% Типове жертвоприношення може складатися з сотні монет, кількох трупів,
  напоїв, магічних предметів, зброї чи книг, їжі.
  
%FMT% *%CMD%* _вівтар_ *досвід*|*мана*|*навчуваність*

Зібравши гідну жертву, можна здійснити приношення цією командою. В обмін можна
попросити про ту чи іншу перевагу: більше досвіду за вбивства, менше витрачати
мани, швидше навчатися (це прохання недоступне {hh145людям{x -- вони і так швидко навчаються).
Такі бонуси в разі вдалого жертвоприношення даються на кілька днів і видно
по команді *календар*, *час* і *рахунок*.

%SA% %H% {hh1релігія{x, {hh1027календар{x
</text>
    <title l="en">{CItems: {xsacrifice, altars</title>
    <title l="ru">{CВещи: {xпожертвование, алтари</title>
    <title l="ua">{CРечі: {xпожертвування, вівтарі</title>
  </help>
  <hint l="en">sacrifice to the gods</hint>
  <hint l="ru">принести жертву богам</hint>
  <hint l="ua">принести жертву богам</hint>
  <name l="en">sacrifice</name>
  <name l="ru">жертвовать</name>
  <name l="ua">жертвувати</name>
  <order>player_only</order>
  <position>rest</position>
</Command>