<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Command>
  <cat>info</cat>
  <extra>keep_hide ghost afk</extra>
  <help id="1029" level="-1" type="CommandHelp">
    <extra l="en">day evening morning night today</extra>
    <extra l="ru">день ночь сегодня утро вечер &apos;время дня&apos; &apos;время суток&apos;</extra>
    <extra l="ua">день ніч сьогодні ранок вечір &apos;час дня&apos; &apos;час доби&apos;</extra>
    <text l="en">The time of day (day or night) affects many events in the game. For example, at night without a
{hh65lantern{x or {hh830infrared vision{x you can&apos;t see anything in the room, and even with a lantern
you can&apos;t see {hh1021adjacent exits{x. During the day outside, {hh144vampires{x are scorched by the sun&apos;s rays.

You can leave messages that are only visible at certain times of the day
(see %H% {hh61tags{x)

%FMT% *%CMD%*
This command shows the time of day and date. In some parts of our world, time flows differently. If you have a watch, the time of day can be seen in the status line
(%H% {hh1012hint{x).

%SA% %H% {hh16update{x, {hh1027calendar{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">Время суток (день или ночь) влияет на многие события в игре. Например, ночью без
{hh65фонаря{x или {hh830инфравидения{x нельзя ничего разглядеть в комнате, а даже с фонарем
не видно {hh1021соседние выходы{x. Днем на улице {hh144вампиров{x обжигают лучи солнца. 

Можно оставлять сообщения, которые видно только в определенное время суток
(см. %H% {hh61тэги{x)

%FMT% *%CMD%*
Эта команда показывает время суток и дату. В некоторых точках нашего мира время
течет по-иному. Если у тебя есть часы, время суток можно видеть в строке статуса
(%H% {hh1012подсказка{x).

%SA% %H% {hh16обновление{x, {hh1027календарь{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">Час доби (день або ніч) впливає на багато подій у грі. Наприклад, вночі без
{hh65ліхтаря{x або {hh830інфравізора{x не можна нічого розглянути в кімнаті, а навіть із ліхтарем
не видно {hh1021сусідні виходи{x. Вдень на вулиці {hh144вампірів{x обпалюють промені сонця.

Можна залишати повідомлення, які видно тільки в певний час доби
(див. %H% {hh61теги{x)

%FMT% *%CMD%*
Ця команда показує час доби та дату. У деяких точках нашого світу час
тече по-іншому. Якщо у тебе є години, час доби можна бачити в рядку статусу
(%H% {hh1012підказка{x).

%SA% %H% {hh16оновлення{x, {hh1027календар{x
</text>
    <title l="en">Time of Day</title>
    <title l="ru">Время суток</title>
    <title l="ua">Час доби</title>
  </help>
  <hint l="en">find out the time of day and date</hint>
  <hint l="ru">узнать время суток и дату</hint>
  <hint l="ua">дізнатися час доби та дату</hint>
  <name l="en">time</name>
  <name l="ru">время</name>
  <name l="ua">час</name>
  <order>player_only</order>
  <position>dead</position>
</Command>
