<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<weather>

  <event id="sunrise">
    
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Тусклое зимнее солнце нехотя выползает из-за Моря Дракона.</line>
      <line l="en">A dim winter sun crawls reluctantly up from behind the Dragon Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">Тьмяне зимове сонце знехотя виповзає з-за Моря Дракона.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Над Виноцветным морем занимается блеклый рассвет -- Атум-Ра просыпается неохотно.</line>
      <line l="en">A pale dawn breaks over the Wine-Dark Sea -- Atum-Ra wakes unwillingly.</line>
      <line l="ua">Над Винноколірним морем займається блідий світанок -- Атум-Ра прокидається знехотя.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Скупые лучи золотят иней на востоке, но тепла в них нет.</line>
      <line l="en">Thin rays gild the frost in the east, but there is no warmth in them.</line>
      <line l="ua">Скупі промені золотять паморозь на сході, та тепла в них немає.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Бледное солнце показывается над Морем Дракона и повисает в стылой дымке.</line>
      <line l="en">A wan sun shows over the Dragon Sea and hangs there in a freezing haze.</line>
      <line l="ua">Бліде сонце показується над Морем Дракона і зависає у зимній імлі.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Рассвет крадется с востока тихо, будто боится разбудить мороз.</line>
      <line l="en">Dawn creeps in from the east quietly, as if afraid to wake the frost.</line>
      <line l="ua">Світанок скрадається зі сходу тихо, наче боїться збудити мороз.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Весеннее солнце весело выкатывается из-за Моря Дракона.</line>
      <line l="en">A spring sun rolls up merrily from behind the Dragon Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">Весняне сонце весело викочується з-за Моря Дракона.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Варда гасит последние звезды, и над Виноцветным морем встает солнце.</line>
      <line l="en">Varda snuffs the last stars, and the sun climbs over the Wine-Dark Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">Варда гасить останні зорі, і над Винноколірним морем встає сонце.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Над восточными водами розовеет молодой рассвет.</line>
      <line l="en">A young dawn flushes pink over the eastern waters.</line>
      <line l="ua">Над східними водами рожевіє молодий світанок.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Солнце поднимается над Морем Дракона, и роса вспыхивает искрами.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun lifts over the Dragon Sea, and the dew flares into sparks.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце підіймається над Морем Дракона, і роса спалахує іскрами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Свежий рассвет заливает мир золотом с востока.</line>
      <line l="en">A fresh dawn floods the world with gold from the east.</line>
      <line l="ua">Свіжий світанок заливає світ золотом зі сходу.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Жаркое летнее солнце стремительно выкатывается из-за Моря Дракона.</line>
      <line l="en">A hot summer sun rolls swiftly up from behind the Dragon Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">Спекотне літнє сонце стрімко викочується з-за Моря Дракона.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Над Виноцветным морем вспыхивает раскаленный рассвет, обещая пекло.</line>
      <line l="en">A blazing dawn flares over the Wine-Dark Sea, promising a scorcher.</line>
      <line l="ua">Над Винноколірним морем спалахує розжарений світанок, обіцяючи пекло.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Солнце Атум-Ра встает рано и сразу принимается жечь вовсю.</line>
      <line l="en">Atum-Ra's sun rises early and sets to searing at full strength at once.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце Атум-Ра встає рано й одразу береться пекти на всю силу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Едва рассвело над Морем Дракона, а с востока уже пышет зноем.</line>
      <line l="en">Barely dawn over the Dragon Sea, and already heat pours in from the east.</line>
      <line l="ua">Ледь розвиднілось над Морем Дракона, а зі сходу вже пашить спекою.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Багровое солнце всплывает над Морем Дракона, суля долгий жаркий день.</line>
      <line l="en">A crimson sun floats up over the Dragon Sea, boding a long hot day.</line>
      <line l="ua">Багряне сонце випливає над Морем Дракона, віщуючи довгий спекотний день.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Осеннее солнце устало выбирается из-за Моря Дракона.</line>
      <line l="en">An autumn sun hauls itself wearily up from behind the Dragon Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">Осіннє сонце втомлено вибирається з-за Моря Дракона.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Над Виноцветным морем сочится серый осенний рассвет.</line>
      <line l="en">A grey autumn dawn seeps over the Wine-Dark Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">Над Винноколірним морем сочиться сірий осінній світанок.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Солнце встает поздно, кутаясь в туман над восточными водами.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun rises late, wrapped in mist above the eastern waters.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце встає пізно, кутаючись у туман над східними водами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Хмурый рассвет нехотя расползается с востока.</line>
      <line l="en">A sullen dawn spreads reluctantly out of the east.</line>
      <line l="ua">Похмурий світанок знехотя розповзається зі сходу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Тусклый диск поднимается над Морем Дракона сквозь пелену туч.</line>
      <line l="en">A dull disc climbs over the Dragon Sea through a veil of cloud.</line>
      <line l="ua">Тьмяний диск підіймається над Морем Дракона крізь пелену хмар.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

  
  <event id="precip_start">
    
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">С севера, от Мертвого моря, наносит первый снег.</line>
      <line l="en">The first snow drifts in from the north, off the Dead Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">З півночі, від Мертвого Моря, наносить перший сніг.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Закружились {Wснежинки{x -- Королева Воронов правит свою зиму.</line>
      <line l="en">{WSnowflakes{x begin to whirl -- the Raven Queen keeps her winter.</line>
      <line l="ua">Закружляли {Wсніжинки{x -- Королева Воронів править свою зиму.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Холодный ветер с Мертвого моря приносит колючую метель.</line>
      <line l="en">A cold wind off the Dead Sea brings a stinging flurry.</line>
      <line l="ua">Холодний вітер від Мертвого Моря приносить колючу заметіль.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Небо посерело, и на землю тихо посыпался {Wснег{x.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky greys over, and {Wsnow{x sifts quietly down onto the land.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо посіріло, і на землю тихо посипався {Wсніг{x.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Повалил густой снег, укрывая землю белым покрывалом.</line>
      <line l="en">Thick snow begins to fall, drawing a white blanket over the ground.</line>
      <line l="ua">Повалив густий сніг, укриваючи землю білим покривалом.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Заморосил легкий весенний дождик, пахнущий мокрой землей.</line>
      <line l="en">A light spring drizzle sets in, smelling of wet earth.</line>
      <line l="ua">Заморосив легкий весняний дощик, що пахне мокрою землею.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Первые капли весеннего дождя весело застучали по листве.</line>
      <line l="en">The first drops of spring rain patter merrily on the leaves.</line>
      <line l="ua">Перші краплі весняного дощу весело затарабанили по листю.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Небо расплакалось теплыми весенними слезами.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky breaks into warm spring tears.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо розплакалось теплими весняними сльозами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Пошел дождь -- молодой, звонкий, будто умытый.</line>
      <line l="en">Rain begins -- young, ringing, freshly washed.</line>
      <line l="ua">Пішов дощ -- молодий, дзвінкий, наче вмитий.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Весенняя морось повисла в воздухе прозрачной сеткой.</line>
      <line l="en">A spring mist hangs in the air like a sheet of clear gauze.</line>
      <line l="ua">Весняна мжичка повисла в повітрі прозорою сіткою.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Хлынул теплый летний ливень, тяжелый и щедрый.</line>
      <line l="en">A warm summer downpour bursts loose, heavy and generous.</line>
      <line l="ua">Ринула тепла літня злива, важка і щедра.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Духоту разорвал внезапный летний дождь.</line>
      <line l="en">A sudden summer rain tears through the sultry air.</line>
      <line l="ua">Задуху розірвав раптовий літній дощ.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">С юга наползла туча, и на пыль упали первые крупные капли.</line>
      <line l="en">A cloud rolls up from the south, and the first big drops hit the dust.</line>
      <line l="ua">З півдня насунула хмара, і на пил упали перші великі краплі.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Небо не выдержало жары и пролилось долгожданным дождем.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky gives up on the heat and spills a long-awaited rain.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо не витримало спеки і пролилося довгожданим дощем.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Начался ливень -- парной, июльский, во весь опор.</line>
      <line l="en">The downpour begins -- steamy, high-summer, at full tilt.</line>
      <line l="ua">Почалась злива -- парка, липнева, на всю силу.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Зарядил холодный осенний дождь -- надолго и всерьез.</line>
      <line l="en">A cold autumn rain settles in -- for the long haul, and in earnest.</line>
      <line l="ua">Зарядив холодний осінній дощ -- надовго і всерйоз.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">С Кровавого моря нагнало туч, и посыпалась промозглая морось.</line>
      <line l="en">Clouds blow in off the Bloody Sea, and a raw drizzle begins.</line>
      <line l="ua">З Кривавого Моря нагнало хмар, і посипалась промозгла мжичка.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Пошел дождь, унылый и серый, как сама осень.</line>
      <line l="en">Rain begins, dreary and grey as autumn itself.</line>
      <line l="ua">Пішов дощ, понурий і сірий, як сама осінь.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Осенний ливень обрушился стеной, гоня прочь остатки тепла.</line>
      <line l="en">An autumn downpour comes down like a wall, driving off the last of the warmth.</line>
      <line l="ua">Осіння злива ринула стіною, женучи геть рештки тепла.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Захлюпал промозглый дождь, и мир стал на тон темнее.</line>
      <line l="en">A raw, dank rain starts up, and the world goes a shade darker.</line>
      <line l="ua">Заляпотів промозклий дощ, і світ став на тон темніший.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

  
  <event id="day_begin">
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Морозное зимнее утро вступило в свои права.</line>
      <line l="en">A frosty winter morning has taken hold.</line>
      <line l="ua">Морозний зимовий ранок вступив у свої права.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Короткий зимний день начался, и снег скрипит под ногами.</line>
      <line l="en">The short winter day has begun, and snow squeaks underfoot.</line>
      <line l="ua">Короткий зимовий день почався, і сніг рипить під ногами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Солнце поднялось невысоко и светит холодно, без тепла.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun has risen only low, shining cold and without warmth.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце піднялося невисоко і світить холодно, без тепла.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Зимний день разгорелся, ясный и звонкий от мороза.</line>
      <line l="en">The winter day comes up clear and ringing with frost.</line>
      <line l="ua">Зимовий день розгорівся, ясний і дзвінкий від морозу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Наступил новый день, и над снегами висит белесое солнце.</line>
      <line l="en">A new day has come, and a whitish sun hangs over the snows.</line>
      <line l="ua">Настав новий день, і над снігами висить білясте сонце.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Свежее весеннее утро полнится птичьим гомоном.</line>
      <line l="en">A fresh spring morning fills with the clamour of birds.</line>
      <line l="ua">Свіжий весняний ранок повниться пташиним гамором.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Начался новый день, теплый и полный молодой зелени.</line>
      <line l="en">A new day has begun, warm and full of young green.</line>
      <line l="ua">Почався новий день, теплий і повний молодої зелені.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Солнце поднялось высоко, и весенний мир окончательно проснулся.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun has climbed high, and the spring world is fully awake.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце піднялося високо, і весняний світ остаточно прокинувся.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Весенний день разгорается, пахнущий землей и цветами.</line>
      <line l="en">The spring day warms up, smelling of earth and blossom.</line>
      <line l="ua">Весняний день розгорається, пахнучи землею і квітами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Утренний свет заливает пробудившиеся поля.</line>
      <line l="en">Morning light floods the wakened fields.</line>
      <line l="ua">Ранкове світло заливає пробуджені поля.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Летнее утро уже дышит зноем -- день будет жарким.</line>
      <line l="en">The summer morning already breathes heat -- the day will be hot.</line>
      <line l="ua">Літній ранок уже дихає спекою -- день буде гарячим.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Солнце поднялось высоко и принялось печь всерьез.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun has climbed high and set to baking in earnest.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце піднялося високо і взялося пекти всерйоз.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Начался долгий летний день, знойный и белый от солнца.</line>
      <line l="en">A long summer day has begun, sultry and white with sun.</line>
      <line l="ua">Почався довгий літній день, спекотний і білий від сонця.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Жаркий день вступил в силу, и воздух дрожит над дорогой.</line>
      <line l="en">The hot day has taken hold, and the air shivers above the road.</line>
      <line l="ua">Гарячий день вступив у силу, і повітря тремтить над дорогою.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Солнце Атум-Ра забралось в зенит и жжет без пощады.</line>
      <line l="en">Atum-Ra's sun has climbed to its height and burns without mercy.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце Атум-Ра забралося в зеніт і пече без пощади.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Зябкое осеннее утро занялось нехотя.</line>
      <line l="en">A chilly autumn morning comes on reluctantly.</line>
      <line l="ua">Зимкий осінній ранок зайнявся знехотя.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Начался серый осенний день, пахнущий прелой листвой.</line>
      <line l="en">A grey autumn day has begun, smelling of rotting leaves.</line>
      <line l="ua">Почався сірий осінній день, що пахне прілим листям.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Солнце поднялось невысоко и тускло светит сквозь дымку.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun has risen low and shines dully through the haze.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце піднялося невисоко і тьмяно світить крізь імлу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Осенний день разгорелся хмурый и короткий.</line>
      <line l="en">The autumn day comes up sullen and short.</line>
      <line l="ua">Осінній день розгорівся похмурий і короткий.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Мир проснулся под низким осенним небом.</line>
      <line l="en">The world wakes under a low autumn sky.</line>
      <line l="ua">Світ прокинувся під низьким осіннім небом.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

  <event id="sunset">
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Короткий зимний день гаснет, и с запада наползает стужа.</line>
      <line l="en">The short winter day burns out, and cold creeps in from the west.</line>
      <line l="ua">Короткий зимовий день гасне, і з заходу насувається холод.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Солнце садится в Море Золотого Круга, и мороз крепчает.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun sets into the Sea of the Golden Circle, and the frost tightens.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце сідає в Море Золотого Кола, і мороз міцнішає.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Багровый закат догорает над стылыми снегами.</line>
      <line l="en">A crimson sunset burns down over the frozen snows.</line>
      <line l="ua">Багряний захід догоряє над мерзлими снігами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Солнце скатилось за западный край, и сразу пахнуло стужей.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun rolls off the western edge, and cold bites at once.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце скотилося за західний край, і одразу дихнуло холодом.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Зимнее солнце тонет рано, оставляя небо цвета льда.</line>
      <line l="en">The winter sun sinks early, leaving a sky the colour of ice.</line>
      <line l="ua">Зимове сонце тоне рано, лишаючи небо кольору льоду.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Весенний закат гаснет тихо и розово над западными водами.</line>
      <line l="en">The spring sunset fades soft and pink over the western waters.</line>
      <line l="ua">Весняний захід гасне тихо і рожево над західними водами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Солнце садится в Море Золотого Круга, и вечер пахнет сыростью.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun sets into the Sea of the Golden Circle, and the evening smells of damp.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце сідає в Море Золотого Кола, і вечір пахне вологою.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Долгие весенние сумерки ложатся на молодую зелень.</line>
      <line l="en">Long spring twilight settles over the young green.</line>
      <line l="ua">Довгі весняні сутінки лягають на молоду зелень.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Солнце ушло за горизонт, и защелкали первые соловьи.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun has gone below the horizon, and the first nightingales strike up.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце зайшло за обрій, і заклацали перші солов'ї.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Закат медленно тает над западом, обещая теплую ночь.</line>
      <line l="en">The sunset melts slowly over the west, promising a warm night.</line>
      <line l="ua">Захід поволі тане над обрієм, обіцяючи теплу ніч.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Долгий летний закат заливает запад червонным золотом.</line>
      <line l="en">A long summer sunset floods the west with red-gold.</line>
      <line l="ua">Довгий літній захід заливає небокрай червоним золотом.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Солнце неспешно тонет в Море Золотого Круга, и жара спадает.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun sinks unhurried into the Sea of the Golden Circle, and the heat eases.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце неквапом тоне в Морі Золотого Кола, і спека спадає.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Раскаленный диск садится за западный край, но зной еще держится.</line>
      <line l="en">The blazing disc sets past the western edge, but the heat still lingers.</line>
      <line l="ua">Розжарений диск сідає за західний край, та спека ще тримається.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Летний вечер долго не темнеет, и небо на западе тлеет углями.</line>
      <line l="en">The summer evening is long in darkening, the western sky smouldering like coals.</line>
      <line l="ua">Літній вечір довго не темніє, і небо на заході жевріє вуглинами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Солнце ушло, оставив теплые сумерки и звон цикад.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun is gone, leaving warm dusk and the ring of cicadas.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце зайшло, лишивши теплі сутінки і дзвін цикад.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Осеннее солнце тускло догорает и рано прячется на западе.</line>
      <line l="en">The autumn sun burns down dully and hides early in the west.</line>
      <line l="ua">Осіннє сонце тьмяно догоряє і рано ховається на заході.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Солнце село в Море Золотого Круга, и потянуло промозглым холодом.</line>
      <line l="en">The sun has set into the Sea of the Golden Circle, and a raw cold draws in.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сонце сіло в Море Золотого Кола, і потягло промозклим холодом.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Серый закат угас без красок, и сразу стемнело.</line>
      <line l="en">The grey sunset fades without colour, and night comes at once.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сірий захід згас без барв, і одразу стемніло.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Короткий осенний день погас, и с полей поползла сырость.</line>
      <line l="en">The short autumn day dies, and damp creeps up from the fields.</line>
      <line l="ua">Короткий осінній день згас, і з полів поповзла вогкість.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Закат утонул в тучах над западом, не оставив и полоски света.</line>
      <line l="en">The sunset drowns in cloud over the west, leaving not a strip of light.</line>
      <line l="ua">Захід потонув у хмарах над обрієм, не лишивши й смужки світла.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

  <event id="night_begin">
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Длинная зимняя ночь смыкается над миром, черная и морозная.</line>
      <line l="en">The long winter night closes over the world, black and frozen.</line>
      <line l="ua">Довга зимова ніч змикається над світом, чорна і морозна.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Настала стылая ночь, и звезды Варды колют небо ледяными иглами.</line>
      <line l="en">A frozen night has come, and Varda's stars prick the sky like icy needles.</line>
      <line l="ua">Настала студена ніч, і зорі Варди колють небо крижаними голками.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Мороз с Мертвого моря крепчает, едва сгущается тьма.</line>
      <line l="en">The frost off the Dead Sea tightens the moment the darkness thickens.</line>
      <line l="ua">Мороз від Мертвого Моря міцнішає, щойно згущується темрява.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Черное зимнее небо усыпано колючими звездами.</line>
      <line l="en">The black winter sky is strewn with prickling stars.</line>
      <line l="ua">Чорне зимове небо всіяне колючими зорями.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Длинная ночь Королевы Воронов ложится на снега.</line>
      <line l="en">The Raven Queen's long night settles over the snows.</line>
      <line l="ua">Довга ніч Королеви Воронів лягає на сніги.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Теплая весенняя ночь опускается на землю.</line>
      <line l="en">A warm spring night descends upon the land.</line>
      <line l="ua">Тепла весняна ніч опускається на землю.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Стемнело, и в небе зажглись звезды Варды над молодой листвой.</line>
      <line l="en">Darkness falls, and Varda's stars kindle over the young leaves.</line>
      <line l="ua">Стемніло, і в небі спалахнули зорі Варди над молодим листям.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Весенняя ночь пахнет сырой землей и первыми цветами.</line>
      <line l="en">The spring night smells of wet earth and the first blossoms.</line>
      <line l="ua">Весняна ніч пахне вогкою землею і першими квітами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Ночь пришла короткая и мягкая, полная лягушачьих трелей.</line>
      <line l="en">The night comes short and soft, full of the trilling of frogs.</line>
      <line l="ua">Ніч прийшла коротка і м'яка, повна жаб'ячих трелей.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">На землю спустилась тихая весенняя ночь.</line>
      <line l="en">A quiet spring night has come down upon the land.</line>
      <line l="ua">На землю спустилася тиха весняна ніч.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Душная летняя ночь никак не приносит прохлады.</line>
      <line l="en">A sultry summer night brings no coolness at all.</line>
      <line l="ua">Задушлива літня ніч ніяк не приносить прохолоди.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Стемнело, и звезды Варды густо высыпали на теплое небо.</line>
      <line l="en">Darkness falls, and Varda's stars spill thick across the warm sky.</line>
      <line l="ua">Стемніло, і зорі Варди густо висипали на тепле небо.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Короткая летняя ночь звенит цикадами и не спешит остывать.</line>
      <line l="en">The short summer night rings with cicadas and is slow to cool.</line>
      <line l="ua">Коротка літня ніч дзвенить цикадами і не поспішає холонути.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Тьма Тайфоэн легла на землю, но зной все еще держится.</line>
      <line l="en">Taiphoen's darkness lies over the land, yet the heat still holds.</line>
      <line l="ua">Темрява Тайфоен лягла на землю, та спека все ще тримається.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Настала тихая теплая ночь, и над садами замерцали светлячки.</line>
      <line l="en">A still, warm night has come, and fireflies glimmer over the gardens.</line>
      <line l="ua">Настала тиха тепла ніч, і над садами замерехтіли світлячки.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Холодная осенняя ночь наступает рано и надолго.</line>
      <line l="en">A cold autumn night comes early and stays long.</line>
      <line l="ua">Холодна осіння ніч настає рано і надовго.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Стемнело быстро, и звезды Варды проступили сквозь рваные тучи.</line>
      <line l="en">Darkness comes fast, and Varda's stars show through ragged cloud.</line>
      <line l="ua">Стемніло швидко, і зорі Варди проступили крізь подерті хмари.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Сырая осенняя ночь пахнет прелой листвой и туманом.</line>
      <line l="en">The damp autumn night smells of rotting leaves and mist.</line>
      <line l="ua">Вогка осіння ніч пахне прілим листям і туманом.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Тьма легла на озябшие поля, и потянуло промозглым ветром.</line>
      <line l="en">Darkness settles over the chilled fields, and a raw wind draws in.</line>
      <line l="ua">Темрява лягла на змерзлі поля, і потягло промозклим вітром.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Долгая осенняя ночь смыкается под низкими тучами.</line>
      <line l="en">The long autumn night closes in under low cloud.</line>
      <line l="ua">Довга осіння ніч змикається під низькими хмарами.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

  <event id="clouds_gather">
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">С севера, от Мертвого моря, наползают снеговые тучи.</line>
      <line l="en">Snow-laden clouds crawl up from the north, off the Dead Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">З півночі, від Мертвого Моря, насуваються снігові хмари.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Небо затянуло серой мглой, тяжелой от близкого снега.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky is veiled in grey murk, heavy with snow to come.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо затягло сірою імлою, важкою від близького снігу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Свинцовые тучи сомкнулись, и день померк.</line>
      <line l="en">Leaden clouds close in, and the day dims.</line>
      <line l="ua">Свинцеві хмари зімкнулися, і день померкнув.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Небо набрякло снегом и опустилось совсем низко.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky swells with snow and sinks down very low.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо набрякло снігом і опустилося зовсім низько.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Мертвое море дохнуло стужей, и небо заволокло тучами.</line>
      <line l="en">The Dead Sea breathes out cold, and the sky is smothered in cloud.</line>
      <line l="ua">Мертве Море дихнуло холодом, і небо заволокло хмарами.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Небо затягивается легкими весенними тучами.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky veils over with light spring clouds.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо затягує легкими весняними хмарами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">С запада наплывают дождевые облака, набухшие влагой.</line>
      <line l="en">Rain clouds drift in from the west, swollen with water.</line>
      <line l="ua">Із заходу напливають дощові хмари, набряклі вологою.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Небо помрачнело, обещая теплый весенний дождь.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky darkens, promising a warm spring rain.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо спохмурніло, обіцяючи теплий весняний дощ.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Молодая синева затянулась пеленой облаков.</line>
      <line l="en">The young blue veils over with a film of cloud.</line>
      <line l="ua">Молода блакить затягнулася пеленою хмар.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Тучи собираются, но пахнут они не бедой, а дождем.</line>
      <line l="en">Clouds gather, but they smell not of trouble, only of rain.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари збираються, та пахнуть вони не бідою, а дощем.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">На горизонте вспухают тяжелые грозовые тучи.</line>
      <line l="en">Heavy thunderheads swell up along the horizon.</line>
      <line l="ua">На обрії набухають важкі грозові хмари.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Небо потемнело, и в духоте запахло близкой грозой.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky darkens, and the sultry air smells of a storm to come.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо потемніло, і в задусі запахло близькою грозою.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">С юго-востока громоздятся черные тучи.</line>
      <line l="en">Black clouds pile up out of the south-east.</line>
      <line l="ua">З південного сходу громадяться чорні хмари.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Раскаленное небо затягивает мутной пеленой.</line>
      <line l="en">The scorched sky veils over with a murky film.</line>
      <line l="ua">Розжарене небо затягує каламутною пеленою.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Тучи копятся, суля долгожданную грозу.</line>
      <line l="en">Clouds build up, boding a long-awaited storm.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари громадяться, віщуючи довгождану грозу.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">С Кровавого моря нагоняет низкие свинцовые тучи.</line>
      <line l="en">Low leaden clouds are driven in off the Bloody Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">З Кривавого Моря наганяє низькі свинцеві хмари.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Небо заволокло сплошной серой хмарью.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky is smothered in unbroken grey overcast.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо заволокло суцільною сірою хмарою.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Тучи сомкнулись наглухо, и стало сумрачно, как в сумерки.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds seal shut, and it grows as gloomy as dusk.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари зімкнулися наглухо, і стало похмуро, як у сутінки.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Осеннее небо набрякло дождем и придавило поля.</line>
      <line l="en">The autumn sky swells with rain and presses down on the fields.</line>
      <line l="ua">Осіннє небо набрякло дощем і придавило поля.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Серая муть затянула небо от края до края.</line>
      <line l="en">Grey murk veils the sky from edge to edge.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сіра каламуть затягла небо від краю до краю.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

  <event id="clouds_clear">
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Тучи разошлись, открыв стеклянно-синее зимнее небо.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds part, baring a glassy-blue winter sky.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари розійшлися, відкривши скляно-синє зимове небо.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Небо расчистилось, и мороз сразу стал злее под ясным Гек Тенгри.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky clears, and the frost bites keener at once under clear Goktengri.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо розчистилося, і мороз одразу став лютіший під ясним Гьок Тенгрі.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Тучи ушли, и над снегами повисло холодное солнце.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds move off, and a cold sun hangs over the snows.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари відійшли, і над снігами зависло холодне сонце.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Снеговые тучи откатились к северу, к Мертвому морю.</line>
      <line l="en">The snow clouds roll back north, toward the Dead Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">Снігові хмари відкотилися на північ, до Мертвого Моря.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Небо очистилось до звонкой синевы, и заискрился иней.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky clears to a ringing blue, and the frost begins to sparkle.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо очистилося до дзвінкої блакиті, і заіскрилася паморозь.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Тучи расходятся, и снова открывается бескрайнее небо Гек Тенгри.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds part, and the boundless sky of Goktengri opens once more.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари розходяться, і знову відкривається безкрає небо Гьок Тенгрі.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Небо расчистилось, и весеннее солнце заиграло на мокрой листве.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky clears, and the spring sun plays on the wet leaves.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо розчистилося, і весняне сонце заграло на мокрому листі.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Облака разбежались, оставив умытую синеву.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds scatter, leaving a rain-washed blue.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари розбіглися, лишивши вмиту блакить.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Тучи растаяли, и запахло свежестью и молодой травой.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds melt away, and the air smells of freshness and young grass.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари розтанули, і запахло свіжістю та молодою травою.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Небо прояснилось, и в вышине зазвенел жаворонок.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky brightens, and high above a lark begins to sing.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо прояснилося, і у високості задзвенів жайворонок.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Тучи разошлись, и на землю обрушился летний зной.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds part, and summer heat crashes back down on the land.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари розійшлися, і на землю ринула літня спека.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Небо очистилось до слепящей синевы Гек Тенгри.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky clears to the blinding blue of Goktengri.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо очистилося до сліпучої блакиті Гьок Тенгрі.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Грозовые тучи ушли, оставив парное умытое небо.</line>
      <line l="en">The thunderheads move off, leaving a steamy, rain-washed sky.</line>
      <line l="ua">Грозові хмари відійшли, лишивши парке вмите небо.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Облака растаяли, и солнце снова взялось печь.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds melt away, and the sun sets back to baking.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари розтанули, і сонце знову взялося пекти.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Небо расчистилось, и над горизонтом встала радуга.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky clears, and a rainbow rises over the horizon.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо розчистилося, і над обрієм встала веселка.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Тучи нехотя расползлись, приоткрыв блеклую синеву.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds drag apart reluctantly, baring a faded blue.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари знехотя розповзлися, відкривши бліду блакить.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Небо расчистилось, но солнце светит скупо и без тепла.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky clears, but the sun shines meanly and without warmth.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо розчистилося, та сонце світить скупо і без тепла.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Серая пелена расползлась, и проглянуло прохладное небо.</line>
      <line l="en">The grey veil pulls apart, and a cool sky peers through.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сіра пелена розповзлася, і визирнуло прохолодне небо.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Тучи откатились к Кровавому морю, оставив ясный холодок.</line>
      <line l="en">The clouds roll back toward the Bloody Sea, leaving a clear chill.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хмари відкотилися до Кривавого Моря, лишивши ясний холодок.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Небо прояснилось ненадолго, обещая скорые заморозки.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky brightens briefly, promising an early frost.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо прояснилося ненадовго, обіцяючи скорі приморозки.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

  <event id="lightning_start">
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">{WМолнии{x вспарывают снеговые тучи -- зимняя гроза, редкая и злая.</line>
      <line l="en">{WLightning{x rips through the snow clouds -- a rare and vicious winter storm.</line>
      <line l="ua">{WБлискавки{x шматують снігові хмари -- зимова гроза, рідкісна і люта.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Сквозь метель полыхнули {Wмолнии{x, и грянул гром.</line>
      <line l="en">{WLightning{x flares through the blizzard, and thunder crashes.</line>
      <line l="ua">Крізь заметіль спалахнули {Wблискавки{x, і вдарив грім.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Тешуб взялся за молот даже в стужу -- небо раскололось огнем.</line>
      <line l="en">Teshub takes up his hammer even in the cold -- the sky splits with fire.</line>
      <line l="ua">Тешуб узявся за молот навіть у холоднечу -- небо розкололося вогнем.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Над мерзлой землей заплясали синие сполохи молний.</line>
      <line l="en">Blue flashes of lightning dance above the frozen earth.</line>
      <line l="ua">Над мерзлою землею затанцювали сині спалахи блискавок.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Ледяной ветер принес грозу с юго-востока, из Пространств Хаоса.</line>
      <line l="en">An icy wind brings a storm from the south-east, out of the Reaches of Chaos.</line>
      <line l="ua">Крижаний вітер приніс грозу з південного сходу, з Просторів Хаосу.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">{WМолнии{x распороли небо -- пришла первая весенняя гроза.</line>
      <line l="en">{WLightning{x tears the sky open -- the first spring storm has come.</line>
      <line l="ua">{WБлискавки{x розпанахали небо -- прийшла перша весняна гроза.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Небо озарилось {Wмолниями{x, и свежо запахло грозой.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky lights up with {Wlightning{x, and the air smells sharp with storm.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо осяялося {Wблискавками{x, і свіжо запахло грозою.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Тешуб пробует молот -- по молодой листве хлещет гроза.</line>
      <line l="en">Teshub tries out his hammer -- a storm lashes the young leaves.</line>
      <line l="ua">Тешуб пробує молот -- по молодому листю шмагає гроза.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Первая гроза года катится с юго-востока, из Пространств Хаоса.</line>
      <line l="en">The year's first storm rolls in from the south-east, out of the Reaches of Chaos.</line>
      <line l="ua">Перша гроза року котиться з південного сходу, з Просторів Хаосу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">{WМолнии{x вспыхнули над полями, и раскатился молодой гром.</line>
      <line l="en">{WLightning{x flashes over the fields, and young thunder rolls out.</line>
      <line l="ua">{WБлискавки{x спалахнули над полями, і розкотився молодий грім.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">{WМолнии{x раскалывают небо -- где-то Тешуб взялся за свой молот.</line>
      <line l="en">{WLightning{x splits the sky -- somewhere Teshub has taken up his hammer.</line>
      <line l="ua">{WБлискавки{x розколюють небо -- десь Тешуб узявся за свій молот.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Тяжелая летняя гроза встала стеной от юго-востока, от Пространств Хаоса.</line>
      <line l="en">A heavy summer storm rises like a wall from the south-east, from the Reaches of Chaos.</line>
      <line l="ua">Важка літня гроза стала стіною з південного сходу, від Просторів Хаосу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Духота лопнула, и небо полыхнуло {Wмолниями{x.</line>
      <line l="en">The sultry air bursts, and the sky blazes with {Wlightning{x.</line>
      <line l="ua">Задуха луснула, і небо спалахнуло {Wблискавками{x.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Гром грянул так, что задрожала земля -- молот Тешуба в полную силу.</line>
      <line l="en">Thunder crashes hard enough to shake the ground -- Teshub's hammer at full force.</line>
      <line l="ua">Грім ударив так, що здригнулася земля -- молот Тешуба на повну силу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Слепящие {Wмолнии{x рвут черное грозовое небо.</line>
      <line l="en">Blinding {Wlightning{x rends the black storm sky.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сліпучі {Wблискавки{x шматують чорне грозове небо.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">{WМолнии{x полыхнули в свинцовых тучах -- поздняя осенняя гроза.</line>
      <line l="en">{WLightning{x flares in the leaden clouds -- a late autumn storm.</line>
      <line l="ua">{WБлискавки{x спалахнули у свинцевих хмарах -- пізня осіння гроза.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Тешуб бьет молотом сквозь холодный ливень.</line>
      <line l="en">Teshub strikes his hammer through the cold downpour.</line>
      <line l="ua">Тешуб б'є молотом крізь холодну зливу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">С юго-востока, из Пространств Хаоса, надвинулась хмурая гроза.</line>
      <line l="en">A sullen storm looms in from the south-east, out of the Reaches of Chaos.</line>
      <line l="ua">З південного сходу, з Просторів Хаосу, насунулася похмура гроза.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Небо распорото {Wмолниями{x, и по лужам хлещет дождь.</line>
      <line l="en">The sky is torn with {Wlightning{x, and rain lashes the puddles.</line>
      <line l="ua">Небо розпанахане {Wблискавками{x, і по калюжах шмагає дощ.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Гром прокатился над озябшими полями, глухой и долгий.</line>
      <line l="en">Thunder rolls over the chilled fields, dull and long.</line>
      <line l="ua">Грім прокотився над змерзлими полями, глухий і довгий.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

  <event id="precip_stop">
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Снегопад стихает, и наступает белая морозная тишина.</line>
      <line l="en">The snowfall dies down, and a white, frozen silence settles in.</line>
      <line l="ua">Снігопад стихає, і настає біла морозна тиша.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Метель улеглась, и снег лежит нетронутым покрывалом.</line>
      <line l="en">The blizzard has died away, and the snow lies in an untouched blanket.</line>
      <line l="ua">Заметіль уляглася, і сніг лежить незайманим покривалом.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Последние снежинки осели, и мир застыл в морозном покое.</line>
      <line l="en">The last snowflakes settle, and the world freezes into frosty stillness.</line>
      <line l="ua">Останні сніжинки осіли, і світ завмер у морозному спокої.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Снег перестал, и над белыми полями повисла тишина.</line>
      <line l="en">The snow has stopped, and silence hangs over the white fields.</line>
      <line l="ua">Сніг перестав, і над білими полями зависла тиша.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Пурга унялась, оставив сугробы и колючий морозный воздух.</line>
      <line l="en">The snowstorm lets up, leaving drifts and sharp, frosty air.</line>
      <line l="ua">Хуртовина вгамувалася, лишивши кучугури і колюче морозне повітря.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Весенний дождь выдохся, и с листьев скатываются капли.</line>
      <line l="en">The spring rain spends itself, and drops slide from the leaves.</line>
      <line l="ua">Весняний дощ видихнувся, і з листя скрапують краплі.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Дождь прошел, и умытый воздух запах свежестью.</line>
      <line l="en">The rain passes, and the washed air smells of freshness.</line>
      <line l="ua">Дощ минув, і вмите повітря запахло свіжістю.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Морось развеялась, и в разрывах туч блеснуло солнце.</line>
      <line l="en">The drizzle disperses, and sun glints through the breaks in the cloud.</line>
      <line l="ua">Мжичка розвіялася, і в розривах хмар блиснуло сонце.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Дождик перестал, и на мокрых ветках защебетали птицы.</line>
      <line l="en">The rain stops, and birds begin to chirp on the wet branches.</line>
      <line l="ua">Дощик перестав, і на мокрих гілках защебетали птахи.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Ливень отступил, оставив звонкие лужи и запах земли.</line>
      <line l="en">The downpour retreats, leaving ringing puddles and the smell of earth.</line>
      <line l="ua">Злива відступила, лишивши дзвінкі калюжі і запах землі.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Летний ливень оборвался так же внезапно, как начался.</line>
      <line l="en">The summer downpour breaks off as suddenly as it began.</line>
      <line l="ua">Літня злива обірвалася так само раптово, як почалася.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Дождь прошел, и от разогретой земли поднялся пар.</line>
      <line l="en">The rain passes, and steam rises from the heated ground.</line>
      <line l="ua">Дощ минув, і від розігрітої землі піднялася пара.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Гроза отгремела, и дождь сошел на нет.</line>
      <line l="en">The storm has thundered itself out, and the rain trails off.</line>
      <line l="ua">Гроза відгриміла, і дощ зійшов нанівець.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Ливень выдохся, оставив свежесть и звонкую капель.</line>
      <line l="en">The downpour spends itself, leaving freshness and ringing drips.</line>
      <line l="ua">Злива видихнулася, лишивши свіжість і дзвінке скрапування.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Дождь кончился, и парная духота снова наползла на землю.</line>
      <line l="en">The rain ends, and steamy closeness creeps back over the land.</line>
      <line l="ua">Дощ скінчився, і парка задуха знову насунула на землю.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Осенний дождь наконец выдохся, оставив мокрый унылый мир.</line>
      <line l="en">The autumn rain finally spends itself, leaving a wet, dreary world.</line>
      <line l="ua">Осінній дощ нарешті видихнувся, лишивши мокрий понурий світ.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Морось перестала, но небо так и осталось серым.</line>
      <line l="en">The drizzle stops, but the sky stays grey all the same.</line>
      <line l="ua">Мжичка перестала, та небо так і лишилося сірим.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Дождь утих, и с голых веток срываются последние капли.</line>
      <line l="en">The rain quiets, and the last drops fall from the bare branches.</line>
      <line l="ua">Дощ ущух, і з голого гілля зриваються останні краплі.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Ливень отступил, оставив хлюпающую грязь и промозглый холод.</line>
      <line l="en">The downpour retreats, leaving squelching mud and a raw chill.</line>
      <line l="ua">Злива відступила, лишивши хлюпку багнюку і промозклий холод.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Дождь иссяк, и над мокрыми полями заклубился туман.</line>
      <line l="en">The rain runs dry, and mist curls up over the wet fields.</line>
      <line l="ua">Дощ вичерпався, і над мокрими полями заклубочився туман.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

  <event id="storm_ease">
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Зимняя гроза откатилась, и снова повалил тихий снег.</line>
      <line l="en">The winter storm rolls off, and quiet snow begins to fall again.</line>
      <line l="ua">Зимова гроза відкотилася, і знову повалив тихий сніг.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Молот Тешуба смолк, и метель улеглась в морозную тишину.</line>
      <line l="en">Teshub's hammer falls silent, and the blizzard settles into frosty stillness.</line>
      <line l="ua">Молот Тешуба стих, і заметіль уляглася в морозну тишу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Сполохи молний угасли над снегами, гром откатился к северу.</line>
      <line l="en">The flashes of lightning die over the snows, and thunder rolls off to the north.</line>
      <line l="ua">Спалахи блискавок згасли над снігами, грім відкотився на північ.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Гроза утихла, и мороз тут же взялся сковывать талый снег.</line>
      <line l="en">The storm dies down, and the frost sets at once to locking the melted snow.</line>
      <line l="ua">Гроза вщухла, і мороз одразу взявся сковувати талий сніг.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="winter">
      <line l="ru">Гром смолк, и над стылой землей повисла белая тишь.</line>
      <line l="en">The thunder falls quiet, and a white hush hangs over the frozen land.</line>
      <line l="ua">Грім стих, і над холодною землею зависла біла тиша.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Весенняя гроза откатилась, оставив ровный шум дождя.</line>
      <line l="en">The spring storm rolls off, leaving the steady hiss of rain.</line>
      <line l="ua">Весняна гроза відкотилася, лишивши рівний шум дощу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Молот Тешуба стих вдали, и над полями встала радуга.</line>
      <line l="en">Teshub's hammer falls quiet in the distance, and a rainbow rises over the fields.</line>
      <line l="ua">Молот Тешуба стих удалині, і над полями встала веселка.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Молнии унялись, и дождь стал теплым и ласковым.</line>
      <line l="en">The lightning settles, and the rain turns warm and gentle.</line>
      <line l="ua">Блискавки вгамувалися, і дощ став теплим і лагідним.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Гроза ушла на запад, и посвежевший воздух зазвенел птицами.</line>
      <line l="en">The storm moves off to the west, and the freshened air rings with birds.</line>
      <line l="ua">Гроза відійшла на захід, і посвіжіле повітря задзвеніло птахами.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="spring">
      <line l="ru">Гром откатился, оставив умытую зелень и капли на ветках.</line>
      <line l="en">The thunder rolls away, leaving rain-washed green and drops on the branches.</line>
      <line l="ua">Грім відкотився, лишивши вмиту зелень і краплі на гіллі.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Гроза понемногу утихает, молний больше нет.</line>
      <line l="en">The storm eases little by little; the lightning is gone.</line>
      <line l="ua">Гроза потроху вщухає, блискавок більше немає.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Молот Тешуба смолкает вдали, остается лишь ровный шум дождя.</line>
      <line l="en">Teshub's hammer falls quiet in the distance, leaving only the steady hiss of rain.</line>
      <line l="ua">Молот Тешуба стихає вдалині, лишається тільки рівний шум дощу.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Гроза откатилась за горизонт, и от земли повалил густой пар.</line>
      <line l="en">The storm rolls off beyond the horizon, and thick steam rises from the ground.</line>
      <line l="ua">Гроза відкотилася за обрій, і від землі повалила густа пара.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Молнии отгуляли, и над остывшими полями протянулась радуга.</line>
      <line l="en">The lightning has run its course, and a rainbow stretches over the cooled fields.</line>
      <line l="ua">Блискавки відгуляли, і над охололими полями простяглася веселка.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="summer">
      <line l="ru">Гром удаляется, ворча, и ливень сходит на ровный шелест.</line>
      <line l="en">The thunder recedes, grumbling, and the downpour eases to a steady patter.</line>
      <line l="ua">Грім віддаляється, буркочучи, і злива спадає до рівного шелесту.</line>
    </variant>

    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Осенняя гроза отгремела, и зарядил ровный холодный дождь.</line>
      <line l="en">The autumn storm has thundered out, and a steady cold rain sets in.</line>
      <line l="ua">Осіння гроза відгриміла, і зарядив рівний холодний дощ.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Молот Тешуба стих, оставив промозглую морось.</line>
      <line l="en">Teshub's hammer falls silent, leaving a raw drizzle.</line>
      <line l="ua">Молот Тешуба стих, лишивши промозклу мжичку.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Молнии угасли в тучах, и гром уполз к Кровавому морю.</line>
      <line l="en">The lightning dies in the clouds, and thunder crawls off toward the Bloody Sea.</line>
      <line l="ua">Блискавки згасли у хмарах, і грім уповз до Кривавого Моря.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Гроза утихла, но небо так и осталось свинцовым.</line>
      <line l="en">The storm dies down, but the sky stays leaden all the same.</line>
      <line l="ua">Гроза вщухла, та небо так і лишилося свинцевим.</line>
    </variant>
    <variant season="autumn">
      <line l="ru">Гром откатился вдаль, и по лужам зашуршал унылый дождь.</line>
      <line l="en">The thunder rolls off into the distance, and a dreary rain rustles on the puddles.</line>
      <line l="ua">Грім відкотився вдалину, і по калюжах зашурхотів понурий дощ.</line>
    </variant>
  </event>

</weather>
