<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Command>
  <cat></cat>
  <extra>keep_hide ghost</extra>
  <help id="1042" level="102" ref="wizlock" type="CommandHelp">
    <text l="en">%FMT%  *%CMD%*
%FFF%  *wizlock*

Wizlock and newlock prevent attempts to enter the MUD. Wizlock blocks
the entry of non-gods (i.e. with a level &lt; 102), an exception is made for players
who lost connection and are trying to get back in. Newlock only blocks
the creation of new characters, this is a typical measure against spam.
Wizlock should be avoided, and the introduction of newlock should be
announced in advance via internal mail.

Gods must have a Supreme level or higher to switch the game to wizlock mode.
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT%  *%CMD%*
%FFF%  *wizlock*

Wizlock и newlock блокируют попытки входа в MUD. Wizlock блокирует
вход не-богов (т.е. с уровнем &lt; 102), исключение делается для игроков,
потерявших соединение, и пытающихся зайти опять. Newlock блокирует
только создание новых персонажей, это типичная мера против спама(spam).
Wizlock лучше избегать, а введение newlock должно быть предварительно
сообщено путем внутренней почты.

Боги должны иметь уровень не меньше Supreme для перевода игры в режим wizlock.
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT%  *%CMD%*
%FFF%  *wizlock*

Wizlock і newlock блокують спроби входу в MUD. Wizlock блокує
вхід не-богів (тобто з рівнем &lt; 102), виняток робиться для гравців,
які втратили з'єднання і намагаються зайти знову. Newlock блокує
лише створення нових персонажів, це типова міра проти спаму.
Варто уникати використання wizlock, а введення newlock має бути
попередньо оголошено за допомогою внутрішньої пошти.

Боги повинні мати рівень не нижче Supreme для переведення гри у режим wizlock.
</text>
  </help>
  <hint l="en">prohibit the creation of new characters</hint>
  <hint l="ru">запретить создание новых персонажей</hint>
  <hint l="ua">заборонити створення нових персонажів</hint>
  <level>108</level>
  <log>1</log>
  <name l="en">newlock</name>
  <name l="ru"></name>
  <name l="ua"></name>
  <position>dead</position>
</Command>