<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Help type="HelpContainer">
  <node id="68" labels="info" level="-1" type="Help">
    <extra l="en">bots dreamland multicharing multing rules world worldrules</extra>
    <extra l="ru">альт автоматизация ботоводство боты мечты мира мультинг передача &apos;правила мира&apos; твинк вещей законы мультоводство</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <keyword l="en">game rules</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">игровые правила</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">Our goal is to maintain a fun and interesting game atmosphere. We want to give all players
the opportunity and freedom to enjoy the game and the community. But freedom does not mean
enjoying yourself at the expense of insulting or humiliating others. That is why these rules
exist.

Violation of any of these rules may be grounds for punishing your character (up to and
including deletion). Compliance with the rules is overseen by the {hh92Immortals{x. Ignorance of the
rules {Rdoes not exempt you from responsibility{x for breaking them.
 
{R%A% {xAny disrespect toward players and the Immortals of the Dreamworld, or toward the World
itself, is entirely unacceptable. This world {ybans profanity{x and outright abuse directed at anyone
or anything. It is forbidden to threaten or insult players on the basis of racial or ethnic origin,
gender, sexual orientation, religious beliefs, and so on. You should also refrain from settling
disputes between players in {hh1059public channels{x.

{R%A% {xIt is strictly forbidden to {yexploit bugs{x found in the program. If you have
found a mistake or bug -- {hh996report it to the Gods{x and do not use it. It is dishonest and can
disrupt the game for other players -- especially bugs that cause the World to crash. Those
guilty of exploiting bugs will be severely punished.

{R%A% {yThe Immortals deserve respect{x -- they are here to maintain the game atmosphere.
For example, do not ask an invisible Immortal who he or she is, and certainly do not repeat a
question or request multiple times -- the Immortals may be busy at that moment. To reach one of
the Gods quickly, use external channels, for example {hh66Telegram or Discord{x.

{R%A% {yBe careful with titles and descriptions.{x {hh1007Titles{x and {hh1083descriptions{x that
insult players or Immortals are strictly forbidden. It is also better to avoid titles that are
provocative or inconsistent with your race, level, or class. Read the help {y{hc? description{x
and {y{hc? title{x -- there is a lot of useful advice there.

{R%A% {yMultiplaying is forbidden{x (having more than one character in the world simultaneously),
and especially having one of your characters assist another in any form, including casting and
help with money or items -- directly, via other players, or any other way. The punishment for
this is prison, a ban, or {Rcharacter deletion{x. Remember to type the {y{hcexit{x command with one
character before logging into the world with another. Also forbidden are "storage characters"
for {hh42limits{x -- such characters will be immediately deleted and their owners punished. Nobody
likes cheaters and hoarders.

Among other ways of detecting multiplaying, the Gods look at IP addresses. That is, if someone
"handed you a character" and you logged into it from the same IP address as another character --
you will both be punished for multiplaying. Do not hand characters over to others.

{R%A% {yBotting{x is not forbidden, but it is certainly not encouraged. All manner of things
can happen to characters left unattended on automatic triggers or scripts, and their safety
is not guaranteed.

{R%A% {xThe {ylanguages of communication{x accepted in our world are {yUkrainian and Russian{x.
English is permitted, but keep in mind that not all players will understand it. Try not to use
transliteration (writing Cyrillic text in Latin letters), as screen readers do not handle it well.

{R%A% {ySpamming is forbidden{x, especially in public channels and notes. It disrupts other
players. This also applies to settling disputes between players in any form and to heavy floods
on topics unrelated to the game.

{R%A% {ySexual harassment is forbidden in any form.{x If your partner has not given prior
consent to the use of certain {hh1061emotes{x or {hh1095socials{x, especially provocative or intimate ones,
it is better not to use them. Also, do not immediately use socials on other players when you do
not know what they do -- you can end up in a very unpleasant situation. First study
'help &lt;social name&gt;'.

{R%A% {xThese rules also apply to out-of-game communication channels, for example
{hh66Telegram and Discord{x -- in those channels spam, flooding, extreme disrespect, profanity, and
insults are likewise forbidden. The line between friendly ribbing and deliberate trolling --
hopefully you can find it yourself. In those channels the rule of {hh1063OOC{x (out of character)
applies -- meaning you may not insult anyone on the basis of {hh31roleplay{x, clan diplomacy,
or other purely in-game factors.

{R%A% {xIf the Immortals have punished your character and you are TRULY certain that
a mistake has been made -- write to dreamland.mud@gmail.com

{R%A% {xChanges to the rules may be made by the Immortals without additional
warning or notice. Our apologies.
 
These rules are simple, logical, and clearly enough worded. If you are caught breaking them --
you WILL be punished. The Immortals themselves decide on the appropriateness and severity of
the punishment.
</text>
    <text l="ru">Наша цель -- поддержание веселой и интересной игровой атмосферы. Мы хотим дать возможность и свободу всем игрокам получить удовольствие от игры и общения с сообществом. Но свобода не значит получение удовольствия за счет оскорбления или унижения других. Поэтому существуют эти правила.

Нарушение любого из этих правил может стать основанием для наказания твоего персонажа (вплоть до удаления). За соблюдением правил следят {hh92Бессмертные{x. Незнание правил {Rне освобождает от ответственности{x за их нарушение.
 
{R%A% {xЛюбое неуважение к игрокам и Бессмертным Мира Мечты, а также и самому Миру,
крайне недопустимо. В этом мире {yзапрещены нецензурные выражения{x и откровенная ругань по отношению к кому-либо или чему-либо. Запрещено угрожать и оскорблять игроков на основании расовой или этнической принадлежности, пола, сексуальной ориентации, религиозных убеждений и так далее. Также следует воздержаться от выяснения отношений между игроками в {hh1059общих каналах{x.

{R%A% {xКатегорически запрещено {yиспользовать найденные ошибки{x в программе. Если ты
наш{Smел{Sfла{Sx ошибку или баг -- {hh996сообщи о ней Богам{x и не используй ее. Это нечестно и может нарушить игру других игроков -- особенно ошибки, приводящие к падению Мира. Виновные в эксплуатации багов будут жестоко наказаны.

{R%A% {yБессмертных стоит уважать{x -- они призваны поддерживать игровую атмосферу.
Например, не стоит спрашивать невидимого Бессмертного, кто он или она такая, и уж точно не стоит по нескольку раз повторять вопрос или просьбу -- Бессмертные могут быть в данный момент чем-то заняты. Чтобы быстро связаться с кем-то из Богов используй внешние каналы, например, {hh66Телеграм или Дискорд{x.

{R%A% {yОсторожней с титулами и описаниями.{x Строго запрещены {hh1007титулы{x и {hh1083описания{x, 
оскорбляющие игроков или Бессмертных. Вызывающих или не соответствующих твоей расе, уровню или классу титулов тоже лучше избегать. Почитай справку {y{hc? описание{x и {y{hc? титул{x, там много полезных советов.

{R%A% {yЗапрещен мультинг{x (одновременное нахождение в мире несколькими персонажами),
а тем более помощь одним твоим персонажем другому в любом виде, включая обкаст и помощь деньгами либо вещами -- непосредственно, передачей через других игроков или как-либо еще. Наказание за это -- тюрьма, бан или {Rудаление персонажа{x. Не забывай писать команду {y{hcвыход{x одним персонажем перед заходом в мир другим. Также запрещены &quot;персонажи-хранилища&quot; {hh42лимитов{x -- таковые будут немедленно удалены, а их владельцы -- наказаны. Читеров и жадин никто не любит.

Среди прочих способов определить мультинг Боги смотрят на айпи адрес. То есть если тебе &quot;передали персонажа&quot; и ты им зашел с одного айпи-адреса с другим персонажем -- вы оба будете наказаны за мультинг. Не надо передавать персонажей.

{R%A% {yБотоводство{x не запрещено, но отнюдь не приветствуется. С персонажами,
оставленными без надзора на автоматических триггерах или скриптах, всякое может случиться, и их безопасность не гарантирована. 

{R%A% {xПринятыми в нашем мире {yязыками общения{x являются {yукраинский и русский{x. 
Английский допустим, но нужно учитывать, что его поймут не все игроки. Старайся не использовать транслит (запись кириллического текста латиницей), так как его нормально не читают скринридеры.

{R%A% {yСпамить нельзя{x, особенно в общих каналах и нотах. Это мешает другим игрокам.
Сюда же относится выяснение отношений между игроками в любом виде и обильный флуд на темы, не имеющие отношения к игре. 

{R%A% {yСексуальные домогательства запрещены в любом виде.{x Если твой партнер или
партнерша заранее не выразили согласия на использования определенных {hh1061эмоций{x или {hh1095социалов{x, особенно вызывающего или интимного характера, применять их лучше не стоит. Также не стоит сразу применять по отношению к другим игрокам социалы, действие которых тебе неизвестно. Можно попасть в очень неприятную ситуацию. Сперва изучи &apos;справка &lt;название социала&gt;&apos;.

{R%A% {xЭти правила распространяются и на околоигровые каналы связи, например
{hh66Телеграм и Дискорд{x -- в этих каналах также запрещен спам, флуд, крайнее неуважение, мат и оскорбления. Границу между дружескими подколками и намеренным троллингом, надеюсь, ты сможешь найти сам{Sfа{Sx. В этих каналах действует правило {hh1063OOC{x (вне персонажа) -- это значит, что нельзя оскорблять кого-либо на основе {hh31отыгрыша{x, клановой дипломатии и других сугубо игровых факторов.

{R%A% {xЕсли Бессмертные наказали твоего персонажа, и ты ДЕЙСТВИТЕЛЬНО уверен{Sfа{Sx, что
произошла ошибка -- напиши письмо на адрес dreamland.mud@gmail.com

{R%A% {xИзменения в законах могут проводиться Бессмертными без дополнительного
предупреждения или уведомления. Уж простите.
 
Эти правила просты, логичны и достаточно четко сформулированы. Если тебя поймают за их нарушением -- ты БУДЕШЬ наказан{Sfа{Sx. Уместность и меру наказания Бессмертные выбирают сами.
</text>
    <text l="ua">Наша мета -- підтримувати веселу й цікаву ігрову атмосферу. Ми хочемо дати
можливість і свободу всім гравцям насолоджуватися грою й спілкуванням зі спільнотою.
Але свобода не означає отримувати задоволення за рахунок образи чи приниження інших.
Тому й існують ці правила.

Порушення будь-якого з цих правил може стати підставою для покарання твого персонажа
(аж до видалення). За дотриманням правил стежать {hh92Безсмертні{x. Незнання правил {Rне
звільняє від відповідальності{x за іх порушення.
 
{R%A% {xБудь-яка неповага до гравців і Безсмертних Світу Мрii, а також до самого Світу,
вкрай неприпустима. У цьому світі {yзаборонені нецензурні вирази{x і відверта лайка
стосовно кого-небудь або чого-небудь. Забороняється погрожувати й ображати гравців
на підставі расовоі чи етнічноі належності, статі, сексуальноі орієнтацii, релігійних
переконань тощо. Також слід утримуватися від зʼясування стосунків між гравцями в
{hh1059загальних каналах{x.

{R%A% {xКатегорично забороняється {yвикористовувати знайдені помилки{x у програмі. Якщо ти
знайшов{Sfла{Sx помилку або баг -- {hh996повідом про неі Богам{x і не використовуй ii. Це нечесно
і може порушити гру інших гравців -- особливо помилки, що призводять до падіння Світу.
Винні в експлуатацii багів будуть жорстоко покарані.

{R%A% {yБезсмертних варто поважати{x -- вони покликані підтримувати ігрову атмосферу.
Наприклад, не варто питати невидимого Безсмертного, хто він або вона, і вже точно не
варто кілька разів повторювати запитання чи прохання -- Безсмертні можуть бути в цей
момент чимось зайняті. Щоб швидко звʼязатися з кимось із Богів, використовуй зовнішні
канали, наприклад {hh66Телеграм або Діскорд{x.

{R%A% {yОбережніше з титулами й описами.{x Суворо заборонені {hh1007титули{x і {hh1083описи{x, що
ображають гравців або Безсмертних. Відвертих або невідповідних твоій расі, рівню
чи класу титулів теж краще уникати. Почитай довідку {y{hc? опис{x і {y{hc? титул{x -- там
багато корисних порад.

{R%A% {yМультинг заборонений{x (одночасна присутність у світі кількома персонажами),
а тим паче допомога одним твоім персонажем іншому в будь-якому вигляді, включно
з обкастом і допомогою грошима або речами -- безпосередньо, передачею через інших
гравців або будь-яким іншим чином. Покарання за це -- вʼязниця, бан або {Rвидалення
персонажа{x. Не забувай вводити команду {y{hcвихід{x одним персонажем перед входом у світ
іншим. Також заборонені "персонажі-сховища" {hh42лімітів{x -- такі будуть негайно видані,
а іхні власники -- покарані. Читерів і жадюг ніхто не любить.

Серед інших способів визначити мультинг Боги дивляться на IP-адресу. Тобто якщо
тобі "передали персонажа" і ти зайшов{Sfла{Sx з ним з одноі IP-адреси з іншим персонажем --
вас обох покарають за мультинг. Не треба передавати персонажів.

{R%A% {yБотоводство{x не заборонене, але аж ніяк не вітається. З персонажами,
залишеними без нагляду на автоматичних тригерах або скриптах, може статися
всяке, і іхня безпека не гарантована.

{R%A% {xПрийнятими в нашому світі {yмовами спілкування{x є {yукраінська та російська{x.
Англійська допустима, але треба враховувати, що ii зрозуміють не всі гравці. Намагайся
не використовувати трансліт (запис кириличного тексту латиницею), бо його нормально
не читають скрінридери.

{R%A% {yСпамити не можна{x, особливо в загальних каналах і нотах. Це заважає іншим гравцям.
Сюди ж відноситься зʼясування стосунків між гравцями в будь-якому вигляді й рясний
флуд на теми, що не стосуються гри.

{R%A% {yСексуальні домагання заборонені в будь-якому вигляді.{x Якщо твій партнер або
твоя партнерка заздалегідь не виявили згоди на використання певних {hh1061емоцій{x або
{hh1095соціалів{x, особливо відвертого чи інтимного характеру, застосовувати іх краще
не варто. Також не варто одразу застосовувати до інших гравців соціали, дію яких
ти не знаєш -- можна потрапити в дуже неприємну ситуацію. Спершу вивчи
'довідка &lt;назва соціалу&gt;'.

{R%A% {xЦі правила поширюються й на позаігрові канали звʼязку, наприклад
{hh66Телеграм і Діскорд{x -- у цих каналах теж заборонені спам, флуд, крайня неповага,
мат і образи. Межу між дружніми підколками й навмисним тролінгом, сподіваємось,
ти зможеш знайти сам{Sfа{Sx. У цих каналах діє правило {hh1063OOC{x (поза персонажем) --
це означає, що не можна ображати кого-небудь на підставі {hh31рольовоі гри{x,
клановоі дипломатii та інших суто ігрових чинників.

{R%A% {xЯкщо Безсмертні покарали твого персонажа і ти СПРАВДІ впевнен{Sfа{Sx, що
сталася помилка -- напиши листа на адресу dreamland.mud@gmail.com

{R%A% {xЗміни в правилах можуть вноситися Безсмертними без додаткового
попередження або повідомлення. Вибачте вже.
 
Ці правила прості, логічні й достатньо чітко сформульовані. Якщо тебе зловлять
на іх порушенні -- ти БУДЕШ покаран{Sfа{Sx. Доречність і міру покарання Безсмертні
обирають самі.
</text>
    <title l="en"></title>
    <title l="ru">{CИгровые правила Мира Мечты{x</title>
    <title l="ua"></title>
  </node>
  <node id="69" labels="system" level="-1" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">greeting</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">%PAUSE%DREAMLAND 4.0 by Ruffina, Filths, Taiphoen, Kerrad, Bast (&apos;help credits&apos;)

         ,&quot;|          $$$$$$$$   $$$$$$$    $$$$$$$$      $$      $$$$     $$$$
           A           $$    $$   $$   $$    $$   $$      $$       $$$      $$
          / \  ,&quot;|     $$     $$  $$   $$    $$ $  $     $ $$      $$$$    $$$
    ,&quot;|  [&quot;&quot;M#   A     $$     $$  $$$$$$     $$$$       $   $$     $$ $$  $ $$
      A   | #   /.\    $$     $$  $$   $$    $$ $  $   $$$$$$$$    $$  $$$  $$
     /.\ [&quot;&quot;M# [&quot;&quot;M#   $$    $$   $$    $$   $$   $$  $$     $$$   $$   $   $$
    [&quot;&quot;M# | #  U&quot;U#U  $$$$$$$$   $$$$   $$$ $$$$$$$$ $$$$   $$$$$ $$$$     $$$$
     | #  | #  \ .:/
     | #  | #___| #         $$$$          $$      $$$$  $$$$$  $$$$$$$$
     | &quot;--&apos;     .-&quot;          $$           $$       $$$$  $$$    $$    $$
   |&quot;-&quot;-&quot;-&quot;-&quot;-#-#-##         $$          $ $$       $ $$  $     $$     $$
   | D   # ## ######         $$         $   $$      $  $$ $     $$     $$
    \ L     .::::&apos;/          $$   $    $$$$$$$$     $   $$$     $$     $$
     \      ::::&apos;/           $$  $$   $$     $$$   $$$   $$$    $$    $$
   :8a|    # # ##           $$$$$$$$ $$$$   $$$$$ $$$$$  $$$$  $$$$$$$$
   ::88a      ###   
  ::::::888a88aLA                       
 :::::::::::::::a8a	             https://dreamland.rocks
 :::::8::::888:Y8888               telnet dreamland.rocks 9000   
:: ::::88a::::88a:Y88a         
&apos; .: ::Y88a:::::8a:Y88a
.::  :::Y88as88a...s88aa

1. KOI8-U    2. ALT (CP866)   3. WIN (CP1251)   4. ISO (ISO-8859-5) 
5. MAC       6. Translit      7. UTF-8
Please select your Ukrainian or Russian codepage: 
</text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
  </node>
  <node id="70" labels="system" level="-1" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">newyeargreeting</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">%PAUSE%{Y           . &quot; -.
          &apos;       .
         .   {W({Y    . {C$$$$$$$$   $$$$$$$    $$$$$$$$      $$      $$$$     $$$$
             {W(){Y  .&apos;  {C$$    $$   $$   $$    $$   $$      $$       $$$      $$
          {Y`. {W`|{Y,.    {C$$     $$  $$   $$    $$ $  $     $ $$      $$$$    $$$
       {m      |&quot;|     {C$$     $$  $$$$$$     $$$$       $   $$     $$ $$  $ $$
             {M({m |     {C$$     $$  $$   $$    $$ $  $   $$$$$$$$    $$  $$$  $$
             {m|{M\{m|     {C$$    $$   $$    $$   $$   $$  $$     $$$   $$   $   $$
             {m| {M)    {C$$$$$$$$   $$$$   $$$ $$$$$$$$ $$$$   $$$$$ $$$$     $$$$
             {M( {m|                      
             {m|{M\{m|    {g _    {C$$$$          $$      $$$$  $$$$$  $$$$$$$$
 {G.\|,{m      {g_{m | {M){g _.-{G&gt;J     {C$$           $$       $$$$  $$$    $$    $$
 {G-&gt;{gJ|{G/, .  \{g&quot;&quot;{G-&quot;{G&quot;/{GVl/z     {C$$          $ $$       $ $$  $     $$     $$
  {G&apos;-t{gX|b{G|\|{g\^\k\^y{GJr/&apos;     {C$$         $   $$      $  $$ $     $$     $$
   {G&apos;^-{gj/PZ{G=\{gR&gt;p/{GT|&apos;        {C$$   $    $$$$$$$$     $   $$$     $$     $$
     {G._{g-s{GF{gK)/{G|&apos;&quot;           {C$$  $$   $$     $$$   $$$   $$$    $$    $$
    {G_-{gzH{G|/{y|               {C$$$$$$$$ $$$$   $$$$$ $$$$$  $$$$  $$$$$$$$
   {G--{g%/{G|  {y|                     
   {G&apos;/{g|{y    |                             
         {Y_{yM{Y_                     {Whttp://dreamland.rocks
      {Y,&apos;&quot;{Y_{Y  &quot;`.                {Wtelnet dreamland.rocks 9000 
     {Y/  {Y(_){Y    \             
    {Y|          {y.{Y|       
    {Y:         {y.:{Y;       
     {Y\ {Y`._   {y.:{Y/          {w1) KOI8-U          4) ISO (ISO-8859-5)   7) UTF-8 
      {Y`._ {y..:{Y;&apos;           {w2) ALT (CP866)     5) MAC
         {Y&quot;&quot;&quot;{x              {w3) WIN (CP1251)    6) Transliteration
Please, select your Ukrainian or Russian codepage:</text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
  </node>
  <node id="71" labels="system" level="102" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">rom2anatolia whatsnew</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">.
%PAUSE%* ROM BUGs are fixed.
* PlayerKilling and Stealing is permitted for all levels, within
  restrictions of course. * 7 Clans are implemented with special skills and spells. * If one clan is raided and its item is taken and put to anothers clan
  shrine, the raided clan cannot use their clan powers. * New 8 classes are added with full features. * New 14 races are added with full features. * Clan only, race only, alignment only spells and skills implemented. * Some channels are removed (gossip,auction). * New auction channel introduced. * Over 200 new skills and spells are introduced. * New practicing type is introduced. * Damagable and repairable equipments are introduced. * Bank is implemented. * Color code is inserted. * Mobiles started to track last foughts. * Spells castable to room (room affects, do_raffect command) are implemented. * Good players can request objects from good mobs. * Anti-Paladins can demand objects from any mob (chance of attacking). * Automatic rebooting system is implemented. * New areas are added. * Objects and Mobile progs are implemented. * Ice melts in hot areas. * New score command is introduced.( One can use old one with nscore command) * In who command, one can restrict the clans, races or PKs. * Players can pray the gods by pray channel. * Automaticaly generated quest is introduced. * Hero players can teach their 100% skills or spells to other players. * Tailed mobile can now attack with their tails. * When you look a mob, you can see its race. * Hometowns and ethos are implemented. * Religions and their related tattos are implemented * Special quest kassandra (please read the referred books in melancholy).

</text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
  </node>
  <node id="72" labels="system" level="102" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">from20to21</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">.
%PAUSE%* Reported bugs are fixed.
* Track has been rearranged. * Players become able to shoot arrows, throwing spears with full features:
	poisoning, shocking, burning, frosting arrows and spears
	stuck in arrows and spears. * Shot arrows or thrown spears may be stuck in the target mobiles. * Riding skill is given to knights. * In groups shalafi vs battle, chaos vs ruler, invader vs knight is prevented * Spellbane become permanent with no cost of mana. * Blade barrier, aid, desert fist,gate spells are given to clerics. * Chance of damaging an object reduced. * Tracking mobiles become able to open door. * Golems autorescue their masters. * If created golem kills master&apos;s quest mob, it is ok as well. * Area flags introduced. * Next questtimes has been rearranged. * Quest code reconstructed. * Vampire became immune to negative attacks. * Immunity to negative spell is given to necromancer. * Spell craft adjustment done. * Lance skill is given to knights for mount. * Secondary attack given to warrior class.(Second attack for dual) * Making arrow (blue,red,white,green) skills given to Ranger. * Dishonoring is now optional for Samurais. * Chance of tattoos has been increased. * Is_same_group is reorganized. * Leadership spell is given to rulers( immunity to charm). * Evil spirit spell is given to invaders. * Mortal strike skill is given to battleragers. * Now offensive spells are castable to other rooms, as well:
	cast &apos;acid blast&apos; n.fido
	cast &apos;acid blast&apos; e.2.fido * Mobiles starts to remember the players that once fight with them, untill
  they are killed, or anatolia is rebooted. * Races of mobiles is now a header of mobiles description. * PC&apos;s can speak either common language or their mothertongue. * Only magical lights now can damage vampires. * Track skill is now only for rangers. * Shout and yell channels cannot be ON/OFF. * Spell craft rearranged.

</text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
  </node>
  <node id="73" labels="system" level="-1" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">diku</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">.%PAUSE% Original game idea, concept, and design:

          Katja Nyboe [Superwoman] (katz@freja.diku.dk)
          Tom Madsen [Stormbringer] (noop@freja.diku.dk)
          Hans Henrik Staerfeldt [God] (bombman@freja.diku.dk)
          Michael Seifert [Papi] (seifert@freja.diku.dk)
          Sebastian Hammer [Quinn] (quinn@freja.diku.dk)

Developed at: DIKU -- The Department of Computer Science
                      at the University of Copenhagen.
</text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
  </node>
  <node id="74" labels="system" level="-1" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">merc</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">%PAUSE%This mud is based on Merc 2.2, created by Furey, Hatchet, and Kahn. 
Merc 2.1 is available as Merc_22.tar.gz from ftp.game.org 

Thanks to ...
  ... Diku Mud for starting it all.
  ... The Free Software Foundation and DJ Delorie for kick-ass tools.
  ... Copper Mud and Alfa Mud for releasing their code and worlds.
  ... Aod of Generic for ... well, everything. You&apos;re a hoopy frood, Aod.
  ... Alander for many ideas and contributions.
  ... John Brothers of Silly for permission to use Silly code and worlds.
  ... Zrin for administering the mailing list.
  ... Abaddon for proofreading our comm.c.
  ... Hind, Quin, Vic, Diavolo, Oleg, Trienne, and others for porting help.
  ... Diavolo, Grodyn, Morgenes, and others for code and bug fixes.
  ... Raff, Doctor, VampLestat, Nirrad, Tyrst, PinkF, Chris, Glop for worlds.
  ... the players and imps of Mud Dome, Final Mud, Mud Lite, Vego Mud, Rivers
      of Mud, Ruhr Mud, and Mystic Realms for bug reports, ideas, new code,
      and hours of enjoyment.

</text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
  </node>
  <node id="75" labels="system" level="-1" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">rom</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">ROM started in early February 1993, using Merc 1.0 code. In July of 1993, ROM II was started, eventually replacing the original ROM. ROM was up for a little over a year, after which the code (version 2.3) was released, and various other ROM muds were started, including Rivers of Mud under a new management (Zump&apos;s ROM), at rom.org 9000.

Alander&apos;s current project is Tesseract, the latest version of the ROM code. It can be found at hypercube.org 9000.

The following people contributed to the ROM flavor of the merc base code:

Socials --
    Kelsey and Liralen

New, Improved Valhalla --
    Liralen

Puff&apos;s new special proc and improved poofin/poofout code --
    Seth

Maps and map shop --
    Ezra, Regnan (Olympus)

Nirvana zone --
    Forstall (mobiles rewritten by Alander)

Mob Factory --
    Pinkfloyd (originally written for ROM, mobiles rewritten by Alander)

Geographically correct Midgaard (tm) --
    Alander

Ideas and playtesting --
    Thousands of dedicated mudders around the world

Beta testing --
    Ken Blosser, Doug Araya, and Sherene Neil all helped with bug reports
    and suggestions, saving a lot of headaches

New Thalos area was donated by Onivel of Jedi, who was also the originator of the ASCII flags used in the zone files

ROM 2.4 was developed during my time with Moosehead mud, and the release shares many of the features I wrote while I was there. Additional code was written by Seth Scott (the new poofin/poofout), and many contributions and ideas from the Merc list were used. 

The new features of 2.4 were largely produced in bull sessions with Gabrielle (my wife) and Brian Moore, without whom this release wouldn&apos;t have happened. In particular, the new privacy code, furniture, and wiznet are largely the results of Gabrielle&apos;s ideas.

Changes to the standard diku mob and object format, as well as the changes to Merc 2.1 source code, were done by Alander over many a late night of hair-pulling. Hope you enjoy it.

(my apologies if anyone was forgotten in this list)
</text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
  </node>
  <node id="76" labels="system" level="-1" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">anatolia</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">анатолия</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">. 
      ANATOLIA started in early September 1996, using Rom2.4 code. In June of 1997, ANATOLIA II was started, eventually replacing the original
ANATOLIA.

The following people contributed to the ANATOLIA flavor of the ROM base code:

Addition of New Areas --
	Ibrahim Canpunar, Serdar Bulut and Murat Bicer

Revision of New Areas --
	Ibrahim Canpunar

Revision and Addition of New Helps --
	Ibrahim Canpunar and Serdar Bulut

Additional Maps --
	Ibrahim Canpunar

Ideas and playtesting --
    So many dedicated mudders around the world. Especially Amac Ural, Mustafa Ongel, Ibrahim Uzel, Rasit Gumus, David Heide.

Complete C Code --
	chiefly by Serdar Bulut,
        with major contributions by Murat Bicer,
        and also Ibrahim Canpunar and Devrim Baris Acar. 

Used snippets (Available on internet) --
	Quest Code (c) 1996 Ryan Addams (moongate@moongate.ams.com)
	Some snippets by Erwin S. Andreasen. 
		erwin@pip.dknet.dk
</text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
    <title l="en"></title>
    <title l="ru">Кодовая база ANATOLIA</title>
    <title l="ua"></title>
  </node>
  <node id="77" labels="system" level="-1" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">backdoorgreeting</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">Welcome to Dream Land building plot. The address of this world is
       telnet dreamland.rocks 9000 
              http://dreamland.rocks
     
1) KOI8-U 4) ISO (ISO-8859-5) 7) UTF-8
2) ALT (CP866) 5) MAC
3) WIN (CP1251) 6) Transliteration Input your &lt;codepage&gt; &lt;username&gt; &lt;password&gt;: 
</text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
  </node>
  <node id="79" labels="info" level="-1" type="Help">
    <keyword l="en">about dreamland.rocks introduction</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">дримленд дримлэнд &apos;мир грез&apos; &apos;мир мечты&apos; &apos;мир снов&apos; вступление вводная</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">In the {CDreamworld{x you can live dozens of lives and walk many paths: Good and Evil, sword and magic, bloody killer and holy nun, wise wizard and raving berserker-warrior. The supreme value of this world is FREEDOM -- your character can become anything you desire, anything you ever dreamed of.

{CThe Dreamworld{x is a text game, you will have to read a lot and type often. If you start playing in our web client, it will be much more convenient -- many things you can do just by clicking buttons and links on the screen. But besides that you will sometimes need to type {hh1079commands{x in the input field. For example, *wear sword* or *cast shield*.

Absolute freedom means freedom to choose who you want to become. You can inhabit the body of any of 25 {hh54sentient races{x -- human or elf, giant or dwarf. You can fight on the side of Good or Evil, or you can maintain {hh33neutrality{x. You can master one of twelve {hh28classes{x: become a warrior, samurai, ninja -- or learn to cast spells and become a witch or necromancer.

The choice of {hh81Path{x is yours!
</text>
    <text l="ru">В {CМире Мечты{x можно прожить десятки жизней и пройти множество путей: Добра и Зла, меча и магии, кровавого убийцы и святой монахини, мудрого волшебника и безумного воина-берсеркера. Главной ценностью этого мира является СВОБОДА -- твой персонаж может стать всем, чем ты захочешь, всем, чего тебе мечталось достичь.

{CМир Мечты{x -- текстовая игра, тебе придется много читать и часто печатать. Если ты начнешь играть в нашем веб-клиенте, будет гораздо удобнее -- много чего ты сможешь сделать, просто нажимая на кнопки и ссылки на экране. Но кроме этого тебе иногда придется набирать {hh1079команды{x в строке ввода. Например, *надеть меч* или *колдовать щит*.

Абсолютная свобода означает свободу выбора того, кем ты хочешь стать. Можно вселиться в тело любой из 25 {hh54разумных рас{x -- человека или эльфа, гиганта или карлика. Можно сражаться на стороне Добра или Зла, а можно сохранять {hh33нейтралитет{x. Можно освоить один из двенадцати {hh28классов{x: стать воином, самураем, ниндзей -- или научиться колдовать и стать ведьмой или некромантом.

Выбор {hh81Пути{x -- за тобой!
</text>
    <text l="ua">У {CСвіті Мрії{x можна прожити десятки життів і пройти безліч шляхів: Добра і Зла, меча й магії, кривавого вбивці і святої черниці, мудрого чарівника і безумного воїна-берсеркера. Головною цінністю цього світу є СВОБОДА -- твій персонаж може стати всім, чим ти забажаєш, усім, про що тобі мрілося.

{CСвіт Мрії{x -- текстова гра, тобі доведеться багато читати і часто друкувати. Якщо ти почнеш грати у нашому веб-клієнті, буде набагато зручніше -- багато що ти зможеш зробити, просто натискаючи на кнопки й посилання на екрані. Але крім цього тобі іноді доведеться набирати {hh1079команди{x у рядку введення. Наприклад, *одягнути меч* або *чаклувати щит*.

Абсолютна свобода означає свободу вибору того, ким ти хочеш стати. Можна вселитися в тіло будь-якої з 25 {hh54розумних рас{x -- людини або ельфа, велетня або карлика. Можна битися на боці Добра або Зла, а можна зберігати {hh33нейтралітет{x. Можна опанувати один із дванадцяти {hh28класів{x: стати воїном, самураєм, ніндзею -- або навчитися чаклувати і стати відьмою чи некромантом.

Вибір {hh81Шляху{x -- за тобою!
</text>
    <title l="en"></title>
    <title l="ru">{CМир Мечты:{x Вступление</title>
    <title l="ua"></title>
  </node>
  <node id="80" labels="info" level="0" type="Help">
    <extra l="en">timeline</extra>
    <extra l="ru">первая пятая таймлайн третья времена вторая эпоха эпохи &apos;черный властелин&apos; четвертая миямото</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <keyword l="en">dreamland history</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">история мира</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">The universe is boundless, and within it there exist an infinite number of worlds and parallel
realities. In one of those worlds -- the one called Earth -- was created
the world of {hhDiku{x, from which grew hundreds of {hhROM{x and {hhAnatolia{x worlds.

{hh1565Varda{x and {hh1576Leo{x, the Supreme Gods of our world, created it from the Void as a mirror
reflection of the Anatolia worlds. Since then our world has changed beyond recognition, and its
history spans many millennia and several epochs.

{CFIRST EPOCH{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
At the dawn of time the world was young and full of Chaos. Varda and Leo tirelessly wove and
developed the fabric of our reality, painstakingly ordering Chaos and creating life from
the void. In their work the Supreme Gods were aided by the pantheon of the first Immortals
of our world, among them {hh1578Tananda{x and Corvin (later known as {hh1577Dwarkin{x), Glorund and
{hh1570NoFate{x. Varda created the first sapient race, the {hh156elves{x, and after them came {hh145humans{x and
several others -- yet many millennia remained before the coming of the numerous {hh54races that
exist today{x.

Along the freshly made roads of Thera wandered dozens of young heroes: the first
archmage {hh1479Shalafi{x, Susanin, the necromancer Burzum, the warrior Miyamoto who later became
the {hh1494Hunter{x, the ranger {hh1582Allanon{x, and the legendary leader of the {hh1485Invaders{x, the Dark Lord
Satan. Timidly and uncertainly, the first heroes began to learn the Paths of this world,
balancing one another.

But the balance was soon broken. Strangers from other worlds and realities, such as the
Forgotten Dungeon, began to enter the Dreamworld. With their coming the First Epoch ends
and the Second begins. Almost no chronicles of the First Epoch have survived, but memory
of those times is still alive.

{CSECOND EPOCH{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Legendary gods and heroes without number passed through the Dreamworld in this epoch.
Many generations were raised on the tales and legends of those days. Those
legends have taken firm root in the culture and chronicles of the living -- an adventurer
interested in history can read them in the Book of Legends, kept in the library of
{hh1392Midgaard{x on Elm Street.

Heroes of that time could carry skills from past lives through {hh1064rebirth{x,
gaining truly terrible power. Echoes of the Great Wars of this epoch can still be heard,
and the earth still remembers the oceans of blood spilled then.

The {hh1464Order of Knights{x under kings {hh1566Razer{x and Silvan, together with their
loyal cardinal Rjak, battled the mighty Cabal of Invaders. The dark knight
{hh1568Hauzer{x led the armies of Darkness in the conquest of the world, and fighting in the
front ranks were the legendary {hh133cleric{x of Darkness Krauss and the {hh132strangler{x Derini,
the warrior Fiorine and her brother, {hh143necromancer{x Reistlyn. Archmage Shalafi {hh1573Mihail{x and
{hh138anti-paladin{x Shur held back the assault of the mad {hh1471Battlerager{x clan under the command of
the famous warriors Sherhan and Eirenar. As a counterbalance to the bloody killers who
preyed on children and adolescents, the faction of the Three of the Forest arose --
Zaleshanin, Zverodral, and {hh1584Teelak{x, who later became immortal.

The pantheon of Immortals was joined by several new celestials, but great Tananda,
wearied of the tedious battles, left the world. Our world lost a piece of its soul forever
with her departure. Freed from the burden of Chaos, the god Dwarkin set about realising
his vision of a perfect world populated by ideal heroes -- the Universals. The Second
Epoch ends with their coming and the Great Cataclysm, which wiped every living thing from
the face of Thera.

{DNB: At present no Universals remain, and one can read about them in a small cave in
Midgaard -- the last monument to their former glory.{x

{CTHIRD EPOCH{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
The arrival of the Universals utterly shattered the centuries-old balance of power. It
was a time of chaos and uncertainty, the destruction of the old order and the renewal
of the Paths.

The young warrior Branwen becomes Queen of the Knights, and the calculating {hh135thief{x
Harran leads the Cabal of Invaders. Dissatisfied with the new strategy of the leadership,
the bloodthirsty {hh1569Mephisto{x leaves the Cabal and creates a new clan, the {hh1500Ghosts{x,
gathering all the maniacs and killers who survived the Cataclysm. Order in the half-
destroyed world is helped along by the young {hh140ranger{x Galen, who heads the {hh1461Order of
Rulers{x and rewrites the {hh1529legal code{x into its current form.

Many heroes of the Second Epoch, dissatisfied with the changes, leave the Dreamworld,
and some are reborn from the ashes as Immortals. The mighty warrior Sherhan becomes the
god {hh1574Turlok{x, the winged Fiorine becomes the ghost dragoness {hh1567Taiphoen{x and withdraws into
oblivion for a long time. Even the old gods shed their old guises and change names:
Dwarkin, weighed down by the heavy lot of the Universals, retreats into the forests under
the name Corvin, and his loyal comrade Teelak becomes {hh1584Tirna{x, patron of outcasts.
Finally, the young satyress {hh1571Ruffina{x joins the celestial pantheon, and with her arrival
the Fourth Epoch begins.

{CFOURTH EPOCH{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
{D(the rest of the page is torn out at the root)
In the corner you notice a small, hasty signature:
&apos;I'll finish it soon. Ruffina.&apos;{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">Вселенная безбрежна, и в ней существует бесконечное число миров и параллельных
реальностей. В одном из этих миров -- том, который называют Землей -- был создан
мир {hhDiku{x, из которого выросли сотни миров {hhROM{x и {hhAnatolia{x. 

{hh1565Варда{x и {hh1576Лео{x, Верховные Боги нашего мира, создали его из Пустоты как зеркальное
отражение миров Анатолии. И с тех пор наш мир неузнаваемо изменился, и его
история насчитывает много тысячелетий и несколько эпох.

{CПЕРВАЯ ЭПОХА{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
На заре времен мир был юн и полон Хаоса. Варда и Лео неустанно развивали и плели
ткань нашей реальности, кропотливо упорядочивая Хаос и творя жизнь из пустоты.
В их работе Верховным Богам помогал пантеон первых Бессмертных нашего мира,
таких как {hh1578Тананда{x и Корвин (позже известный как {hh1577Дворкин{x), Глорунд и {hh1570НоФейт{x.
Варда создала первую разумную расу, {hh156эльфов{x, за ними последовали {hh145люди{x и еще
несколько, но до пришествия многих {hh54рас, существующих сегодня{x, оставалось еще
несколько тысячелетий.

По свежесотворенным дорогам Тэры разбрелись десятки молодых героев: первый
архимаг {hh1479Шалафи{x, Сусанин, некромант Бурзум, воин Миямото, позже ставший
{hh1494Наемником{x, следопыт {hh1582Алланон{x, и легендарный лидер {hh1485Захватчиков{x, Черный Властелин
Сатан. Робко и неуверенно, первые герои стали познавать Пути этого мира,
уравновешивая друг друга.

Но вскоре баланс был нарушен. В Мир Мечты начали проникать чужаки из других
миров и реальностей, таких как Забытое Подземелье. С их приходом завершается
Первая Эпоха и начинается Вторая. О Первой Эпохе не сохранилось почти никаких
летописей, но память о тех временах все еще жива.

{CВТОРАЯ ЭПОХА{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Множество легендарных богов и героев прошли через Мир Мечты в эту эпоху.
На сказках и преданиях о тех временах были воспитаны многие поколения. Эти
легенды прочно вошли в культуру и летописи ныне живущих -- интересующийся
историей приключенец может прочитать их в Книге Легенд, хранящейся в библиотеке
{hh1392Мидгаарда{x на улице Вязов.

Герои того времени могли получать умения из прошлых жизней при {hh1064перерождении{x,
получая поистине ужасное могущество. Отголоски эха Великих Войн этой эпохи
слышны и поныне, и земля все еще помнит океаны крови, пролитые тогда. 

{hh1464Орден Рыцарей{x под предводительством королей {hh1566Разера{x и Сильвана, а также их
верного кардинала Рьяка, сражался с могущественным Кабалом Захватчиков. Темный
рыцарь {hh1568Хаузер{x вел армии Тьмы на завоевание мира, а в первых рядах сражались
легендарный {hh133жрец{x Тьмы Краусс и {hh132душитель{x Дерини, воительница Фиориннэ и ее брат,
{hh143некромант{x Рейстлин. Архимаг Шалафи {hh1573Михаил{x и {hh138анти-паладин{x Шур сдерживали натиск
безумного клана {hh1471Баттлрейджеров{x под предводительством знаменитых воинов Шерхана
и Эйренара. В противовес кровавым убийцам, обижающим детей и подростков,
возникает фракция Троих из Леса -- Залешанин, Зверодрал и {hh1584Тилак{x, позже ставший
бессмертным.

Пантеон Бессмертных пополнили несколько новых небожителей, но уставшая от
скучных сражений, мир покинула Великая Тананда. Наш мир навеки потерял частичку
своей души с ее уходом. Освобожденный от гнета Хаоса, бог Дворкин приступил к
воплощению своего видения совершенного мира, населенного идеальными героями,
универсалами. Вторая Эпоха оканчивается их пришествием и Великим Катаклизмом,
стершим с лица Тэры все живое.

{DNB: На текущий момент универсалов уже не осталось, и почитать о них можно
в маленькой пещере в Мидгаарде -- последнем памятнике их былой славы.{x

{CТРЕТЬЯ ЭПОХА{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Приход универсалов полностью нарушил устоявшийся веками баланс сил. То было
время хаоса и неопределенности, разрушения устоев и обновления Путей.

Королевой Рыцарей становится молодая воительница Бранвен, а Кабал Захватчиков
ведет за собой расчетливый {hh135вор{x Харран. Недовольный новой стратегией руководства,
Кабал покидает кровожадный {hh1569Мефисто{x и создает новый клан, {hh1500Призраков{x, объединивший
всех выживших в Катаклизме маньяков и убийц. Порядок в полуразрушенном мире
помогает поддерживать молодой {hh140рейнджер{x Гален, возглавивший {hh1461Орден Правителей{x и
переписавший {hh1529свод законов{x в его нынешней форме. 

Многие герои Второй Эпохи, недовольные переменами, покидают Мир Мечты, а
некоторые -- возрождаются из пепла в роли Бессмертных. Могучий воин Шерхан
становится богом {hh1574Турлоком{x, крылатая Фиориннэ становится призрачным драконом
{hh1567Тайфоэн{x и надолго уходит в небытие. И даже старые боги сбрасывают старые обличья
и меняют имена: удрученный тяжкой долей универсалов Дворкин уходит в леса под
именем Корвина, а его верный соратник Тилак становится {hh1584Тирной{x, покровителем
изгнанников. Наконец, к пантеону небожителей присоединяется молодая сатирша
{hh1571Руфина{x, и с ее приходом начинается Четвертая Эпоха.

{CЧЕТВЕРТАЯ ЭПОХА{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
{D(остаток страницы вырван с корнем)
В углу ты замечаешь маленькую торопливую подпись:
&apos;Скоро допишу. Руфина.&apos;{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">Всесвіт безмежний, і в ньому існує нескінченна кількість світів і паралельних
реальностей. В одному з цих світів -- тому, що зветься Землею -- було створено
світ {hhDiku{x, з якого виросли сотні світів {hhROM{x і {hhAnatolia{x.

{hh1565Варда{x і {hh1576Лео{x, Верховні Боги нашого світу, створили його з Пустоти як дзеркальне
відображення світів Анатолii. Відтоді наш світ змінився до невпізнання, і його
історія налічує багато тисячоліть і кілька епох.

{CПЕРША ЕПОХА{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
На зорі часів світ був молодим і сповненим Хаосу. Варда і Лео невтомно розвивали
й плели тканину нашоі реальності, кропітко впорядковуючи Хаос і творячи життя з
пустоти. У своій роботі Верховним Богам допомагав пантеон перших Безсмертних
нашого світу, таких як {hh1578Тананда{x і Корвін (пізніше відомий як {hh1577Дворкін{x), Ґлорунд і
{hh1570НоФейт{x. Варда створила першу розумну расу -- {hh156ельфів{x, за ними послідували {hh145люди{x і
ще декілька, але до приходу багатьох {hh54рас, що існують сьогодні{x, залишалося ще
кілька тисячоліть.

По свіжоствореним дорогам Тери розбрелися десятки молодих героів: перший
архімаг {hh1479Шалафі{x, Сусанін, некромант Бурзум, воін Міямото, що пізніше став
{hh1494Найманцем{x, слідопит {hh1582Алланон{x і легендарний лідер {hh1485Загарбників{x, Чорний Владика
Сатана. Несміло й невпевнено, перші герої почали пізнавати Шляхи цього світу,
врівноважуючи одне одного.

Але незабаром баланс було порушено. У Світ Мрii почали проникати чужинці з інших
світів і реальностей, таких як Забуте Підземелля. З іх приходом завершується
Перша Епоха і починається Друга. Про Першу Епоху майже не збереглося літописів,
але памʼять про ті часи досі жива.

{CДРУГА ЕПОХА{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Незліченні легендарні боги й герої пройшли крізь Світ Мрii в цю епоху.
На казках і переказах про ті часи виросли багато поколінь. Ці
легенди міцно увійшли в культуру й літописи нині живих -- зацікавлений
історією пригодник може прочитати іх у Книзі Легенд, що зберігається в бібліотеці
{hh1392Мідгаарду{x на вулиці В'язів.

Герої того часу могли отримувати вміння з минулих життів при {hh1064переродженні{x,
здобуваючи воістину жахливу могутність. Відгомін Великих Війн цієі епохи
чутний і понині, і земля досі памʼятає океани крові, що пролилися тоді.

{hh1464Орден Лицарів{x під проводом королів {hh1566Разера{x і Сілвана, а також іхнього
вірного кардинала Рʼяка, бився з могутнім Кабалом Загарбників. Темний
лицар {hh1568Хаузер{x вів армii Темряви на завоювання світу, а в перших лавах билися
легендарний {hh133жрець{x Темряви Краусс і {hh132душитель{x Деріні, воітельниця Фіорінне
і ii брат, {hh143некромант{x Рейстлін. Архімаг Шалафі {hh1573Михаіл{x і {hh138анті-паладін{x Шур
стримували натиск шаленого клану {hh1471Баттлрейджерів{x під проводом знаменитих воінів
Шерхана й Ейренара. На противагу кривавим вбивцям, що кривдили дітей і підлітків,
виникає фракція Трьох із Лісу -- Залешанін, Звіродрал і {hh1584Тілак{x, що пізніше
став безсмертним.

Пантеон Безсмертних поповнили кілька нових небожителів, але стомлена нудними
битвами велика Тананда покинула світ. Наш світ назавжди втратив частинку своєі
душі з ii відходом. Звільнений від гніту Хаосу, бог Дворкін взявся за втілення
свого бачення досконалого світу, населеного ідеальними героями -- універсалами.
Друга Епоха завершується іхнім приходом і Великим Катаклізмом, що зтер із
личини Тери все живе.

{DПрим.: На поточний момент універсалів уже не залишилося, і почитати про них
можна в маленькій печері в Мідгаарді -- останньому памʼятнику іхньоі колишньоі слави.{x

{CТРЕТЯ ЕПОХА{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Прихід універсалів повністю порушив усталений віками баланс сил. То був
час хаосу й невизначеності, руйнування устоів та оновлення Шляхів.

Королевою Лицарів стає молода воітельниця Бранвен, а Кабал Загарбників
веде за собою розважливий {hh135злодій{x Харран. Незадоволений новою стратегією
керівництва, Кабал залишає кровожерний {hh1569Мефісто{x і створює новий клан,
{hh1500Привидів{x, що обʼєднав усіх вцілілих у Катаклізмі маньяків і вбивць. Порядок у
напівзруйнованому світі допомагає підтримувати молодий {hh140рейнджер{x Ґален,
що очолив {hh1461Орден Правителів{x і переписав {hh1529звід законів{x у його нинішній формі.

Багато героів Другоі Епохи, незадоволених змінами, покидають Світ Мрii, а
деякі -- відроджуються з попелу в ролі Безсмертних. Могутній воін Шерхан
стає богом {hh1574Турлоком{x, крилата Фіорінне стає примарним драконом
{hh1567Тайфоен{x і надовго іде в небуття. І навіть старі боги скидають колишні
обличчя й міняють імена: пригнічений важкою долею універсалів Дворкін іде
в ліси під іменем Корвіна, а його вірний соратник Тілак стає {hh1584Тірною{x,
покровителем вигнанців. Зрештою, до пантеону небожителів приєднується молода
сатирша {hh1571Руфіна{x, і з ii приходом починається Четверта Епоха.

{CЧЕТВЕРТА ЕПОХА{x
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------
{D(решта сторінки вирвана з корінцем)
У кутку ти помічаєш маленький поспішний підпис:
&apos;Незабаром допишу. Руфіна.&apos;{x
</text>
    <title l="en"></title>
    <title l="ru">{CИсторические эпохи Мира Мечты{x</title>
    <title l="ua"></title>
  </node>
  <node id="81" labels="info" level="-1" type="Help">
    <extra l="en">chaos &apos;eight paths&apos; evil good nature order rage reason society ways</extra>
    <extra l="ru">добра добро хаоса колесо общества общество порядка порядок природа природы путей путь ярости ярость разума свобода свободы зла зло</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <keyword l="en">paths</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">пути &apos;восемь путей&apos;</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">In the Dreamworld there are so-called =Eight Paths:= the great principles locked in eternal war with their opposites:

  {W%A% {hh6Path of Light{x{W: self-sacrifice for the common good and the destruction of Darkness{x
  {D%A% {hh7Path of Dark{x{D: absolute power and might at any cost{x
  
  {B%A% {hh8Path of Reason{x{B: intellect, magic, and rational study of being{x 
  {R%A% {hh10Path of Rage{x{R: emotion, strength, and passion against the call of reason{x
  
  {w%A% {hh23Path of Order{x{w: laws, cosmic harmony, and the balance of Creation{x 
  {M%A% {hh25Path of Chaos{x{M: absolute freedom and the destruction of Order{x
  
  {g%A% {hh49Path of Nature{x{g: ecology and the natural course of things, against progress{x
  {Y%A% {hh52Path of Society{x{Y: progress against nature; technology and the social fabric{x

  {C%A% {hh1497Path of Freedom{x{C: denial of all Paths and clans{x
  
The Paths are the foundation of your character's {hh31roleplay{x. The point of the Paths is in making choices and accepting certain constraints for your character -- constraints that will help you inhabit your role more deeply. Your every decision, your every step, is a contribution to one of the Paths. Killed a villain? A step on the Path of Light. Mastered a magic spell? A step on the Path of Reason. Grew a tree? A step on the Path of Nature.

Each Path has its own secret qualities, each Path has its corresponding {hh3clans{x, {hh54races{x, and {hh28classes{x, and each Path is watched over by its own {hh1pantheon{x of official religions and secret cults. If you choose to believe in one of the gods or goddesses, they will be able to help you on your Path.

Not every Path is available to every character. A vampire can never walk the Path of Light, a ranger will never agree to trade Nature for noisy cities, and a chaotic thief will fail to become a champion of Order. But a warrior or samurai may well choose the Path of Reason over Rage, while at the same time protecting Nature -- or, on the contrary, developing technology and progress. The choice is yours!

To learn more about the so-called =Wheel of Paths= -- the friendly and hostile Paths and their relationships with one another -- read the book of the same name in the Midgaard city {hh2088Library{x.
</text>
    <text l="ru">В Мире Мечты есть так называемые =Восемь Путей:= великие начала, находящихся в вечной войне со своими противоположностями:

  {W%A% {hh6Путь Света{x{W: самопожертвование ради общего блага и гибели Тьмы{x
  {D%A% {hh7Путь Тьмы{x{D: абсолютная власть и могущество, любой ценой{x
  
  {B%A% {hh8Путь Разума{x{B: интеллект, магия и рациональное познание сущего{x 
  {R%A% {hh10Путь Ярости{x{R: эмоции, сила и страсть, вопреки зову разума{x
  
  {w%A% {hh23Путь Порядка{x{w: законы, космическая гармония и баланс Мироздания{x 
  {M%A% {hh25Путь Хаоса{x{M: абсолютная свобода и уничтожение Порядка{x
  
  {g%A% {hh49Путь Природы{x{g: экология и естественный ход вещей, вопреки прогрессу{x
  {Y%A% {hh52Путь Общества{x{Y: прогресс вопреки природе, технологии и социум{x

  {C%A% {hh1497Путь Свободы{x{C: отрицание всех Путей и кланов{x
  
Пути -- основа {hh31отыгрыша{x твоего персонажа. Смысл Путей -- в принятии выбора, в создании определенных ограничений для своего персонажа, которые помогут тебе лучше вжиться в роль. Каждое твое решение, каждый шаг -- твой вклад в один из Путей. Убил{Sfа{Sx злодея? Шаг по пути Света. Овладел{Sfа{Sx магическим заклинанием? Шаг по пути Разума. Вырастил{Sfа{Sx дерево? Шаг по Пути Природы.

Каждый путь обладает своими тайными особенностями, каждому пути соответствуют свои {hh3кланы{x, {hh54расы{x и {hh28классы{x, и каждому пути покровительствует свой {hh1пантеон{x официальных религий и таинственных культов. Если ты решишь поверить в одного из богов и богинь, они смогут помочь тебе на твоем Пути.

Не все Пути доступны любому персонажу. Вампиру никогда не встать на Путь Света, рейнджер никогда не согласится променять Природу на шумные города, а хаотичному вору не удастся стать чемпионом Порядка. Но зато воин или самурай вполне могут встать на Путь Разума вместо Ярости, и при этом беречь и защищать Природу или наоборот, развивать технологии и прогресс. Выбор за тобой!

Чтобы узнать больше о так называемом =Колесе Путей= -- дружественных и враждебных Путях и их взаимоотношениях между собой -- почитай одноименную книгу в городской {hh2088Библиотеке{x Мидгаарда.
</text>
    <text l="ua">У Світі Мрії є так звані =Вісім Шляхів:= великі начала, що перебувають у вічній війні зі своїми протилежностями:

  {W%A% {hh6Шлях Світла{x{W: самопожертва заради спільного блага і загибелі Темряви{x
  {D%A% {hh7Шлях Темряви{x{D: абсолютна влада і могутність будь-якою ціною{x
  
  {B%A% {hh8Шлях Розуму{x{B: інтелект, магія і раціональне пізнання сущого{x 
  {R%A% {hh10Шлях Люті{x{R: емоції, сила і пристрасть всупереч голосу розуму{x
  
  {w%A% {hh23Шлях Порядку{x{w: закони, космічна гармонія і баланс Світобудови{x 
  {M%A% {hh25Шлях Хаосу{x{M: абсолютна свобода і знищення Порядку{x
  
  {g%A% {hh49Шлях Природи{x{g: екологія і природний хід речей всупереч прогресу{x
  {Y%A% {hh52Шлях Суспільства{x{Y: прогрес всупереч природі, технології і соціум{x

  {C%A% {hh1497Шлях Свободи{x{C: заперечення всіх Шляхів і кланів{x
  
Шляхи -- основа {hh31відіграшу{x твого персонажа. Сенс Шляхів -- у прийнятті вибору, у створенні певних обмежень для свого персонажа, які допоможуть тобі краще вжитися в роль. Кожне твоє рішення, кожен крок -- твій внесок в один із Шляхів. Убив{Sfа{Sx злодія? Крок по Шляху Світла. Опанував{Sfа{Sx магічне заклинання? Крок по Шляху Розуму. Виростив{Sfа{Sx дерево? Крок по Шляху Природи.

Кожен Шлях має свої таємні особливості, кожному Шляху відповідають свої {hh3клани{x, {hh54раси{x і {hh28класи{x, і кожному Шляху покровительствує свій {hh1пантеон{x офіційних релігій і таємних культів. Якщо ти вирішиш повірити в одного з богів чи богинь, вони зможуть допомогти тобі на твоєму Шляху.

Не всі Шляхи доступні будь-якому персонажу. Вампіру ніколи не стати на Шлях Світла, рейнджер ніколи не погодиться проміняти Природу на галасливі міста, а хаотичному злодієві не вдасться стати чемпіоном Порядку. Зате воїн або самурай цілком можуть стати на Шлях Розуму замість Люті, і при цьому берегти й захищати Природу або навпаки -- розвивати технології й прогрес. Вибір за тобою!

Щоб дізнатися більше про так зване =Колесо Шляхів= -- дружні й ворожі Шляхи та їхні взаємини між собою -- почитай однойменну книгу в міській {hh2088Бібліотеці{x Мідгаарда.
</text>
    <title l="en"></title>
    <title l="ru">{CВосемь Путей{x твоего персонажа</title>
    <title l="ua"></title>
  </node>
  <node id="83" labels="char item" level="-1" type="Help">
    <extra l="en">ac</extra>
    <extra l="ru">&apos;класс брони&apos; &apos;защита от разрезания&apos; &apos;защита от ударов&apos; &apos;защита от уколов&apos; &apos;защита от экзотики&apos;</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <keyword l="en">&apos;armor class&apos;</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">&apos;класс защиты&apos;</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">{CArmor class{x (AC) is a parameter that determines how difficult it is to hit your character. The LOWER the armor class -- the better. You can reduce your armor class with {hh1015equipment{x, skills, or {hh37dexterity{x.

The opposite of armor class is {hh47accuracy{x. The higher the accuracy, the lower an armor class you can penetrate.

Specific armor class types (for example, pierce protection, bash protection) affect armor class against specific weapon damage types. Some armor protects better against a dagger thrust, and other armor -- against a mace blow.

Different items have different armor class depending on the size of the item -- more precisely, on where it is worn. Body armor has the highest protection, four times that of other armor (x4), shields are somewhat lower (x3), and helmets, bracers, and greaves are twice the standard (x2).
</text>
    <text l="ru">{CКласс защиты{x (armor class, AC) -- параметр, который определяет, насколько сложно по твоему персонажу попасть. Чем НИЖЕ класс защиты -- тем лучше. Уменьшать класс защиты можно {hh1015вещами{x, умениями или {hh37ловкостью{x.

Противоположностью класса защиты является {hh47точность{x. Чем выше точность, тем более низкий класс защиты ты сможешь пробить.

Отдельные типы класса защиты (например, защита от уколов, защита от ударов) влияют на класс защиты против конкретных типов повреждений оружия. Какая-то броня лучше защитит от выпада кинжалом, а иная -- от удара дубиной.

У разных вещей разный класс защиты в зависимости от размера вещи -- точнее, от того, куда она надевается. У брони на тело самая высокая защита, в 4 раза выше остальной брони (x4), у щитов чуть пониже (x3), а у шлемов, наручей и поножей вдвое выше обычного (x2).
</text>
    <text l="ua">{CКлас захисту{x (armor class, AC) -- параметр, який визначає, наскільки складно потрапити по твоєму персонажу. Чим НИЖЧИЙ клас захисту -- тим краще. Зменшувати клас захисту можна {hh1015речами{x, уміннями або {hh37спритністю{x.

Протилежністю класу захисту є {hh47влучність{x. Чим вища влучність, тим нижчий клас захисту ти зможеш пробити.

Окремі типи класу захисту (наприклад, захист від уколів, захист від ударів) впливають на клас захисту проти конкретних типів пошкоджень зброї. Якась броня краще захистить від випаду кинджалом, а інша -- від удару булавою.

У різних речей різний клас захисту залежно від розміру речі -- точніше, від того, куди вона одягається. У броні на тіло найвищий захист, у 4 рази вищий за решту броні (х4), у щитів трохи нижче (х3), а у шоломів, наручів і поножів удвічі вищий за звичайний (х2).
</text>
    <title l="en"></title>
    <title l="ru">Класс защиты</title>
    <title l="ua"></title>
  </node>
  <node id="86" labels="info" level="-1" type="Help">
    <extra l="en">deserts forests indoors inside mountains norecall private &apos;room types&apos; safe underwater</extra>
    <extra l="ru">беседка безопасная безопасные дикая горы комната леса местность &apos;под водой&apos; помещение природа приватная пустыня сейф-зона &apos;солнечный свет&apos; свойства сэйф флаги комнат</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <keyword l="en">rooms</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">комнаты &apos;типы местности&apos;</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua"></keyword>
    <text l="en">Every location (room, cell) in {hh998zones{x has some terrain type and certain hidden properties.

Room properties determine under what conditions you can reach a given place, as well as how various skills and spells work there. Here are just a few examples:
%A% =Safe room=: in such rooms no combat can begin -- neither in {hh32PK{x
  nor even with monsters -- and {hh42limits{x deteriorate faster. Found very rarely. 
  Also, a character under the effect of {hh2146adrenaline{x cannot enter these rooms.
%A% =No-recall=, cursed: the {hh862recall{x prayer does not work
  and neither do other {hh1126transport{x skills. If you try to use them, you will see
  &quot;The gods have abandoned you.&quot; A similar effect is also given by the {hh548curse{x effect on you.
%A% =Private=: only two characters can be in this room at the same time.
  There are also =solitary= rooms -- for one person only.
%A% =Indoors=: in such places you cannot see the {hh1028weather{x (logically) and
  cannot use various nature-based or {hh1028weather{x skills.
  Indoors, vampires are not hurt by =sunlight=. Logical.

Terrain types determine how many skills work, as well as the speed of {hh18movement{x through the room. A couple of examples:
%A% =Inside=: space within some building, but not necessarily
  under a roof (indoors) -- for example, a monastery's inner courtyard.
  Sunlight strikes vampires at half strength.
%A% =Forest=: in these places you can {hh1023chop{x a tree.
  Sunlight strikes vampires at half strength.
%A% =Desert=, =mountains=: in these places the spell
  {hh770fist of the desert{x and some others will trigger. Moving through mountains and deserts is slower.
  Also, in deserts items made of ice and similar materials melt.
%A% =Water=, =underwater=: see {hc{yhelp swim{x
%A% =Air=: to pass through, you must learn to {hh575fly{x
  Sunlight strikes vampires twice as hard.

Most ranger and druid skills work only in =wilderness=: this includes forest, field, hills, and mountains. If =wild terrain= is mentioned, this also includes desert. There are very many terrain types and properties, and some of them you will only discover through experience...
</text>
    <text l="ru">Каждая местность (комната, клетка) в {hh998зонах{x имеет какой-то тип местности и определенные скрытые свойства.

Свойства комнат определяют, при каких условиях в это место попасть, а также работу разных умений и заклинаний в этом месте. Вот лишь несколько примеров:
%A% =Безопасная комната=: в таких комнатах нельзя начать бой ни в {hh32ПК{x,
  ни даже с монстрами, и быстрее разваливаются {hh42лимит{xы. Встречаются очень редко. 
  Также в эти комнаты не может зайти персонаж под {hh2146адреналином{x.
%A% =Без возврата=, проклятая: не работает молитва {hh862возврата{x
  и другие {hh1126транспортные{x умения. При попытке их использовать ты увидишь
  &quot;Боги покинули тебя.&quot; Подобный эффект также дает эффект {hh548проклятия{x на тебе.
%A% =Приватная=: в этой комнате могут одновременно находиться только
  два персонажа. Бывают еще =одиночные= комнаты -- только для одного.
%A% =В помещении=: в таких местах нельзя увидеть {hh1028погоду{x (логично) и
  пользоваться разнообразными природными или {hh1028погодными{x умениями.
  В помещении вампиров не ранит =солнечный свет=. Логично.

Типы местности определяют работу многих умений, а также скорость {hh18передвижения{x через эту комнату. Пара примеров:
%A% =Внутри=: пространство внутри какого-либо здания, но необязательно
  под крышей (в помещении) -- например, внутренний дворик монастыря.
  Солнечный свет бьет вампиров вдвое слабее.
%A% =Лес=: в этих местах можно {hh1023срубить{x дерево.
  Солнечный свет бьет вампиров вдвое слабее.
%A% =Пустыня=, =горы=: в этих местах сработает заклинание
  {hh770кулака пустыни{x и некоторые другие. Через горы и пустыни идти медленнее.
  Также, в пустынях тают вещи, сделанные изо льда и подобных материалов.
%A% =Вода=, =под водой=: см. {hc{yсправка плавать{x
%A% =Воздух=: чтобы пройти, нужно научиться {hh575летать{x
  Солнечный свет бьет вампиров вдвое сильнее.

Большинство умений рейнджеров и друидов работают только на =природе=: в это входят лес, поле, холмы и горы. Если упоминается &quot;=дикая местность=&quot;, в это также включается пустыня. Типов местности и свойств очень много, и некоторые из них придется узнать только на практике...
</text>
    <text l="ua">Кожна місцевість (кімната, клітинка) у {hh998зонах{x має якийсь тип місцевості і певні приховані властивості.

Властивості кімнат визначають, за яких умов до цього місця можна потрапити, а також роботу різних умінь і заклинань у цьому місці. Ось лише кілька прикладів:
%A% =Безпечна кімната=: у таких кімнатах не можна почати бій ні в {hh32ПК{x,
  ні навіть з монстрами, і швидше розвалюються {hh42ліміт{xи. Трапляються дуже рідко. 
  Також у ці кімнати не може зайти персонаж під {hh2146адреналіном{x.
%A% =Без повернення=, проклята: не працює молитва {hh862повернення{x
  та інші {hh1126транспортні{x уміння. При спробі їх використати ти побачиш
  &quot;Боги покинули тебе.&quot; Подібний ефект також дає ефект {hh548прокляття{x на тобі.
%A% =Приватна=: у цій кімнаті можуть одночасно перебувати тільки
  два персонажі. Бувають ще =одиночні= кімнати -- лише для одного.
%A% =У приміщенні=: у таких місцях не можна побачити {hh1028погоду{x (логічно) і
  користуватися різноманітними природними або {hh1028погодними{x уміннями.
  У приміщенні вампірів не ранить =сонячне світло=. Логічно.

Типи місцевості визначають роботу багатьох умінь, а також швидкість {hh18пересування{x через цю кімнату. Пара прикладів:
%A% =Всередині=: простір усередині якоїсь будівлі, але необовʼязково
  під дахом (у приміщенні) -- наприклад, внутрішній двір монастиря.
  Сонячне світло бʼє вампірів удвічі слабше.
%A% =Ліс=: у цих місцях можна {hh1023зрубати{x дерево.
  Сонячне світло бʼє вампірів удвічі слабше.
%A% =Пустеля=, =гори=: у цих місцях спрацює заклинання
  {hh770кулака пустелі{x та деякі інші. Через гори і пустелі йти повільніше.
  Також у пустелях тануть речі, зроблені з льоду та подібних матеріалів.
%A% =Вода=, =під водою=: див. {hc{yдовідка плисти{x
%A% =Повітря=: щоб пройти, потрібно навчитися {hh575літати{x
  Сонячне світло бʼє вампірів удвічі сильніше.

Більшість умінь рейнджерів і друїдів працюють тільки на =природі=: до цього входять ліс, поле, пагорби і гори. Якщо згадується =дика місцевість=, до цього також входить пустеля. Типів місцевості й властивостей дуже багато, і деякі з них доведеться дізнатися тільки на практиці...
</text>
    <title l="en"></title>
    <title l="ru">Типы местностей и свойства комнат</title>
    <title l="ua"></title>
  </node>
  <node id="1010" labels="info" level="-1" type="Help">
    <extra l="en">developers implementors programmers thanks translate translations credits</extra>
    <extra l="ru">создатели благодарности переводы программисты</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <text l="en"></text>
    <text l="ru">%PAUSE%{x   * {WDikuMUD{x by Hans Staerfeldt, Katja Nyboe, Tom Madsen, 
     Michael Seifert and Sebastian Hammer (see &apos;help diku&apos;)
   * {WMERC 2.1{x by Hatchet, Furey, and Kahn (see &apos;help merc&apos;)
   * {WROM 2.4{x by Russ Taylor (see &apos;help rom&apos;)
   * {WANATOLIA 2.1{x by Serdar BULUT and Ibrahim CANPUNAR (see &apos;help anatolia&apos;)
   
   * {WDreamLand 2.0{x (c) 1998-2003 by 
	Igor Antonenko         (Leo)
	Olga Ridvanuk          (Varda)
	Igor Petrenko          (NoFate, Demogorgon)
	Sergey Tereschenko     (Sturm)
	Denis Lukinykh         (Dwarkin, Corvin)
	Vladimir Gulyaev       (Tirna, Teelak)
	Roman Cherednichenko   (Glorund)
	Aleksandr Zadvinsky    (Kiddy)
	Vladimir Kirichenko    (Razer)
	Nazar Koval            (Nazar, Redrum)
	Vladimir Doropey       (Reorx)  
	Denis Kulgeiko         (Burzum)
	Aleksandr Andreyanov   (Manwe)
     
    Russian localization and area translations by Olga Rydvanuk and:
	Bastian, Cradya, Corvin, Derini, Dred, Garret, Grom, Fantik,
	Finraag, Hauzer, Hinore, Joker, Krauss, Fiorine, Lexx, Miyamoto, 
	Reistlyn, Resky, Sherhan, Teelak, Varda, Xok, Zav, Бесенок, Холод

    Area creation by Branwen, Cradya, Galen, Miyamoto, Tananda, Teelak, Shur
    
    Greeting by Eugene Orlov. 
    
   * {WDreamLand 3.0{x (c) 2003-2012 by Ruffina

    Code contributions by Sturm, Unicorn, and from realms of Forgotten Dungeon,
    Shades of Gray, Anatolia 3.0, DalekenMUD, Labyrinth

    Fenia coding by Ancifer, Filths, Kind, Miyamoto, Ruqun, Cotton

    Quest scenarios by Cotton, Miyamoto, Ragnar, Tleylax

    Area translations by Bastian, Brillar, Cradya, Irlana, Karmina, Nimoa, 
    Pradd, SinLair, Shavatar, Thoren, Tsamada, Vrem and from realms of 
    Forgotten Dungeon, Shadow Realms

    Area creation by Aileen, Ancifer, Cotton, Cradya, Dalt, Emmanuil, Hellen, 
    Irlana, McLaud, Myrriti, Thoren, Filths
   
   * {WDreamLand 4.0{x (c) 2018- by Ruffina, Filths, Taiphoen, Kerrad, Bast

    Area translations by Dalt, Miyamoto, Nimoa, Pianka, Tahi, Zustin, Fiorine

    Map making by Jimini, Miyamoto, Nimoa, Tahi, Zustin, Misty

    Area creation by Pianka, Tahi, Miyamoto, Fiorine
  </text>
    <text l="ua"></text>
    <title l="en"></title>
    <title l="ru">{CСтраничка благодарности{x</title>
    <title l="ua"></title>
  </node>
</Help>
