<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Help type="HelpContainer">
  <node keyword="RULES WORLDRULES ПРАВИЛА 'ПРАВИЛА МИРА'" level="0" type="Help" labels="info">Атмосфера, царящая в этом мире, в огромной степени зависит от персонажей
населяющих его. Старайтесь стать частью Вашего персонажа, окунуться в Мир
сказок и мечтаний, и Мир подарит Вам незабываемые минуты, часы, дни,...

  Ниже приводится список основных правил, действующих в Dream Land.
Нарушение любого из этих правил является основанием для наказания Вашего 
персонажа (вплоть до удаления). Незнание правил не освобождает от 
ответственности за их нарушение.
 
1. Любое неуважение к персонажам населяющим Dream Land, а также и самому Миру
крайне недопустимо. В этом мире запрещены нецензурные выражения и откровенная
ругань по отношению к кому-либо или чему-либо. Также следует воздержаться от
выяснения отношений между игроками в общих каналах.

2.Категорически запрещено использовать найденные ошибки в программе. Если Вы
нашли ошибку, сообщите о ней Богам и не используйте ее. Особенно это касается
ошибок, приводящих к падению Мира. 
Виновные в эксплуатации ошибок будут жестоко наказаны.

3.Бессмертные в Dream Land призваны поддерживать игровую атмосферу. Неуважение 
к Бессмертным, игнорирование их рекомендаций и наставлений может вызвать 
адекватную реакцию оных. Никогда не спрашивайте невидимого Бессмертного, кто 
он такой. Такие вопросы считаются невежливыми и будут оставлены без ответа. 

4.  Избегайте вызывающих и не соответствующих вашей расе, уровню или классу
титулов. Также запрещаются оскорбительные по отношению к кому-либо титулы и
описания. Тем не менее рекомендуется вводить описание своего персонажа -
грамотно написанные description и title позволит другим легче понять ту роль,
которую Вы играете в этом Мире. При нахождении Вашего title или description
несоответствующим роли,классу,расе Бессмертные могут потребовать от Вас сменить
его. Особо злостные нарушители будут наказаны.

5.Запрещена одновременная игра несколькими персонажами, а тем более помощь
одного Вашего персонажа другому в любом виде - включая заклинания и помощь
деньгами либо вещами - как непосредственно, так и передачей через   других 
игроков или как-либо еще. Наказание за это - удаление одного персонажа.
  Также запрещены &quot;персонажи-хранилища&quot; - таковые будут немедленно удалены,
а их владельцы - наказаны.

6.Спам (SPAM) в общих каналах и нотах категорически запрещается. Сюда же
относится выяснение отношений между игроками в любом виде и переписка на темы,
не имеющие отношения к Миру. Вы получите одно предупреждение, после чего будете
наказаны.

7.Сексуальные приставания в любом виде не допускаются. Если обе стороны
заранее не пришли к согласию по используемым emote/socials, воздержитесь от их
применения. Также не стоит сразу применять по отношению к другим игрокам
socials, действие которых Вам неизвестно. Вы можете попасть в очень неприятную
ситуацию.

8.Если Бессмертные наказали Ваш персонаж и Вы ДЕЙСТВИТЕЛЬHО уверены в том, что
произошла ошибка, Вы можете написать письмо на адрес ruffina.koza@gmail.com

9.Изменения в законах могут проводиться Бессмертными без дополнительного
предупреждения, уведомления и даже без признака здравого смысла.
 
Эти правила просты, логичны и достаточно четко сформулированы. Если Вас поймают
за их нарушением - Вы БУДЕТЕ наказаны. Степень наказания будет определена
Бессмертными Dream Land.

</node>
  <node keyword="GREETING" level="-1" type="Help">%PAUSE%DikuMUD by Hans Staerfeldt, Katja Nyboe,Tom Madsen, Michael Seifert,
and Sebastian Hammer. Based on MERC 2.1 code by Hatchet, Furey, and Kahn.
ROM 2.4 copyright (c) 1993-1995 Russ Taylor.
ANATOLIA 2.1, copyright 1997 by Serdar BULUT and Ibrahim CANPUNAR
DREAMLAND 2.0 by Igor Antonenko, Olga Ridvanuk, Igor Petrenko, Denis Lukinykh,
Nazar Koval, Vladimir Doropey, Denis Kulgeiko, Aleksandr Andreyanov,
Aleksandr Zadvinsky, Vladimir Kirichenko, Vladimir Gulyaev, Sergey Tereschenko
Russian localization: Olga Ridvanuk and others who play and build this MUD.
Greeting by Eugene Orlov. Previously available on mud.kiev.ua, dreamland.org.ua. 
DREAMLAND 4.0 by Ruffina (see &apos;help credits&apos; for details)

         ,&quot;|          $$$$$$$$   $$$$$$$    $$$$$$$$      $$      $$$$     $$$$
           A           $$    $$   $$   $$    $$   $$      $$       $$$      $$
          / \  ,&quot;|     $$     $$  $$   $$    $$ $  $     $ $$      $$$$    $$$
    ,&quot;|  [&quot;&quot;M#   A     $$     $$  $$$$$$     $$$$       $   $$     $$ $$  $ $$
      A   | #   /.\    $$     $$  $$   $$    $$ $  $   $$$$$$$$    $$  $$$  $$
     /.\ [&quot;&quot;M# [&quot;&quot;M#   $$    $$   $$    $$   $$   $$  $$     $$$   $$   $   $$
    [&quot;&quot;M# | #  U&quot;U#U  $$$$$$$$   $$$$   $$$ $$$$$$$$ $$$$   $$$$$ $$$$     $$$$
     | #  | #  \ .:/
     | #  | #___| #         $$$$          $$      $$$$  $$$$$  $$$$$$$$
     | &quot;--&apos;     .-&quot;          $$           $$       $$$$  $$$    $$    $$
   |&quot;-&quot;-&quot;-&quot;-&quot;-#-#-##         $$          $ $$       $ $$  $     $$     $$
   | D   # ## ######         $$         $   $$      $  $$ $     $$     $$
    \ L     .::::&apos;/          $$   $    $$$$$$$$     $   $$$     $$     $$
     \      ::::&apos;/           $$  $$   $$     $$$   $$$   $$$    $$    $$
   :8a|    # # ##           $$$$$$$$ $$$$   $$$$$ $$$$$  $$$$  $$$$$$$$
   ::88a      ###   
  ::::888a  8a ##                       
  ::::::888a88aLA                      http://dreamland.rocks 
 :::::::::::::::a8a	            telnet dreamland.rocks 9000
 :::::8::::888:Y8888              
::&apos;:::88::::888::Y88a                   
:: ::::88a::::88a:Y88a      1) KOI8-R          4) ISO (ISO-8859-5)   7) UTF-8
&apos; .: ::Y88a:::::8a:Y88a     2) ALT (CP866)     5) MAC
.::  :::Y88as88a...s88aa    3) WIN (CP1251)    6) Transliteration

Please, select your Russian codepage:</node>
  <node keyword="NEWYEARGREETING" level="-1" type="Help">%PAUSE%{Y           . &quot; -.
          &apos;       .
         .   {W({Y    . {C$$$$$$$$   $$$$$$$    $$$$$$$$      $$      $$$$     $$$$
             {W(){Y  .&apos;  {C$$    $$   $$   $$    $$   $$      $$       $$$      $$
          {Y`. {W`|{Y,.    {C$$     $$  $$   $$    $$ $  $     $ $$      $$$$    $$$
       {m      |&quot;|     {C$$     $$  $$$$$$     $$$$       $   $$     $$ $$  $ $$
             {M({m |     {C$$     $$  $$   $$    $$ $  $   $$$$$$$$    $$  $$$  $$
             {m|{M\{m|     {C$$    $$   $$    $$   $$   $$  $$     $$$   $$   $   $$
             {m| {M)    {C$$$$$$$$   $$$$   $$$ $$$$$$$$ $$$$   $$$$$ $$$$     $$$$
             {M( {m|                      
             {m|{M\{m|    {g _    {C$$$$          $$      $$$$  $$$$$  $$$$$$$$
 {G.\|,{m      {g_{m | {M){g _.-{G&gt;J     {C$$           $$       $$$$  $$$    $$    $$
 {G-&gt;{gJ|{G/, .  \{g&quot;&quot;{G-&quot;{G&quot;/{GVl/z     {C$$          $ $$       $ $$  $     $$     $$
  {G&apos;-t{gX|b{G|\|{g\^\k\^y{GJr/&apos;     {C$$         $   $$      $  $$ $     $$     $$
   {G&apos;^-{gj/PZ{G=\{gR&gt;p/{GT|&apos;        {C$$   $    $$$$$$$$     $   $$$     $$     $$
     {G._{g-s{GF{gK)/{G|&apos;&quot;           {C$$  $$   $$     $$$   $$$   $$$    $$    $$
    {G_-{gzH{G|/{y|               {C$$$$$$$$ $$$$   $$$$$ $$$$$  $$$$  $$$$$$$$
   {G--{g%/{G|  {y|                     
   {G&apos;/{g|{y    |                             
         {Y_{yM{Y_                     {Whttp://dreamland.rocks
      {Y,&apos;&quot;{Y_{Y  &quot;`.                {Wtelnet dreamland.rocks 9000 
     {Y/  {Y(_){Y    \             
    {Y|          {y.{Y|       
    {Y:         {y.:{Y;       
     {Y\ {Y`._   {y.:{Y/          {w1) KOI8-R          4) ISO (ISO-8859-5)   7) UTF-8 
      {Y`._ {y..:{Y;&apos;           {w2) ALT (CP866)     5) MAC
         {Y&quot;&quot;&quot;{x              {w3) WIN (CP1251)    6) Transliteration
Please, select your Russian codepage:</node>
  <node keyword="ROM2ANATOLIA WHATSNEW" level="-1" type="Help">.
%PAUSE%* ROM BUGs are fixed.
* PlayerKilling and Stealing is permitted for all levels, within
  restrictions of course.
* 7 Clans are implemented with special skills and spells.
* If one clan is raided and its item is taken and put to anothers clan
  shrine, the raided clan cannot use their clan powers.
* New 8 classes are added with full features.
* New 14 races are added with full features.
* Clan only, race only, alignment only spells and skills implemented.
* Some channels are removed (gossip,auction).
* New auction channel introduced.
* Over 200 new skills and spells are introduced.
* New practicing type is introduced.
* Damagable and repairable equipments are introduced.
* Bank is implemented.
* Color code is inserted.
* Mobiles started to track last foughts.
* Spells castable to room (room affects, do_raffect command) are implemented.
* Good players can request objects from good mobs.
* Anti-Paladins can demand objects from any mob (chance of attacking).
* Automatic rebooting system is implemented.
* New areas are added.
* Objects and Mobile progs are implemented.
* Ice melts in hot areas.
* New score command is introduced.( One can use old one with nscore command)
* In who command, one can restrict the clans, races or PKs.
* Players can pray the gods by pray channel.
* Automaticaly generated quest is introduced.
* Hero players can teach their 100% skills or spells to other players.
* Tailed mobile can now attack with their tails.
* When you look a mob, you can see its race.
* Hometowns and ethos are implemented.
* Religions and their related tattos are implemented
* Special quest kassandra (please read the referred books in melancholy).

</node>
  <node keyword="FROM20TO21" level="-1" type="Help">.
%PAUSE%* Reported bugs are fixed.
* Track has been rearranged.
* Players become able to shoot arrows, throwing spears with full features:
	poisoning, shocking, burning, frosting arrows and spears
	stuck in arrows and spears.
* Shot arrows or thrown spears may be stuck in the target mobiles.
* Riding skill is given to knights.
* In groups shalafi vs battle, chaos vs ruler, invader vs knight is prevented
* Spellbane become permanent with no cost of mana.
* Blade barrier, aid, desert fist,gate spells are given to clerics.
* Chance of damaging an object reduced.
* Tracking mobiles become able to open door.
* Golems autorescue their masters.
* If created golem kills master&apos;s quest mob, it is ok as well.
* Area flags introduced.
* Next questtimes has been rearranged.
* Quest code reconstructed. 
* Vampire became immune to negative attacks.
* Immunity to negative spell is given to necromancer.
* Spell craft adjustment done.
* Lance skill is given to knights for mount.
* Secondary attack given to warrior class.(Second attack for dual)
* Making arrow (blue,red,white,green) skills given to Ranger.
* Dishonoring is now optional for Samurais.
* Chance of tattoos has been increased.
* Is_same_group is reorganized.
* Leadership spell is given to rulers( immunity to charm).
* Evil spirit spell is given to invaders.
* Mortal strike skill is given to battleragers.
* Now offensive spells are castable to other rooms, as well:
	cast &apos;acid blast&apos; n.fido
	cast &apos;acid blast&apos; e.2.fido
* Mobiles starts to remember the players that once fight with them, untill
  they are killed, or anatolia is rebooted.
* Races of mobiles is now a header of mobiles description.
* PC&apos;s can speak either common language or their mothertongue.
* Only magical lights now can damage vampires.
* Track skill is now only for rangers.
* Shout and yell channels cannot be ON/OFF.
* Spell craft rearranged.

</node>
  <node keyword="DIKU" level="-1" type="Help">.%PAUSE%                    Original game idea, concept, and design:

          Katja Nyboe               [Superwoman] (katz@freja.diku.dk)
          Tom Madsen              [Stormbringer] (noop@freja.diku.dk)
          Hans Henrik Staerfeldt           [God] (bombman@freja.diku.dk)
          Michael Seifert                 [Papi] (seifert@freja.diku.dk)
          Sebastian Hammer               [Quinn] (quinn@freja.diku.dk)

Developed at: DIKU -- The Department of Computer Science
                      at the University of Copenhagen.
</node>
  <node keyword="MERC" level="-1" type="Help">%PAUSE%This mud is based on Merc 2.2, created by Furey, Hatchet, and Kahn.  
Merc 2.1 is available as Merc_22.tar.gz from ftp.game.org 

Thanks to ...
  ... Diku Mud for starting it all.
  ... The Free Software Foundation and DJ Delorie for kick-ass tools.
  ... Copper Mud and Alfa Mud for releasing their code and worlds.
  ... Aod of Generic for ... well, everything.  You&apos;re a hoopy frood, Aod.
  ... Alander for many ideas and contributions.
  ... John Brothers of Silly for permission to use Silly code and worlds.
  ... Zrin for administering the mailing list.
  ... Abaddon for proofreading our comm.c.
  ... Hind, Quin, Vic, Diavolo, Oleg, Trienne, and others for porting help.
  ... Diavolo, Grodyn, Morgenes, and others for code and bug fixes.
  ... Raff, Doctor, VampLestat, Nirrad, Tyrst, PinkF, Chris, Glop for worlds.
  ... the players and imps of Mud Dome, Final Mud, Mud Lite, Vego Mud, Rivers
      of Mud, Ruhr Mud, and Mystic Realms for bug reports, ideas, new code,
      and hours of enjoyment.

</node>
  <node keyword="ROM" level="-1" type="Help">ROM started in early February 1993, using Merc 1.0 code. In July of 1993,  
ROM II was started, eventually replacing the original ROM.  ROM was up for
a little over a year, after which the code (version 2.3) was released,
and various other ROM muds were started, including Rivers of Mud under
a new management (Zump&apos;s ROM), at rom.org 9000.

Alander&apos;s current project is Tesseract, the latest version of the ROM code.
It can be found at hypercube.org 9000.

The following people contributed to the ROM flavor of the merc base code:

Socials --
    Kelsey and Liralen

New, Improved Valhalla --
    Liralen

Puff&apos;s new special proc and improved poofin/poofout code --
    Seth

Maps and map shop --
    Ezra, Regnan (Olympus)

Nirvana zone --
    Forstall (mobiles rewritten by Alander)

Mob Factory --
    Pinkfloyd (originally written for ROM, mobiles rewritten by Alander)

Geographically correct Midgaard (tm) --
    Alander

Ideas and playtesting --
    Thousands of dedicated mudders around the world

Beta testing --
    Ken Blosser, Doug Araya, and Sherene Neil all helped with bug reports
    and suggestions, saving a lot of headaches

New Thalos area was donated by Onivel of Jedi, who was also the originator
of the ASCII flags used in the zone files

ROM 2.4 was developed during my time with Moosehead mud, and the release
shares many of the features I wrote while I was there.  Additional code
was written by Seth Scott (the new poofin/poofout), and many contributions
and ideas from the Merc list were used. 

The new features of 2.4 were largely produced in bull sessions with
Gabrielle (my wife) and Brian Moore, without whom this release wouldn&apos;t
have happened.  In particular, the new privacy code, furniture, and
wiznet are largely the results of Gabrielle&apos;s ideas.

Changes to the standard diku mob and object format, as well as the changes
to Merc 2.1 source code, were done by Alander over many a late night of
hair-pulling. Hope you enjoy it.

(my apologies if anyone was forgotten in this list)
</node>
  <node keyword="ANATOLIA" level="-1" type="Help">. 
      ANATOLIA started in early September 1996, using Rom2.4 code. In
June of 1997, ANATOLIA II was started, eventually replacing the original
ANATOLIA.

The following people contributed to the ANATOLIA flavor of the ROM base
code:

Addition of New Areas --
	Ibrahim Canpunar, Serdar Bulut and Murat Bicer

Revision of New Areas --
	Ibrahim Canpunar

Revision and Addition of New Helps --
	Ibrahim Canpunar and Serdar Bulut

Additional Maps --
	Ibrahim Canpunar

Ideas and playtesting --
    So many dedicated mudders around the world. Especially Amac Ural,
Mustafa Ongel, Ibrahim Uzel, Rasit Gumus, David Heide.

Complete C Code --
	chiefly by Serdar Bulut,
        with major contributions by Murat Bicer,
        and also Ibrahim Canpunar and Devrim Baris Acar. 

Used snippets (Available on internet) --
	Quest Code (c) 1996 Ryan Addams (moongate@moongate.ams.com)
	Some snippets by Erwin S. Andreasen. 
		erwin@pip.dknet.dk
</node>
  <node keyword="BACKDOORGREETING" level="-1" type="Help">Welcome to Dream Land building plot. The address of this world is
       telnet dreamland.rocks 9000 
              http://dreamland.rocks
     
1) KOI8-R           4) ISO (ISO-8859-5)  7) UTF-8
2) ALT (CP866)      5) MAC
3) WIN (CP1251)     6) Transliteration
Input your &lt;codepage&gt; &lt;username&gt; &lt;password&gt;: 
</node>
  <node keyword="WIZLIST GODS БОГИ" level="0" type="Help" labels="info">%PAUSE%{x     
{WБоги Мира Грез:{x
{G
         Руфина
         Баст
         Нимоа
         Тайфоэн 
         Пьянка
         Прадд
{x
{WБоги, ушедшие на заслуженный отдых:{x
{C
        NoFate, Разер, Тананда, Бастиан, Крадя, Годива, Кармина, Тилак,
        Корвин, Бурзум, Деккер, Мерикс, Кинд, Турлок, Стурм, Ирлана{x
        
{WОснователи{x: 

        {CВарда, Лео{x
</node>
</Help>
