<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc scavenger</act>
  <aff>flying</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">fly</affects>
  <form>edible sentient biped bird</form>
  <help id="326" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">ааракокран ааракокра ааракокраны</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">ааракокран ааракокра ааракокри</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Aarakocrans= -- sapient bird-folk with a city of perches and nests high in the mountains. Talons instead of hands, feathers instead of a hairdo, and wild luck in the air. Not particularly strong, but agile to a fault.

Well-protected against sound -- they make enough noise themselves to build up a tolerance. Acid, on the other hand, eats their feathers in an instant. In battle they disarm, parry, and dodge. Fly, naturally.

The main settlement is {hh2065Aarakokran City{x, hovering above {hh1867Elemental Canyon{x. Getting to them without wings takes either magic or luck.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Ааракокраны= -- разумные птицелюди с городом из жердочек и гнезд высоко в горах. Лапы вместо рук, перья вместо прически, и дикое везение в воздухе. Не больно сильны, зато ловки до неприличия.

Хорошо защищены от звука -- сами шумят достаточно, чтобы выработать иммунитет. Зато кислота их перья выедает мгновенно. В бою умеют обезоруживать, парировать и уклоняться. Летают, разумеется.

Главное поселение -- {hh2065Ааракокран{x, парящий над {hh1867Каньоном Стихий{x. Чтобы попасть к ним без крыльев, понадобятся либо магия, либо везение.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Ааракокрани= -- розумні птахолюди з містом із жердинок і гнізд високо в горах. Пазурі замість рук, пірʼя замість зачіски, і дика удача в повітрі. Не надто сильні, зате спритні до непристойності.

Добре захищені від звуку -- самі шумлять достатньо, щоб виробити імунітет. Зате кислота їхнє пірʼя виїдає вмить. У бою вміють обеззброювати, парирувати й ухилятися. Літають, ясна річ.

Головне поселення -- {hh2065Ааракокран{x, що ширяє над {hh1867Каньйоном Стихій{x. Щоб потрапити до них без крил, потрібна або магія, або везіння.
</text>
  </help>
  <nameFemale>ааракокра</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>ааракокран|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>ааракокран</nameMale>
  <off>disarm dodge fast parry</off>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye wings claws</parts>
  <res>sound</res>
  <size>medium</size>
  <stats>
    <str>-2</str>
    <int>2</int>
    <wis>1</wis>
    <dex>6</dex>
    <con>-2</con>
    <cha>-1</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>acid</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">finger_l second_wield neck_2 neck_1 finger_r wrist_r wrist_l body light shield head legs feet hands arms about waist wield hold float</wearloc>
</Race>
