<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultPCRace">
  <aff>flying</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">fly</affects>
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes>
    <thief>100</thief>
    <samurai>100</samurai>
    <warrior>100</warrior>
    <necromancer>100</necromancer>
    <ranger>100</ranger>
    <cleric>100</cleric>
    <witch>100</witch>
    <druid>100</druid>
    <anti-paladin>100</anti-paladin>
    <ninja>100</ninja>
    <paladin>100</paladin>
    <warlock>100</warlock>
    <vampire>-1</vampire>
  </classes>
  <form>edible sentient biped mammal bird</form>
  <help id="147" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en">arials</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">ариал ариалы ариелла</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">аріал аріали аріелла</keyword>
    <text l="en">Arials are half-human, half-bird -- the kings of the skies in the Dreamland. Their extraordinarily high intelligence and {hh563affinity for magic{x make them natural-born spellcasters. But to {hh575fly{x they must stay light, and this takes a toll on their strength and stamina. They easily endure the howl of wind and other loud sounds, yet their fragile build makes them prone to {hh614illness{x. And their delicate plumage is highly {hh101vulnerable{x to acid.

Adult, sapient arials possess impressive snow-white or pale-grey wings, with only subtle avian features -- pale skin, sharpened nails, a hooked nose, and enormous black pupils. A hypothesis exists that in the course of development or evolution, arials pass through a journey from a semi-wild avian form to a humanoid one nearly indistinguishable from humans. How this transformation happens and what the history of this evolutionary process is remains, for now, a mystery.

Arials prefer to stay silent about the origins of their race, their ancestral homeland, and in general about any traditions and laws of their society. Half-forgotten legends speak of a lost city deep in the Southern Mountains, inhabited by semi-sapient winged creatures -- {hh2065aarakocra{x. Unfortunately, no cartographer expedition has ever returned from those lands alive, so confirming or disproving the connection between arials and aarakocra is not yet possible.
</text>
    <text l="ru">Ариалы -- полулюди-полуптицы, короли небес Мира Мечты. Чрезвычайно высокий интеллект и {hh563склонность к колдовству{x делают их прирожденными магами. Но для {hh575полета{x им приходиться быть легкими, а это сказывается на их силе и выносливости. Они легко переносят шум ветра и другие громкие звуки, но из-за хрупкого телосложения часто {hh614болеют{x. А их тонкое оперение весьма {hh101уязвимо{x к кислоте.

Взрослые разумные ариалы обладают внушительными снежно-белыми или светло-серыми крыльями и лишь небольшими чертами птиц -- бледной кожей, заостренными ногтями, крючковатым носом и огромными черными зрачками. Существует гипотеза, что в процессе развития или эволюции ариалы проходят путь от полудикой птичьей до гуманоидной формы, почти неотличимой от людей. Как происходит эта трансформация и какова история данного эволюционного процесса пока остается загадкой.

Ариалы предпочитают сохранять молчание о происхождении своей расы, исторической родине, и в целом, о любых традициях и законах своего общества. Полузабытые предания говорят, что в глубине Южных гор есть затерянный город, населенный полуразумными крылатыми созданиями, {hh2065ааракокра{x. К сожалению, экспедициям картографов еще ни разу не удалось вернуться из тех краев в живых, так что подтвердить или опровергнуть связь ариалов и ааракокра пока не представляется возможным.
</text>
    <text l="ua">Аріали -- напівлюди-напівптахи, королі небес Світу Мрій. Надзвичайно високий інтелект і {hh563схильність до чаклунства{x роблять їх природженими магами. Але для {hh575польоту{x їм доводиться бути легкими, і це позначається на силі та витривалості. Вони легко переносять шум вітру та інші гучні звуки, проте через крихку статуру часто {hh614хворіють{x. А їхнє тонке опорядження дуже {hh101вразливе{x до кислоти.

Дорослі розумні аріали мають вражаючі сніжно-білі або світло-сірі крила і лише незначні риси птахів -- бліду шкіру, загострені нігті, гачкуватий ніс і величезні чорні зіниці. Існує гіпотеза, що в процесі розвитку або еволюції аріали проходять шлях від напівдикої пташиної до гуманоїдної форми, майже невідмінної від людей. Як відбувається це перетворення і яка історія цього еволюційного процесу -- поки лишається загадкою.

Аріали воліють мовчати про походження своєї раси, історичну батьківщину і взагалі про будь-які традиції та закони свого суспільства. Напівзабуті перекази говорять, що в глибині Південних гір є загублене місто, населене напіврозумними крилатими істотами -- {hh2065аараккокра{x. На жаль, жодній картографічній експедиції ще не вдалося повернутися з тих країв живою, тож підтвердити або спростувати звʼязок аріалів і аараккокра поки що неможливо.
</text>
  </help>
  <hpBonus>20</hpBonus>
  <manaBonus>50</manaBonus>
  <maxAlign>1000</maxAlign>
  <minAlign>-1000</minAlign>
  <nameFemale>ариелл|а|ы|е|у|ой|е</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>ариал||а|у|а|ом|е</nameMale>
  <nameMaleUa>аріал</nameMaleUa>
  <nameFemaleUa>аріелла</nameFemaleUa>
  <nameMltUa>аріали</nameMltUa>
  <nameMlt>ариал|ы|ов|ам|ов|ам|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameWho>Arial</nameWho>
  <nameWhoRus>Ариал</nameWhoRus>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye wings claws</parts>
  <points>250</points>
  <res>sound</res>
  <size>medium</size>
  <stats>
    <str>-1</str>
    <int>5</int>
    <wis>1</wis>
    <dex>1</dex>
    <con>-2</con>
  </stats>
  <vuln>acid disease</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float finger_l second_wield finger_r shield hands arms wield hold face tattoo tat_arms tat_face tat_wrist_l tat_wrist_r</wearloc>
</Race>
