<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc</act>
  <aff>swim regeneration</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">regeneration swim</affects>
  <form>edible animal mammal</form>
  <help id="310" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">медведь медведица медведи</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">ведмідь ведмедиця ведмеді</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Bears= -- large, shaggy, good-natured right up until the good nature ends. Strong, hardy, slow to wind up, but once wound up -- best step aside.

The thick hide deflects crushing blows and holds the cold -- even in winter a bear doesn't freeze. Wounds close on the move. They swim well. In battle they often fall into {hh829berserk rage{x, knock the weapon out with a paw, and in a hug can crush even a larger foe.

They turn up in {hh1442Mirkwood{x, in {hh1858The Continuity of Parks{x, and other places where the forest is thicker than the patches on a traveller's trousers.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Медведи= -- крупные, мохнатые, добродушные ровно до момента, когда добродушие заканчивается. Сильны, выносливы, медленны на разгон, но если уж разогнались -- держись.

Жирная шкура отбивает дробящие удары и держит холод -- даже зимой медведь не мерзнет. Раны заживают на ходу. Прекрасно плавают. В бою часто впадают в {hh829ярость{x, выбивают оружие лапой и в обнимку могут раздавить даже неприятеля покрупнее.

Встречаются в {hh1442Лихолесье{x, в {hh1858Непрерывности парков{x и других местах, где лес гуще, чем заплатки на штанах путника.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Ведмеді= -- великі, волохаті, добродушні рівно до моменту, коли добродушність закінчується. Сильні, витривалі, повільні на розгін, але як уже розігналися -- тримайся.

Жирна шкура відбиває дробильні удари й тримає холод -- навіть взимку ведмідь не мерзне. Рани гояться на ходу. Чудово плавають. У бою часто впадають у {hh829лють{x, вибивають зброю лапою і в обіймах можуть розчавити навіть супротивника крупніше.

Зустрічаються в {hh1442Лихоліссі{x, у {hh1858Безперервності Парків{x та інших місцях, де ліс гущий, ніж латки на штанах подорожнього.
</text>
  </help>
  <nameFemale>медведица</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>медвед|и|ей|ям|ей|ями|ях</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>медведь</nameMale>
  <off>berserk disarm crush</off>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts feet ear eye claws fangs</parts>
  <res>bash cold</res>
  <size>large</size>
  <stats>
    <str>5</str>
    <int>-5</int>
    <wis>1</wis>
    <dex>-4</dex>
    <con>5</con>
    <cha>-2</cha>
  </stats>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float</wearloc>
</Race>
