<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc</act>
  <aff>flying</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">fly</affects>
  <form>edible animal bird</form>
  <help id="344" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">птица птицы самец птицы самка птицы птахи</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">птаха птахи самець птаха самиця птаха</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Birds= -- winged, feathered, and best appreciated from a distance.
Eagles, hawks, pigeons, magpies, and every other busy resident of
hedges and skies.

Natural fliers. Quick in the air and slippery to hit. Feathers
muffle sound -- a screech won't deafen a bird. Disease, on the
other hand, runs through them quickly: a single sick flock can be
wiped out in a week.

Frail of body but sharp-eyed and nimble -- they spot small things
on the ground from on high.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Птицы= -- крылатые, перьями покрытые. Сюда относятся орлы,
ястребы, голуби, сороки и прочие занятые жители кустов и небес.

Естественно летают. В воздухе быстры и хорошо уклоняются от ударов.
Перья глушат звуковые удары -- громким криком птицу не оглушить.
Зато подвержены болезням: одна заражённая стая может вымереть за
неделю.

Телом слабы и хрупки, но ловки и зорки -- мелочи на земле видят
с воздуха.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Птахи= -- крилаті, пірʼям укриті. Сюди йдуть орли, яструби, голуби,
сороки та інші зайняті мешканці кущів і небес.

Природно літають. У повітрі швидкі й добре ухиляються від ударів.
Пірʼя глушить звукові удари -- голосним криком птаха не оглушити.
Зате піддаються хворобам: одна заражена зграя може вимерти за тиждень.

Тілом слабкі й крихкі, але спритні й зіркі -- дрібниці на землі
бачать з повітря.
</text>
  </help>
  <nameFemale>самка птицы</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>птиц|ы||ам||ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>самец птицы</nameMale>
  <off>dodge fast</off>
  <parts>head legs heart brains guts feet eye wings tail claws</parts>
  <res>sound</res>
  <size>small</size>
  <stats>
    <str>-3</str>
    <int>-1</int>
    <wis>2</wis>
    <dex>7</dex>
    <con>-3</con>
    <cha>1</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>disease</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 body light head legs about waist float tail</wearloc>
</Race>
