<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc</act>
  <aff>infrared sneak</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">infravision sneak</affects>
  <det>imp_invis fade invis hidden acute_vision</det>
  <form>edible animal feline mammal</form>
  <help id="341" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">кот кошка коты кошки</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">кіт кішка коти кішки</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Cats= -- small, lithe, silent, and suspiciously clever. At
times it seems they're appraising you: can you handle the task of
feeding them.

They see by infravision and through any invisibility, prowl
silently, strike like lightning, and dodge well. Cold doesn't
bother them -- the fur holds heat. Fire and water, though, kill
a cat outright: burns like dry brush, sinks like a stone.

Their special significance is to felars: a felar must never kill
a cat, and the {hh969Avenger{x comes after such a deed without
question. To everyone else a cat is either a household freeloader
or a back-alley mini-predator.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Кошки= -- мелкие, гибкие, бесшумные, и подозрительно умные.
Иногда кажется, что они тебя оценивают: справишься ли ты с задачей
их кормления.

Видят в инфракрасном диапазоне и сквозь любую невидимость, крадутся
бесшумно, бьют молниеносно и хорошо уклоняются. Холод им не страшен --
шерсть держит тепло. Зато огонь и вода кошку губят разом: горит как
сухой кустарник, тонет как камень.

Их особая ценность для феларов: убить кошку фелару нельзя, и
{hh969Мститель{x за такое идёт безоговорочно. Для остальных кошка --
обычно домашняя нахлебница либо мини-хищник из подворотни.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Коти= -- дрібні, гнучкі, безшумні, і підозріло розумні. Часом
здається, що вони тебе оцінюють: чи впораєшся ти із завданням їх
годувати.

Бачать у тепловому спектрі й крізь будь-яку невидимість, крадуться
безшумно, бʼють блискавично і добре ухиляються. Холод їм не страшний --
шерсть тримає тепло. Зате вогонь і вода кота гублять разом: горить
як сухий кущ, тоне як камінь.

Їхня особлива цінність для феларів: убити кота фелару не можна, і
{hh969Месник{x за таке йде безкомпромісно. Для інших кіт -- зазвичай
домашня нахлібниця або міні-хижак із підворіття.
</text>
  </help>
  <hunts registry="race">mouse rat fish</hunts>
  <nameFemale>кошка</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>кошк|и||ам||ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>кот</nameMale>
  <off>dodge fast</off>
  <parts>head legs heart brains guts feet ear eye tail claws fangs</parts>
  <res>cold</res>
  <size>small</size>
  <stats>
    <int>-4</int>
    <wis>-2</wis>
    <dex>7</dex>
    <con>-1</con>
    <cha>4</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>fire drowning</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float</wearloc>
</Race>
