<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultPCRace">
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes>
    <thief>100</thief>
    <samurai>100</samurai>
    <warrior>100</warrior>
    <necromancer>100</necromancer>
    <ranger>100</ranger>
    <cleric>100</cleric>
    <witch>100</witch>
    <druid>100</druid>
    <anti-paladin>100</anti-paladin>
    <ninja>100</ninja>
    <paladin>100</paladin>
    <warlock>100</warlock>
    <vampire>-1</vampire>
  </classes>
  <donates registry="race">centaur</donates>
  <form>edible animal sentient centaur mammal</form>
  <help id="151" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en">centaurs</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">кентавр кентавра кентавры</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">кентавр кентавриця кентаври</keyword>
    <text l="en">Centaurs are a race that arose from the excessively active love of humans for horses. Or the other way around -- horses for humans. Appearance: the lower half is equine (tail, hooves, four legs), the upper half is human. Centaurs are considerably larger and stronger, but rather unwieldy. Tough, they {hh101endure{x cold well. What they lack in high intellectual and moral qualities they make up for with tribal wisdom, attractiveness, and sturdy hooves.

They have no particular fondness for magic, but make use of the ancient tongue {hh2041Arcady{x. They are serious competition for satyrs in wine-drinking and other pleasant excesses. By nature centaurs are trusting and straightforward, and so become easy prey for {hh729charming{x spells. They fear electrical discharges (lightning). From childhood they learn to handle spears and shoot a bow.

Trousers and shoes designed for two-legged races will not, of course, fit centaurs, but they can wear horseshoes. In the city of {hh1423Anon{x there is a blacksmith named Zholob who will not only forge horseshoes for a (not-so-)modest fee, but will also {hh1366shoe{x you. The properties of horseshoes depend on level, so it makes sense to buy new ones from time to time. Over the horse body, centaurs can wear barding. Good barding can be found in the {hh1850Prairies{x}.

Centaurs possess an innate ability to strike {hh876two blows{x with their hooves. They know how to deliver a sudden, painful {hh869rear hoof{x kick to the head of anyone who sneaks up from behind with the intent to {hh620snap their neck{x or {hh782knock them out{x. They can {hh227carry{x other characters on their backs. All four-hoofed creatures have a much lower chance of falling to the ground when a {hh2021combat skill{x fails.

%SA% %H% {hh1002ask{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">Кентавры -- раса, произошедшая от чрезмерной активной любви людей к лошадям. Или наоборот -- лошадей к людям. Внешний вид: нижняя половина -- лошадиная (хвост, копыта, четыре ноги), верхняя -- человеческая. Кентавры значительно больше и сильнее, но довольно неповоротливы. Выносливы, хорошо {hh101переносят{x холода. Отсутствие высоких умственно-моральных качеств компенсируют племенной мудростью, привлекательностью и крепкими копытами.

К магии особого влечения не испытывают, но пользуются колдовством древнего языка {hh2041Аркади{x. Составляют серьезную конкуренцию сатирам в винораспитии и других приятных излишествах. По природе кентавры доверчивы и бесхитростны, а потому становятся легкой жертвой для {hh729очаровывающих{x заклинаний. Боятся электрических разрядов (молний). С детства учатся владеть копьями и стрелять из лука.

Штаны и ботинки, предназначенные для двуногих рас, на кентавров, разумеется, не налезут, зато они могут носить подковы. В городе {hh1423Аноне{x есть кузнец Жолоб, который не только изготовит подковы за (не)скромную плату, но и {hh1366подкует{x. Свойства подков зависят от уровня, поэтому имеет смысл периодически покупать новые. На лошадиное тело кентавры могут надевать попоны. Хорошие попоны можно найти в {hh1850Прериях{x.

Кентавры обладают врожденной способностью наносить по {hh876два удара{x копытами. Умеют неожиданно и больно дать {hh869задним копытом{x по лбу тому, кто подкрадывается к ним сзади с целью {hh620свернуть шею{x или {hh782усыпить{x. Могут {hh227возить{x на себе других персонажей. У всех четырехкопытных гораздо меньше вероятность при неудачном использовании {hh2021боевого навыка{x упасть наземь.

%SA% %H% {hh1002попросить{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">Кентаври -- раса, що виникла з надмірно активної любові людей до коней. Або навпаки -- коней до людей. Зовнішній вигляд: нижня половина -- коняча (хвіст, копита, чотири ноги), верхня -- людська. Кентаври значно більші й сильніші, але доволі неповороткі. Витривалі, добре {hh101переносять{x холоди. Відсутність високих розумово-моральних якостей компенсують племінною мудрістю, привабливістю й міцними копитами.

До магії особливого потягу не відчувають, але користуються чаклунством давньої мови {hh2041Аркаді{x. Складають серйозну конкуренцію сатирам у виновипиванні та інших приємних надмірностях. За природою кентаври довірливі й безхитрісні, а тому стають легкою здобиччю для {hh729зачаровуючих{x заклинань. Бояться електричних розрядів (блискавок). З дитинства вчаться володіти списами і стріляти з лука.

Штани й черевики, призначені для двоногих рас, на кентаврів, звісно, не налізуть, зате вони можуть носити підкови. У місті {hh1423Анон{x є коваль Жолоб, який не тільки виготовить підкови за (не)скромну платню, але й {hh1366підкує{x. Властивості підков залежать від рівня, тому має сенс час від часу купувати нові. На кінське тіло кентаври можуть надягати попони. Гарні попони можна знайти в {hh1850Преріях{x}.

Кентаври мають вроджену здатність завдавати {hh876два удари{x копитами. Вміють несподівано і боляче дати {hh869заднім копитом{x по лобі тому, хто підкрадається ззаду з метою {hh620звернути шию{x або {hh782приспати{x. Можуть {hh227возити{x на собі інших персонажів. У всіх чотирикопитних набагато менша ймовірність при невдалому використанні {hh2021бойової навички{x впасти на землю.

%SA% %H% {hh1002попросити{x
</text>
  </help>
  <hpBonus>20</hpBonus>
  <maxAlign>1000</maxAlign>
  <minAlign>-1000</minAlign>
  <nameFemale>кентавр|а|ы|е|у|ой|е</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>кентавр||а|у|а|ом|е</nameMale>
  <nameMlt>кентавр|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameWho>Centa</nameWho>
  <nameWhoRus>Кента</nameWhoRus>
  <off>bash kick kick_dirt</off>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands fingers ear eye tail four_hooves</parts>
  <points>250</points>
  <res>cold</res>
  <size>large</size>
  <stats>
    <str>3</str>
    <int>-1</int>
    <wis>2</wis>
    <dex>-3</dex>
    <con>3</con>
  </stats>
  <vuln>charm lightning</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head about waist float tail horse hooves finger_l second_wield finger_r shield hands arms wield hold face tattoo tat_arms tat_face tat_wrist_l tat_wrist_r</wearloc>
</Race>
