<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultPCRace">
  <aff>flying</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">fly</affects>
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes>
    <thief>100</thief>
    <samurai>100</samurai>
    <warrior>100</warrior>
    <necromancer>100</necromancer>
    <ranger>100</ranger>
    <cleric>100</cleric>
    <witch>100</witch>
    <druid>100</druid>
    <anti-paladin>100</anti-paladin>
    <ninja>100</ninja>
    <paladin>100</paladin>
    <warlock>100</warlock>
    <vampire>-1</vampire>
  </classes>
  <form>edible sentient mist biped mammal</form>
  <help id="153" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <extra l="en">cloudgiant</extra>
    <extra l="ru">гиганты облачная обвел великанша</extra>
    <extra l="ua">хмарний велетень хмарна велетка хмарні велетні</extra>
    <keyword l="en">&apos;cloud giants&apos;</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">облачные великаны</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">хмарні велетні</keyword>
    <text l="en">Cloud giants resemble enormous humans, standing roughly three metres tall. Their facial features are quite handsome and sharply defined. The skin of cloud giants ranges in colour from milky white with a bluish tint to the colour of a blue sky. Their hair is often silver-white or bronze, their eyes bright blue.

Cloud giants are wiser and far stronger than humans, but fall well short of other races in agility. They love music, fine clothing, and jewellery. In combat, cloud giants love to swing enormous maces and can find and hurl {hh218boulders{x at their opponents.

Their gaseous nature grants them the ability to {hh575fly{x, lets them slip more easily from {hh852nets{x, and makes them less vulnerable to cutting weapons -- but easily vulnerable to lightning. It is said that great mages of antiquity could muddle the minds of certain cloud giants and bend them to their will, then imprison them in sealed vessels -- copper lamps, for instance...
</text>
    <text l="ru">Облачные великаны напоминают огромных людей, ростом около трех метров. Черты лица -- довольно красивые и четко очерченные. Кожа облачных великанов варьируется по цвету от молочно-белой с голубоватым оттенком до цвета голубого неба. Цвет волос зачастую серебристо-белый или бронзовый, глаза -- ярко-голубые. 

Облачные великаны мудрее и гораздо сильнее людей, но сильно уступают другим расам в ловкости. Они любят музыку, изящную одежду и драгоценности. В бою облачные великаны любят махать огромными булавами, умеют находить и швырять в противника {hh218камни{x.

Их газообразная форма дарует им способность к {hh575полету{x, позволяет легче выпутываться из {hh852сетей{x и делает их менее уязвимыми к режущему оружию, но легко уязвимыми для молний. Говорят, что великим магам древности удавалось заморочить разум и покорить некоторых облачных великанов, а затем заточить в запечатанных сосудах -- например, медных лампах...
</text>
    <text l="ua">Хмарні велетні нагадують величезних людей заввишки близько трьох метрів. Риси обличчя -- досить гарні й чітко окреслені. Шкіра хмарних велетнів варіюється за кольором від молочно-білої з блакитнуватим відтінком до кольору блакитного неба. Колір волосся найчастіше срібно-білий або бронзовий, очі -- яскраво-блакитні.

Хмарні велетні мудріші й набагато сильніші за людей, але значно поступаються іншим расам у спритності. Вони люблять музику, вишуканий одяг і коштовності. У бою хмарні велетні люблять махати величезними булавами і вміють знаходити та жбурляти в противника {hh218каміння{x.

Їхня газоподібна форма дарує їм здатність до {hh575польоту{x, дозволяє легше вивільнятися з {hh852мереж{x і робить їх менш вразливими до ріжучої зброї, але легко вразливими для блискавок. Кажуть, що великим магам давнини вдавалося заморочити розум і підкорити деяких хмарних велетнів, а потім ув'язнити у запечатаних посудинах -- наприклад, мідних лампах...
</text>
  </help>
  <hpBonus>20</hpBonus>
  <manaBonus>-20</manaBonus>
  <maxAlign>1000</maxAlign>
  <minAlign>-1000</minAlign>
  <nameFemale>облачн|ая|ую|ой|ую|ой|ой великанш|а|и|е|у|ей|е</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>облачн|ый|ого|ому|ого|ым|ом великан||а|у|а|ом|е</nameMale>
  <nameMlt>облачн|ые|ых|ым|ых|ыми|ых великан|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameScore>облачн. вел.</nameScore>
  <nameWho>ClGia</nameWho>
  <nameWhoRus>ОбВел</nameWhoRus>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye</parts>
  <points>250</points>
  <res>slash</res>
  <size>huge</size>
  <stats>
    <str>5</str>
    <wis>2</wis>
    <dex>-6</dex>
    <con>3</con>
  </stats>
  <vuln>lightning mental</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float finger_l second_wield finger_r shield hands arms wield hold face tattoo tat_arms tat_face tat_wrist_l tat_wrist_r</wearloc>
</Race>
