<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc</act>
  <aff>regeneration</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">regeneration</affects>
  <form>edible animal canine mammal</form>
  <help id="334" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">пес собака псы собаки</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">пес собака пси</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Dogs= -- man's best friend, and the postman's worst foe. Loyal to the owner, aggressive to strangers, always ready to share their drool and fur.

The fur holds cold -- winter only helps. Wounds get licked on the move. Fire, though, is ruin: burning fur on a fast animal is a bad combination. In battle they bite like lightning and often fall into rage.

Cats can't stand them (mutually), {hh166felars{x especially. Dogs turn up almost anywhere, from {hh2089Mother Goose{x to {hh1862Haon Dor{x. Many can be tamed and made into followers.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Собаки= -- лучшие друзья человека, и худшие враги почтальона. Преданы хозяину, агрессивны к чужим, всегда готовы поделиться слюной и шерстью.

Шерсть держит холод -- зимой только лучше. Раны на ходу зализывают. Зато огонь для них губителен: горящая шерсть и быстрый зверь -- плохое сочетание. В бою кусают молниеносно и часто впадают в ярость.

Кошки терпеть их не могут (взаимно), {hh166фелары{x особенно. Найти собак можно практически где угодно, от {hh2089Матушки Гусыни{x до {hh1862Хаон Дора{x. Многих можно приручить и сделать своими последователями.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Собаки= -- найкращі друзі людини, і найгірші вороги поштаря. Віддані хазяїну, агресивні до чужих, завжди готові поділитися слиною й шерстю.

Шерсть тримає холод -- взимку лише краще. Рани на ходу зализують. Зате вогонь для них згубний: палаюча шерсть і швидкий звір -- погане поєднання. У бою кусають блискавично і часто впадають у лють.

Коти терпіти їх не можуть (взаємно), {hh166фелари{x особливо. Знайти собак можна практично де завгодно, від {hh2089Матінки Гуски{x до {hh1862Хаон Дора{x. Багатьох можна приручити і зробити своїми послідовниками.
</text>
  </help>
  <nameFemale>собака</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>собак|и||ам||ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>пес</nameMale>
  <off>berserk fast</off>
  <parts>head legs heart brains guts feet ear eye tail claws fangs</parts>
  <res>cold</res>
  <size>small</size>
  <stats>
    <int>-2</int>
    <wis>2</wis>
    <dex>2</dex>
    <con>2</con>
    <cha>2</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>fire</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float tail</wearloc>
</Race>
