<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc rideable</act>
  <aff>infrared flying</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">fly infravision</affects>
  <det>imp_invis invis</det>
  <form>edible sentient reptile dragon</form>
  <help id="347" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">дракон драконица драконы</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">дракон дракониця дракони</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Dragons= -- one of the oldest sentient races of Thera. Vast winged reptiles with shimmering scales and a maw equally suited to hunting deer and rewriting world history. A dragon's intellect rivals a human's, and its memory reaches back to when mortals were still learning to speak.

Fire is the dragon's element -- it bathes in flame without harm. The scales resist charm magic, spells, crushing blows, and mental attacks. The one weak spot is the joints between the scales, where piercing weapons slip in. They fly, see by {hh830infravision{x and through invisibility. In battle they claw an entire area, parry strikes, and lash with the tail.

The best-known strongholds are {hh1419Dragon Spyre{x with Fireflash, {hh2063Dragon Tower{x with Tiamat herself, and {hh2090Cloudy Mountain{x. Without a prepared party and a good spear, don't bother going there.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Драконы= -- одна из древнейших разумных рас Тэры. Огромные крылатые рептилии с переливающейся чешуей и пастью, которой удобно как охотиться на оленей, так и переписывать историю мира. Интеллект драконов не уступает человеческому, память помнит времена, когда смертные еще учились говорить.

Огонь -- родная стихия, дракон в нем купается без вреда. Чешуя устойчива к чарам очарования, к заклинаниям, к дробящим ударам и к ментальным атакам. Уязвимое место одно: сочленения чешуи, через которые проходит колющее оружие. Летают, видят {hh830в инфракрасном диапазоне{x и сквозь невидимость. В бою бьют когтями всей округе, парируют удары и хлещут хвостом.

Самые известные поселения -- {hh1419Пик Драконов{x с Огневспышкой, {hh2063Замок Драконов{x с самой Тиамат и {hh2090Облачная Гора{x. Без подготовленной группы и хорошего копья туда лучше не соваться.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Дракони= -- одна з найдавніших розумних рас Тери. Величезні крилаті рептилії з переливчастою лускою й пащею, якою зручно як полювати на оленів, так і переписувати історію світу. Інтелект драконів не поступається людському, памʼять памʼятає часи, коли смертні ще вчилися говорити.

Вогонь -- рідна стихія, дракон у ньому купається без шкоди. Луска стійка до чарів очарування, до закляттів, до дробних ударів і до ментальних атак. Вразливе місце одне: зчленування луски, крізь які проходить колюча зброя. Літають, бачать {hh830тепловим зором{x і крізь невидимість. У бою бʼють пазурами всю округу, парирують удари й хльоскають хвостом.

Найвідоміші поселення -- {hh1419Пік Драконів{x з Огневспалахом, {hh2063Башта Драконів{x із самою Тіамат і {hh2090Хмарна Гора{x. Без підготованої групи й гарного списа туди краще не сунутися.
</text>
  </help>
  <imm>fire</imm>
  <nameFemale>драконица</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>дракон|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>дракон</nameMale>
  <off>area_attack parry tail crush</off>
  <parts>head legs heart brains guts ear eye long_tongue wings tail claws fangs scales</parts>
  <res>charm spell bash mental</res>
  <size>huge</size>
  <stats>
    <str>3</str>
    <int>5</int>
    <wis>5</wis>
    <dex>-2</dex>
    <con>3</con>
    <cha>2</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>pierce</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 body light head legs about waist float tail</wearloc>
</Race>
