<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultPCRace">
  <aff>infrared</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">infravision</affects>
  <align>evil</align>
  <classes>
    <thief>100</thief>
    <samurai>100</samurai>
    <warrior>100</warrior>
    <necromancer>100</necromancer>
    <ranger>100</ranger>
    <cleric>100</cleric>
    <witch>100</witch>
    <druid>-1</druid>
    <anti-paladin>100</anti-paladin>
    <ninja>100</ninja>
    <paladin>-1</paladin>
    <warlock>100</warlock>
    <vampire>-1</vampire>
  </classes>
  <form>edible sentient biped mammal</form>
  <help id="154" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en">&apos;dark dwarf&apos; duergars</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">дуэргар дуэргары дуэргарша &apos;темные карлики&apos;</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">дуергар дуергари дуергарка &apos;темні карлики&apos;</keyword>
    <text l="en">Duergar (also known as gray dwarves or dark dwarves) came to this world from {hh1854the Underdark{x. Duergar are very strong, agile, and hardy creatures, but solitude and irritability have greatly dulled their intellect. Centuries spent in rotten half-darkness have granted them {hh101resistance{x to disease. But, like their kin on the surface, they hate water and fear acid.

Duergar are slightly shorter than humans, with dull gray skin and a bald head adorned with stubbornly disheveled white beard. Their black eyes, usually full of malice and contempt, frequently fill with blood, sending duergar into a {hh829berserk{x frenzy. They love axes and are skilled at working with {hh714lockpicks{x and locks. Duergar make excellent thieves and ninjas, but other warrior classes suit them well too.
</text>
    <text l="ru">Дуэргары (они же серые дварфы или темные карлики) пришли в этот мир из {hh1854Подземья{x. Дуэргары -- очень сильные, ловкие и выносливые создания, но одиночество и раздражительность сильно притупили их интеллект. Века, проведенные в гнилом полумраке, даровали им {hh101устойчивость{x к болезням. Но, как и их родичи с поверхности, они ненавидят воду и боятся кислоты.

Дуэргары совсем немного ниже людей, у них тускло-серая кожа и лысая башка, украшенная упрямо всклокоченной белой бородой. Черные глаза, обычно наполненные злобой и презрением, частенько наливаются кровью, вводя дуэргаров в состояние {hh829берсерка{x. Они обожают топоры и хорошо умеют разбираться в {hh714отмычках{x и замках. Из дуэргаров получаются прекрасные воры и ниндзи, но и другие воинские классы им тоже хорошо даются.
</text>
    <text l="ua">Дуергари (вони ж сірі дварфи або темні карлики) прийшли до цього світу з {hh1854Підземʼя{x. Дуергари -- дуже сильні, спритні та витривалі створіння, але самотність і роздратованість сильно притупили їхній інтелект. Століття, проведені в гнилому напівмороці, даровали їм {hh101стійкість{x до хвороб. Але, як і їхні родичі з поверхні, вони ненавидять воду і бояться кислоти.

Дуергари трохи нижчі за людей, у них тьмяно-сіра шкіра та лиса голова, прикрашена вперто скуйовдженою білою бородою. Чорні очі, зазвичай сповнені злоби та презирства, часто наливаються крівʼю, вводячи дуергарів у стан {hh829берсерка{x. Вони обожнюють сокири і добре розбираються в {hh714відмичках{x та замках. З дуергарів виходять чудові злодії та ніндзі, але й інші воїнські класи їм теж добре даються.
</text>
  </help>
  <hpBonus>25</hpBonus>
  <manaBonus>-10</manaBonus>
  <maxAlign>-300</maxAlign>
  <minAlign>-1000</minAlign>
  <nameFemale>дуэргарш|а|и|е|у|ей|е</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>дуэргар||а|у|а|ом|е</nameMale>
  <nameMlt>дуэргар|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameWho>Duerg</nameWho>
  <nameWhoRus>Дуэрг</nameWhoRus>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye</parts>
  <points>250</points>
  <res>disease</res>
  <size>medium</size>
  <stats>
    <str>2</str>
    <int>-2</int>
    <dex>2</dex>
    <con>3</con>
  </stats>
  <vuln>acid drowning</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float finger_l second_wield finger_r shield hands arms wield hold face tattoo tat_arms tat_face tat_wrist_l tat_wrist_r</wearloc>
</Race>
