<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc warrior</act>
  <aff>regeneration</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">regeneration</affects>
  <det>hidden life</det>
  <form>magical instant_decay nonadoptable sentient construct biped</form>
  <help id="312" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">земной элементаль земная элементаль</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">земний елементаль земна елементаль</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Earth elementals= -- walking heaps of stone and soil animated
by magic. Slow, heavy, and remarkably stubborn. Literally.

Stone fears neither poison nor disease -- poisoning a pile of
granite is pointless. Summons and ordinary weapons bounce off:
they shatter into rubble, the elemental gathers itself back. Force
magic and loud sound, though, smash it to gravel: stone cracks
from resonance. They see the hidden and the living nearby.

In battle they strike whole areas, go berserk, kick, fling clods
of dirt, and crush with the full mass. The natural home is
{hh1867Elemental Canyon{x.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Земные элементали= -- ходячие груды камня и грунта, оживлённые
магией. Медленные, тяжёлые, и удивительно упёртые. В прямом смысле.

Камню не страшны ни яды, ни болезни -- травить груду гранита глупо.
Призывы и обычное оружие отскакивают: то рассыпается осыпью, элементаль
собирается заново. Зато силовая магия и громкий звук разносят его в
крошку: камень трескается от резонанса. Видят прячущихся и живое
поблизости.

В бою бьют площадными ударами, впадают в ярость, лягают, бросаются
комьями земли и сокрушают всей массой. Естественный дом --
{hh1867Каньон Стихий{x.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Земні елементалі= -- ходячі купи каменю й ґрунту, оживлені
магією. Повільні, важкі, і дивовижно вперті. В прямому сенсі.

Каменю не страшні ні отрути, ні хвороби -- труїти купу граніту
безглуздо. Призиви й звичайна зброя відскакують: то розсипається
осипом, елементаль збирається наново. Зате силова магія й гучний
звук розносять його на крихту: камінь тріскає від резонансу.
Бачать прихованих і живе поблизу.

У бою бʼють площадними ударами, впадають у лють, хвицають, кидаються
грудками землі і трощать усією масою. Природний дім --
{hh1867Каньйон Стихій{x.
</text>
  </help>
  <imm>poison disease</imm>
  <nameFemale>земная элементаль</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>земн|ые|ых|ым|ых|ыми|ых элементал|и|ей|ям|ей|ями|ях</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>земной элементаль</nameMale>
  <off>area_attack berserk kick kick_dirt crush</off>
  <parts>head arms legs hands feet fingers</parts>
  <res>summon weapon</res>
  <size>large</size>
  <stats>
    <str>5</str>
    <wis>6</wis>
    <dex>-5</dex>
    <con>8</con>
    <cha>-2</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>energy sound</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">finger_l second_wield neck_2 neck_1 finger_r wrist_r wrist_l body light shield head legs feet hands arms about waist wield hold float tattoo face</wearloc>
</Race>
