<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultPCRace">
  <aff>flying</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">fly</affects>
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes>
    <thief>100</thief>
    <samurai>100</samurai>
    <warrior>100</warrior>
    <necromancer>100</necromancer>
    <ranger>100</ranger>
    <cleric>100</cleric>
    <witch>100</witch>
    <druid>100</druid>
    <anti-paladin>100</anti-paladin>
    <ninja>100</ninja>
    <paladin>100</paladin>
    <warlock>100</warlock>
    <vampire>-1</vampire>
  </classes>
  <form>edible magical sentient biped mammal</form>
  <help id="155" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en">faeries faery fairy</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">фаэри феи фейри фея</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">феї фей фея фаері</keyword>
    <text l="en">Faeries are tiny, sparkling creatures with wings, the native inhabitants of the lands of {hh1429Arcadia{x. Being magical creatures by nature, they are very intelligent and possess enormous {hh563aptitude for spells{x. Faeries easily deflect energy and light-based attacks. That said, faeries are very weak and fragile, and therefore easily succumb to poison and disease.

Every faerie has access to the magic of their race -- {hh554faerie fire{x and {hh790faerie fog{x. In combat, faeries can {hh750blink{x: escaping an opponent's attacks with rapid teleports. Faeries make excellent mages and decent hybrid classes -- for example, paladins and anti-paladins.
</text>
    <text l="ru">Феи -- крохотные искристые существа с крылышками, исконные жители земель {hh1429Аркадии{x. Будучи изначально магическими существами, они очень умны и обладают огромной {hh563склонностью к заклинаниям{x. Феи легко отражают энергетические и световые атаки. Впрочем, феи очень слабенькие и хрупкие, а потому легко поддаются ядам и болезням. 

Любой фее доступна магия их расы -- {hh554огонь фей{x и {hh790туман фей{x. А в бою феи умеют {hh750мерцат{xь: быстрыми телепортами уходить от атак противника. Из фей получаются отличные маги и неплохие гибридные классы -- например, паладины и анти-паладины.
</text>
    <text l="ua">Феї -- крихітні іскристі істоти з крилами, корінні мешканці земель {hh1429Аркадії{x. Будучи від природи магічними істотами, вони дуже розумні й мають величезну {hh563схильність до заклинань{x. Феї легко відбивають енергетичні й світлові атаки. Втім, феї дуже слабенькі й крихкі, тому легко піддаються отруті й хворобам.

Будь-якій феї доступна магія їхньої раси -- {hh554вогонь фей{x і {hh790туман фей{x. А в бою феї вміють {hh750мерехтіти{x: швидкими телепортами уникати атак противника. З фей виходять чудові маги і непогані гібридні класи -- наприклад, паладини й антипаладини.
</text>
  </help>
  <hpBonus>20</hpBonus>
  <manaBonus>50</manaBonus>
  <maxAlign>1000</maxAlign>
  <minAlign>-1000</minAlign>
  <nameFemale>фе|я|и|е|ю|ей|е</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>фе|й|я|ю|я|ем|е</nameMale>
  <nameMlt>фе|и|й|ям|й|ями|ях</nameMlt>
  <nameWho>Faery</nameWho>
  <nameWhoRus>Фея</nameWhoRus>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye wings</parts>
  <points>250</points>
  <res>energy light</res>
  <size>small</size>
  <stats>
    <str>-3</str>
    <int>5</int>
    <wis>3</wis>
    <con>-3</con>
  </stats>
  <vuln>poison disease</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float finger_l second_wield finger_r shield hands arms wield hold face tattoo tat_arms tat_face tat_wrist_l tat_wrist_r</wearloc>
</Race>
