<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc mage</act>
  <aff>faerie_fire infrared flying</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">fly infravision &apos;faerie fire&apos;</affects>
  <det>imp_invis fade invis hidden acute_vision</det>
  <form>magical instant_decay nonadoptable sentient intangible</form>
  <help id="317" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">огненный элементаль огненная элементаль</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">вогняний елементаль вогняна елементаль</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Fire elementals= -- living tongues of flame, just sentient
enough to know where the fuel is. Hugging them is not advised
even when it's very cold.

Fire is their native element -- they bathe in it unharmed. Summons
and ordinary weapons pass through the flame with little effect.
Cold, though, smothers the fire, and water puts them out for good --
drowning an elemental in a river is easier than cutting it down.

They glow on their own, betray invisible foes with faerie fire,
see by infravision and through any concealment. They fly. In
battle they strike with area flares, go berserk, and crush with
a mass of flame.

Home is {hh1867Elemental Canyon{x. They also turn up in
{hh1851Hell{x and other hot spots.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Огненные элементали= -- живые языки пламени, разумные ровно
настолько, чтобы знать, где горючее. В обнимку с ними лучше не
бросаться, даже если очень холодно.

Огонь для них родная стихия -- купаются и не вредятся. Призывы и
обычное оружие проходят сквозь пламя без особого вреда. Зато холод
сводит огонь на нет, а вода тушит окончательно -- утопить элементаля
в реке проще, чем зарубить.

Светятся сами, выдают невидимых волшебным огнём, видят в инфракрасном
диапазоне и сквозь любые сокрытия. Летают. В бою бьют площадными
вспышками, впадают в ярость и сокрушают массой пламени.

Дом -- {hh1867Каньон Стихий{x. Также встречаются в {hh1851Аду{x и
других горячих точках.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Вогняні елементалі= -- живі язики полумʼя, розумні рівно
настільки, щоб знати, де паливо. В обіймах із ними краще не
кидатися, навіть якщо дуже холодно.

Вогонь для них рідна стихія -- купаються і не шкодяться. Призиви
й звичайна зброя проходять крізь полумʼя без особливої шкоди. Зате
холод зводить вогонь нанівець, а вода гасить остаточно -- утопити
елементаля в річці простіше, ніж зарубати.

Світяться самі, видають невидимих чарівним вогнем, бачать у
тепловому спектрі і крізь будь-які приховання. Літають. У бою бʼють
площадними спалахами, впадають у лють і трощать масою полумʼя.

Дім -- {hh1867Каньйон Стихій{x. Також зустрічаються в
{hh1851Пеклі{x та інших гарячих точках.
</text>
  </help>
  <imm>fire</imm>
  <nameFemale>огненная элементаль</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>огненн|ые|ых|ым|ых|ыми|ых элементал|и|ей|ям|ей|ями|ях</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>огненный элементаль</nameMale>
  <nameNeuter>огненный элементаль</nameNeuter>
  <off>area_attack berserk dodge fast crush</off>
  <res>summon weapon</res>
  <size>large</size>
  <stats>
    <str>4</str>
    <int>5</int>
    <wis>3</wis>
    <dex>2</dex>
    <con>-2</con>
    <cha>-2</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>cold drowning</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">light about float</wearloc>
</Race>
