<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc aggressive</act>
  <aff>infrared curse regeneration</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">regeneration infravision curse</affects>
  <det>hidden life</det>
  <form>poison undead biped</form>
  <help id="309" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">упырь упырица упыри</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">упир упириця упирі</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Ghouls= -- corpse-eaters and fans of all things decaying.
Not quite alive, not quite not, but definitely hungry. Long nails,
crooked teeth, breath... you get the idea.

What's inside them is hard to make worse -- poison, disease and
dark energy are no obstacle. Charm doesn't work on them either,
and cold they barely feel. Fire, holy power, bright light and
silver, though, are an execution for a ghoul: they flare up like
kindling and retreat with a shriek.

They see the living, the hidden, and by infravision; the curse is
ever upon them; wounds knit on the move. In battle they go berserk,
kick, parry, trip, crush, dodge, and move fast.

They prowl near {hh2078Graveyard{x, in {hh1865Chapel Dungeon{x
and in {hh2039Old Marsh{x. They feed mostly on carrion, but won't
turn down the fresh either.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Упыри= -- труподеды и любители всего разлагающегося. Не то
живые, не то нет, но определённо голодные. Ногти длинные, зубы кривые,
дыхание... ну ты понимаешь.

Что внутри у них уже трудно ухудшить -- яды, болезни и тёмная энергия
упырю не помеха. Очарование на них тоже не действует, и холода они
почти не чувствуют. Зато огонь, святая сила, яркий свет и серебро для
упыря -- казнь: вспыхивают как лучина и отступают визжа.

Видят живое, прячущихся и в инфракрасном диапазоне, проклятие при
них всегда, раны зарастают на ходу. В бою впадают в ярость, лягают,
парируют, подсекают, сокрушают, уклоняются и стремительны.

Промышляют у {hh2078Кладбища{x, в {hh1865Подземелье Часовни{x и в
{hh2039Старой Топи{x. Питаются в основном падалью, но свежим тоже
не побрезгуют.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Упирі= -- трупоїди й любителі всього, що розкладається.
Чи то живі, чи то ні, але точно голодні. Нігті довгі, зуби криві,
дихання... ну ти розумієш.

Що в них усередині, погіршити вже важко -- отрути, хвороби й темна
енергія упирю не завада. Очарування на них теж не діє, і холоду
вони майже не відчувають. Зате вогонь, свята сила, яскраве світло
і срібло для упиря -- кара: спалахують як скіпка і відступають з
вереском.

Бачать живе, прихованих і в тепловому спектрі, прокляття при них
завжди, рани заростають на ходу. У бою впадають у лють, хвицають,
парирують, підсікають, нищать, ухиляються і стрімкі.

Промишляють біля {hh2078Цвинтаря{x, в {hh1865Підземеллі Каплиці{x
і в {hh2039Старому Болоті{x. Харчуються переважно падаллю, але
свіжим теж не погребують.
</text>
  </help>
  <imm>poison negative disease</imm>
  <nameFemale>упырица</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>упыр|и|ей|ям|ей|ями|ях</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>упырь</nameMale>
  <off>berserk dodge fast kick parry trip crush</off>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye claws fangs</parts>
  <res>charm cold</res>
  <size>medium</size>
  <stats>
    <str>3</str>
    <int>-4</int>
    <wis>-4</wis>
    <dex>2</dex>
    <con>2</con>
    <cha>-5</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>fire holy light silver</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">finger_l neck_2 neck_1 finger_r wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet arms about waist hold float face</wearloc>
</Race>
