<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc scavenger</act>
  <aff>infrared</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">infravision</affects>
  <form>poison sentient biped mammal</form>
  <help id="337" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">гоблин гоблинша гоблины</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">гоблін гоблінка гобліни</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Goblins= -- small, green, noisy, and remarkably tough to kill. A pack of goblins is noise, filth, and a surprisingly coordinated &apos;overwhelm with numbers&apos; tactic.

They&apos;re used to dirt and infection -- disease barely touches them. Magic, though, mows them down fast: spells and mental attacks pass through a thin skull with no resistance. They see by infravision. One on one they&apos;re weak, in numbers -- a problem.

Main nests are {hh2049Goblin Stronghold{x, {hh2081Goblin Nation{x, and the villages around them. Their hatred for {hh1439gnomes{x is in their nature and not up for discussion.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Гоблины= -- мелкие, зеленые, шумные и удивительно живучие. Стая гоблинов -- это шум, грязь и неожиданно слаженная тактика &quot;завалить количеством&quot;.

Привычны к грязи и заразе -- болезни их почти не берут. Зато магия их выкашивает быстро: и заклинания, и ментальные атаки идут сквозь тонкий череп без сопротивления. Видят в инфракрасном диапазоне. По одиночке слабы, в большом количестве -- проблема.

Главные гнездилища -- {hh2049Крепость Гоблинов{x, {hh2081Земля гоблинов{x и деревни вокруг них. Их злоба к {hh1439гномам{x по природе и не обсуждается.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Гобліни= -- дрібні, зелені, галасливі і дивовижно живучі. Зграя гоблінів -- це шум, бруд і несподівано злагоджена тактика &quot;завалити кількістю&quot;.

Звиклі до бруду й зарази -- хвороби їх майже не беруть. Зате магія їх викошує швидко: і закляття, і ментальні атаки йдуть крізь тонкий череп без опору. Бачать у тепловому спектрі. По одному слабкі, в великій кількості -- проблема.

Головні гніздилища -- {hh2049Твердиня Гоблінів{x, {hh2081Земля Гоблінів{x і села навколо них. Їхня злоба до {hh1439гномів{x за природою і не обговорюється.
</text>
  </help>
  <nameFemale>гоблинша</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>гоблин</nameMale>
  <nameMaleUa>гоблін</nameMaleUa>
  <nameFemaleUa>гоблінка</nameFemaleUa>
  <nameMltUa>гобліни</nameMltUa>
  <nameMlt>гоблин|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye</parts>
  <res>disease</res>
  <size>small</size>
  <stats>
    <str>-1</str>
    <int>-2</int>
    <wis>-1</wis>
    <dex>2</dex>
    <con>1</con>
    <cha>-1</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>spell mental</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">finger_l second_wield neck_2 neck_1 finger_r wrist_r wrist_l body light shield head legs feet hands arms about waist wield hold float tattoo face</wearloc>
</Race>
