<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultPCRace">
  <aff>sneak</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">sneak</affects>
  <align>good neutral evil</align>
  <classes>
    <thief>100</thief>
    <samurai>100</samurai>
    <warrior>100</warrior>
    <necromancer>100</necromancer>
    <ranger>100</ranger>
    <cleric>100</cleric>
    <witch>100</witch>
    <druid>100</druid>
    <anti-paladin>100</anti-paladin>
    <ninja>100</ninja>
    <paladin>100</paladin>
    <warlock>100</warlock>
    <vampire>-1</vampire>
  </classes>
  <form>edible sentient biped mammal</form>
  <help id="148" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en">kenders kendr</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">кендер кендеры кендерша кендр</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">кендер кендери кендерка кендр</keyword>
    <text l="en">Kender are short in stature and resemble humans in appearance. They love to wear their long hair tied in a topknot at the back of the head. Kender ears are as pointed as those of elves, and their eyes glow with the liveliest curiosity and a burning love of adventure. Kender adore stories and know the {hh644legends{x and tales of Thera to perfection.

The favourite weapon of kender is the hoopak, a special forked staff. But they also have an excellent affinity for other staves and spears. Accustomed to the din of large cities, they do not fear loud sounds, but cannot stand the cold. Kender are one of the most agile races, though they are not distinguished by great strength or endurance.

Of all the races inhabiting the Dreamland, kender are among the least aggressive -- but perhaps the most irritating. Some even say that the very appearance of kender on the lands of Thera was an unfortunate mistake of the Gods, one that led to the arrival of {hh977Erevan Ilesere{x and the entire kender race. The location of the kender homeland, Kendermore, remains a secret to this day.

Kender are the carriers of the great ideas "all property not mine is all mine" and "anything not nailed down and pried loose counts as fair game." They steal absolutely everything without any pangs of conscience. Pathological kleptomaniacs -- it is better not to invite them as guests. Or at least lock everything up in a safe first, then bury the safe deep in the garden. Hide {hh238the shovel{x too.
</text>
    <text l="ru">Росту кендеры маленького, внешне похожи на людей. Длинные волосы они обожают собирать в хвост на затылке. Ушки у кендеров острые как у эльфов, а глаза светятся живейшим любопытством и горячей любовью к приключениям. Кендеры обожают истории и в совершенстве знают {hh644легенды{x и сказки Тэры.

Любимое оружие кендеров -- хупак, специальный раздвоенный посох. Но и к другим посохам и копьям у них отличная склонность. Привычные к гулу больших городов, они не боятся громких звуков, но терпеть не могут холода. Кендеры -- одна из самых ловких рас, но не отличаются большой силой и выносливостью.

Из всех рас, населяющих Мир Мечты, кендеры -- один из наименее агрессивных, но, пожалуй, один из наиболее раздражающих народов. Поговаривают даже, что само появление кендеров на просторах Тэры -- досадная ошибка Богов, которая привела к проникновению в мир {hh977Эревана Илесира{x и всей расы кендеров. Местонахождение коренной территории кендеров, Кендермора, и поныне -- тайна. 

Кендеры -- носители великих идей &quot;чужая собственность -- вся моя&quot; и &quot;все, что плохо прибито и можно оторвать, считается плохо лежащим&quot;. Крадут абсолютно все, не мучаясь никакими угрызениями совести. Патологические клептоманы -- в гости таких лучше не приглашать. Ну, или предварительно сложить все вещи в сейф, а сейф закопать в саду поглубже. {hh238Лопату{x тоже спрятать.
</text>
    <text l="ua">Кендери невисокого зросту і зовні схожі на людей. Довге волосся вони обожнюють збирати у хвіст на потилиці. Вуха у кендерів гострі як у ельфів, а очі світяться найжвавішою цікавістю і гарячою любовʼю до пригод. Кендери обожнюють історії і досконало знають {hh644легенди{x та казки Тери.

Улюблена зброя кендерів -- гупак, спеціальний роздвоєний посох. Але й до інших посохів та списів у них чудова схильність. Звикші до гулу великих міст, вони не бояться гучних звуків, але терпіти не можуть холоду. Кендери -- одна з найспритніших рас, але не відрізняються великою силою і витривалістю.

З усіх рас, що населяють Світ Мрій, кендери -- один із найменш агресивних, але, мабуть, один із найбільш дратівливих народів. Кажуть навіть, що сама поява кендерів на просторах Тери -- прикра помилка Богів, яка призвела до проникнення у світ {hh977Еревана Ілесіра{x і всієї раси кендерів. Місцезнаходження корінної території кендерів, Кендермора, і досі -- таємниця.

Кендери -- носії великих ідей "чужа власність -- уся моя" і "все, що погано прибите і можна відірвати, вважається погано закладеним". Крадуть абсолютно все, не мучачись жодними докорами сумління. Патологічні клептомани -- в гості таких краще не запрошувати. Ну, або попередньо скласти все у сейф, а сейф закопати в саду якомога глибше. {hh238Лопату{x теж сховати.
</text>
  </help>
  <hpBonus>20</hpBonus>
  <maxAlign>1000</maxAlign>
  <minAlign>-1000</minAlign>
  <nameFemale>кендерш|а|и|е|у|ей|е</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>кендер||а|у|а|ом|е</nameMale>
  <nameMlt>кендер|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameWho>Kendr</nameWho>
  <nameWhoRus>Кендр</nameWhoRus>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye</parts>
  <points>250</points>
  <res>sound</res>
  <size>small</size>
  <stats>
    <str>-2</str>
    <dex>5</dex>
    <con>-2</con>
  </stats>
  <vuln>cold</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float finger_l second_wield finger_r shield hands arms wield hold face tattoo tat_arms tat_face tat_wrist_l tat_wrist_r</wearloc>
</Race>
