<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc warrior</act>
  <form>edible sentient biped mammal</form>
  <help id="330" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">минотавр мужчина минотавр женщина минотавр минотавры</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">мінотавр чоловік мінотавр жінка мінотавр мінотаври</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Minotaurs= -- half-man, half-bull, with a heavy temper and
an even heavier fist. Tall, muscular, horned, and dreadfully easy
to offend.

Strong beyond decency, the thick body absorbs crushing blows and
breaks summons -- you don't pluck a minotaur out from under its
guards just like that. Mental attacks, though, knock a minotaur
out for a long while: their intellect is tactical, not strategic.

In battle they bash, disarm, kick, fling dirt, parry, crush with
mass, rescue their kin, and often fall into {hh829berserk rage{x.
Surprisingly fast for their size.

The main seat is {hh1841Mahn-Tor{x, a labyrinthine fortress in
the southeast. Now and then minotaurs turn up in other dark
dungeons too.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Минотавры= -- получеловек-полубык с тяжёлым нравом и ещё
более тяжёлым кулаком. Высокие, мускулистые, рогатые, и страшно
обидчивые.

Сильны до неприличия, толстое тело гасит дробящие удары и срывает
призывы -- минотавра из-под охраны просто так не выдернешь. Зато
ментальные атаки минотавра выбивают надолго: интеллект у них
тактический, не стратегический.

В бою сбивают с ног, обезоруживают, лягают, бросаются грязью, парируют,
крушат массой, спасают сородичей, часто впадают в {hh829ярость{x.
Стремительны для своих размеров.

Главное обиталище -- {hh1841Мах'н-Тор{x, лабиринтная крепость на
юго-востоке. Изредка минотавры встречаются и в других тёмных
подземельях.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Мінотаври= -- напівлюдина-напівбик з важким норовом і ще
більш важким кулаком. Високі, мускулясті, рогаті, і страшенно
образливі.

Сильні до непристойності, товсте тіло гасить дробильні удари й
зриває призиви -- мінотавра з-під охорони просто так не висмикнеш.
Зате ментальні атаки мінотавра вибивають надовго: інтелект у них
тактичний, не стратегічний.

У бою збивають з ніг, обеззброюють, хвицають, кидаються багном,
парирують, трощать масою, рятують родичів, часто впадають у
{hh829лють{x. Стрімкі для своїх розмірів.

Головне обійстя -- {hh1841Махʼн-Тор{x, лабіринтна фортеця на
південному сході. Зрідка мінотаври трапляються і в інших темних
підземеллях.
</text>
  </help>
  <nameFemale>женщина минотавр</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>минотавр|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>мужчина минотавр</nameMale>
  <off>bash berserk disarm fast kick kick_dirt parry rescue crush</off>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands fingers ear eye two_hooves horns</parts>
  <res>summon bash</res>
  <size>large</size>
  <stats>
    <str>4</str>
    <int>-5</int>
    <wis>1</wis>
    <dex>-2</dex>
    <con>4</con>
    <cha>-3</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>mental</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">finger_l second_wield neck_2 neck_1 finger_r wrist_r wrist_l body light shield head legs hands arms about waist wield hold float tattoo face hooves</wearloc>
</Race>
