<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc aggressive warrior</act>
  <aff>infrared</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">infravision</affects>
  <form>poison sentient biped mammal</form>
  <help id="315" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">огр мужчина огр женщина огр огры</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">огр чоловік огр жінка огр огри</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Ogres= -- big, dumb, brutish. That's all you need to know
about them at first glance. At second glance -- that they're
strong as well.

Thick hide and a permanent layer of grime make an ogre nearly
immune to disease. They see by infravision. In battle they bash,
kick, parry with whatever's at hand, go berserk, and crush
anything smaller. They walk slowly, and that's their main
weakness -- a fast opponent simply outpaces them.

Bands of ogres live near {hh1873Mount Doom{x, in {hh2075The
Unholy Abbey{x, and similar foul places. Negotiating with one is
usually impossible: either run, or fight.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Огры= -- большие, тупые, грубые. Это всё, что нужно про них
знать в первом приближении. Во втором -- что они ещё и сильные.

Толстая шкура и постоянная грязь делают огра почти неподверженным
болезням. Видят в инфракрасном диапазоне. В бою сбивают с ног, лягают,
парируют чем попало, впадают в ярость и крушат всё, что мельче. Ходят
медленно, и в этом их главная слабость -- быстрого противника просто
не догнать.

Стаи огров водятся возле {hh1873Горы Смерти{x, в {hh2075Дьявольском
Монастыре{x и в подобных скверных местах. Договориться с ним обычно
невозможно: либо беги, либо бей.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Огри= -- великі, тупі, грубі. Це все, що потрібно про них
знати в першому наближенні. У другому -- що вони ще й сильні.

Товста шкура й постійний бруд роблять огра майже непідвладним
хворобам. Бачать у тепловому спектрі. У бою збивають з ніг,
хвицають, парирують чим попало, впадають у лють і трощать усе,
що менше. Ходять повільно, і в цьому їхня головна слабкість --
швидкого супротивника просто не наздогнати.

Зграї огрів водяться біля {hh1873Гори Смерті{x, у {hh2075Нечестивому
Абатстві{x і в подібних мерзенних місцях. Домовитися з ним зазвичай
неможливо: або біжи, або бий.
</text>
  </help>
  <nameFemale>женщина огр</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>огр|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>мужчина огр</nameMale>
  <off>bash berserk kick parry crush</off>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye</parts>
  <res>disease</res>
  <size>large</size>
  <stats>
    <str>5</str>
    <int>-6</int>
    <wis>-1</wis>
    <dex>-3</dex>
    <con>5</con>
    <cha>-4</cha>
  </stats>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">finger_l second_wield neck_2 neck_1 finger_r wrist_r wrist_l body light shield head legs feet hands arms about waist wield hold float tattoo face</wearloc>
</Race>
