<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultPCRace">
  <aff>infrared sneak pass_door</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">infravision sneak &apos;pass door&apos;</affects>
  <align>neutral</align>
  <classes>
    <thief>100</thief>
    <samurai>100</samurai>
    <warrior>100</warrior>
    <necromancer>-1</necromancer>
    <ranger>100</ranger>
    <cleric>100</cleric>
    <witch>100</witch>
    <druid>-1</druid>
    <anti-paladin>-1</anti-paladin>
    <ninja>100</ninja>
    <paladin>-1</paladin>
    <warlock>100</warlock>
    <vampire>-1</vampire>
  </classes>
  <form>edible sentient biped mammal</form>
  <help id="164" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en">rockseers</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">&apos;пещерные эльфы&apos; &apos;пещерный эльф&apos; роксир роксира роксиры</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">&apos;печерні ельфи&apos; &apos;печерний ельф&apos; роксір роксіра роксіри</keyword>
    <text l="en">Rockseers are a race of elves living underground in stone caves. Their hair and skin have long lost all pigment, turning pale or grey like the surrounding rock. Over centuries of dwelling among stone, the cave elves developed interesting traits -- they learned to {hh647seep{x through rock and closed doors, or conversely to {hh870merge with the stone{x, gaining {hh101protection{x from piercing and slashing strikes, though at the cost of greatly {hh705slowing down{x and losing agility.
 
Over long centuries of seclusion they forgot {hh2044Quenya{x, the tongue of the High Elves, and resolved to stay neutral in the elves' quarrels with Evil. In return they preserved resistance to {hh729charm{x and further sharpened {hh830infravision{x in the cave darkness. Rockseers despise tree roots that gnaw and crumble their beloved rocks, and they are vulnerable to anything made of wood -- except magical {hh121staves{x, which they wield to perfection.
</text>
    <text l="ru">Роксиры -- раса эльфов, живущих под землей в каменных пещерах. Их волосы и кожа давно потеряла пигментацию, став белесой или серой, как окружающие скалы. За века обитания среди скал пещерные эльфы развили интересные свойства -- они научились {hh647просачиваться{x сквозь камень и закрытые двери или, наоборот, {hh870сливаться с камнями{x, получая {hh101защиту{x от колющих и рассекающих ударов, но в то же время сильно {hh705замедляясь{x и теряя проворность.
 
За долгие века затворничества они забыли {hh2044квенью{x, язык Светлых эльфов и решили соблюдать нейтралитет в их разборках со Злом. Зато они сохранили сопротивляемость к {hh729очарованию{x и еще больше развили {hh830инфразрение{x в пещерной темноте. Роксирам ненавистны древесные корни, точащие и разрушающие их любимые скалы, и они уязвимы ко всему, что изготовлено из дерева. Кроме магических {hh121жезлов{x, которыми они владеют в совершенстве.
</text>
    <text l="ua">Роксири -- раса ельфів, що живуть під землею в камʼяних печерах. Їхнє волосся і шкіра давно втратили пігментацію, ставши білястою або сірою, як навколишні скелі. За століття проживання серед скель печерні ельфи розвинули цікаві властивості -- вони навчилися {hh647просочуватися{x крізь камінь і зачинені двері або, навпаки, {hh870зливатися зі скелями{x, отримуючи {hh101захист{x від колючих і рубаючих ударів, але водночас сильно {hh705сповільнюючись{x та втрачаючи спритність.
 
За довгі віки затворництва вони забули {hh2044квенью{x, мову Світлих ельфів, і вирішили дотримуватися нейтралітету в їхніх сутичках зі Злом. Натомість зберегли стійкість до {hh729зачарування{x і ще більше розвинули {hh830інфразір{x у печерній темряві. Роксирам ненависне коріння дерев, що точить і руйнує їхні улюблені скелі, і вони вразливі до всього, що виготовлено з дерева. Крім магічних {hh121жезлів{x, якими вони володіють досконало.
</text>
  </help>
  <hpBonus>20</hpBonus>
  <manaBonus>20</manaBonus>
  <maxAlign>150</maxAlign>
  <minAlign>-150</minAlign>
  <nameFemale>роксир|а|ы|е|у|ой|е</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>роксир||а|у|а|ом|е</nameMale>
  <nameMaleUa>роксір</nameMaleUa>
  <nameFemaleUa>роксіра</nameFemaleUa>
  <nameMltUa>роксіри</nameMltUa>
  <nameMlt>роксир|ы|ов|ам|ов|ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameWho>Rocks</nameWho>
  <nameWhoRus>Рокси</nameWhoRus>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye</parts>
  <points>250</points>
  <res>charm</res>
  <size>medium</size>
  <stats>
    <str>-2</str>
    <int>3</int>
    <wis>2</wis>
    <dex>1</dex>
  </stats>
  <vuln>wood</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float finger_l second_wield finger_r shield hands arms wield hold face tattoo tat_arms tat_face tat_wrist_l tat_wrist_r</wearloc>
</Race>
