<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultPCRace">
  <aff>regeneration</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">regeneration</affects>
  <align>evil</align>
  <classes>
    <thief>100</thief>
    <samurai>100</samurai>
    <warrior>100</warrior>
    <necromancer>100</necromancer>
    <ranger>100</ranger>
    <cleric>100</cleric>
    <witch>100</witch>
    <druid>-1</druid>
    <anti-paladin>100</anti-paladin>
    <ninja>100</ninja>
    <paladin>-1</paladin>
    <warlock>100</warlock>
    <vampire>-1</vampire>
  </classes>
  <form>edible poison sentient biped cold_blood</form>
  <help id="157" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <extra l="en"></extra>
    <extra l="ru">троль</extra>
    <extra l="ua">троль трольша тролі</extra>
    <keyword l="en">trolls</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">тролли троллиха тролль</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">тролі</keyword>
    <text l="en">Deep in mountain caves, hiding from outside eyes for centuries, troll society formed -- known only through fragments of fairy tales and myths. After their long seclusion the trolls decided to crawl out of their lairs and join the other races living in the cities.
 
Trolls are clumsy and not particularly sharp-witted, but they compensate with strength, tribal wisdom, and the resilience of mountain stone. These green-skinned, fanged creatures survive when other races can no longer manage: they {hh2130regenerate{x hit points faster than others and can even recover {hh541rotting{x wounds. Burning through their thick hide is best done with fire and acid. Trolls are cold-blooded, and their flesh is inedible even to predators.

A natural inclination toward Evil has developed in trolls {hh101resistance{x to dark magic, and the clubs with which trolls have beaten each other since their claws were young grant them resistance to heavy blows. Trolls make excellent shaman-priests and practically invulnerable warriors.
</text>
    <text l="ru">Глубоко в горных пещерах, веками скрываясь от чужих взглядов, сформировалось общество троллей, известное лишь по обрывкам сказок и мифов. После долгого затворничества тролли решили выползти из своих убежищ и присоединится к другим расам, живущим в городах.
 
Тролли неуклюжи и не особо сообразительны, но компенсируют это силой, племенной мудростью и стойкостью горных камней. Эти зеленокожие и клыкастые твари выживают тогда, когда для других рас это уже не представляется возможным: они быстрее других {hh2130регенерируют{x здоровье и способны восстанавливать даже {hh541гниющие{x раны. Прожечь их толстую шкуру лучше всего получается огнем и кислотой. Тролли -- холоднокровные, а их плоть несъедобна даже для хищников. 

Природная склонность ко Злу развила в троллях {hh101сопротивляемость{x к темной магии, а дубины, которыми тролли мутузят друг друга с младых когтей, даруют им сопротивляемость к тяжелым ударам. Из троллей получаются отличные шаманы-священники и практически неуязвимые воины.
</text>
    <text l="ua">Глибоко в гірських печерах, ховаючись від чужих поглядів упродовж століть, сформувалося суспільство тролів, відоме лише з уривків казок та міфів. Після довгого затворництва тролі вирішили виповзти зі своїх схованок і приєднатися до інших рас, що живуть у містах.
 
Тролі незграбні й не надто кмітливі, але компенсують це силою, племінною мудрістю та стійкістю гірських каменів. Ці зеленошкірі й іклаті створіння виживають тоді, коли для інших рас це вже неможливо: вони швидше за інших {hh2130регенерують{x здоровʼя і здатні відновлювати навіть {hh541гниючі{x рани. Прожерти їхню товсту шкіру найкраще вдається вогнем та кислотою. Тролі -- холоднокровні, а їхня плоть неїстівна навіть для хижаків.

Природна схильність до Зла розвинула в тролів {hh101стійкість{x до темної магії, а дубини, якими тролі мутузять одне одного з малих кігтів, дарують їм стійкість до важких ударів. З тролів виходять відмінні шамани-священники і практично невразливі воїни.
</text>
  </help>
  <hpBonus>20</hpBonus>
  <maxAlign>-300</maxAlign>
  <minAlign>-1000</minAlign>
  <nameFemale>троллих|а|и|е|у|ой|е</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>тролл|ь|я|ю|я|ем|е</nameMale>
  <nameMaleUa>троль</nameMaleUa>
  <nameFemaleUa>трольша</nameFemaleUa>
  <nameMltUa>тролі</nameMltUa>
  <nameMlt>тролл|и|ей|ям|ей|ями|ях</nameMlt>
  <nameWho>Troll</nameWho>
  <nameWhoRus>Трол</nameWhoRus>
  <off>berserk</off>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye claws fangs</parts>
  <points>250</points>
  <res>bash negative</res>
  <size>large</size>
  <stats>
    <str>3</str>
    <int>-2</int>
    <wis>3</wis>
    <dex>-4</dex>
    <con>5</con>
  </stats>
  <vuln>fire acid</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 wrist_r wrist_l body light head legs feet about waist float finger_l second_wield finger_r shield hands arms wield hold face tattoo tat_arms tat_face tat_wrist_l tat_wrist_r</wearloc>
</Race>
