<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc aggressive undead</act>
  <aff>infrared regeneration</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">regeneration infravision</affects>
  <det>evil good undead life</det>
  <form>poison undead</form>
  <help id="339" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">нежить мертвяк нежити</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">нежить мертв'як нежиті</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Undead= -- the general class of unquiet dead: skeletons,
zombies, vampires, liches, ghosts, and other violators of funeral
rites. The common thread is that they're no longer alive but
somehow still mobile.

Dead flesh fears no poison or disease, drowning won't take
either -- they're dead already. Dark energy fortifies them rather
than harms. Holy power, silver, and bright light, though, cut
undead like the living: for them it's a real weapon.

They see by infravision, sense good, evil, the living, and other
dead, wounds knit on the move. In battle they go berserk, parry,
dodge, and move fast.

The class is used mechanically -- for class abilities of paladins,
clerics, and other respected exterminators.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Нежить= -- общий класс не упокоенных мёртвых: скелеты, зомби,
вампиры, личи, призраки, и прочие нарушители правил похорон. Объединяет
их то, что они уже не живые, но почему-то всё ещё мобильные.

Мёртвой плоти не страшны яды и болезни, утонуть тоже не получится --
и так уж мёртвые. Тёмная энергия их укрепляет, а не вредит. Зато
святая сила, серебро и яркий свет режут нежить как живое: для них
это настоящее оружие.

Видят в инфракрасном диапазоне, чуют добро, зло, живое и других
мёртвых, раны зарастают на ходу. В бою впадают в ярость, парируют,
уклоняются и стремительны.

Класс используется механически -- для классовых способностей паладинов,
жрецов, и других уважаемых истребителей.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Нежить= -- загальний клас не упокоєних мертвих: скелети,
зомбі, вампіри, лічі, привиди, та інші порушники правил похорону.
Обʼєднує їх те, що вони вже не живі, але чомусь усе ще рухливі.

Мертвій плоті не страшні отрути й хвороби, потонути теж не
вийде -- і так уже мертві. Темна енергія їх укріплює, а не шкодить.
Зате свята сила, срібло і яскраве світло ріжуть нежить як живе:
для них це справжня зброя.

Бачать у тепловому спектрі, чують добро, зло, живе та інших
мертвих, рани заростають на ходу. У бою впадають у лють, парирують,
ухиляються і стрімкі.

Клас використовується механічно -- для класових здібностей
паладинів, жерців, та інших шанованих винищувачів.
</text>
  </help>
  <imm>poison disease drowning</imm>
  <nameFemale>нежить</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>нежит|ь|и|и|ь|ью|и</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>нежить</nameMale>
  <nameNeuter>нежить</nameNeuter>
  <off>berserk dodge fast parry</off>
  <parts>head arms legs guts hands feet fingers ear eye claws</parts>
  <res>negative</res>
  <size>medium</size>
  <stats>
    <str>3</str>
    <int>-3</int>
    <wis>-3</wis>
    <dex>-2</dex>
    <cha>-5</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>holy light silver</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">finger_l second_wield neck_2 neck_1 finger_r wrist_r wrist_l body light shield head legs feet hands arms about waist wield hold float face</wearloc>
</Race>
