<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc</act>
  <aff>regeneration slow</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">regeneration slow</affects>
  <form>worm</form>
  <help id="311" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">червь черви</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">черв'як черв'яки</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Worms= -- legless, eyeless, and usually underground. From
earthworms to huge cavern kind, capable of swallowing a horse
without wincing.

Underground, neither mental attack, nor bright light, nor loud
sound is anything to a worm -- there are simply no sensors for
them. Drowning isn't an option either: it's indifferent to water.
Fire, though, dries it out in a minute, and acid eats through
the boneless body faster than it can regenerate. In battle it
strikes with body-and-tail, but moves slowly.

Large worms live in {hh1854UnderDark{x, in {hh1841Mahn-Tor{x,
and in the surrounding underground tunnels. Best not encountered
without a tested rope and several companions.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Черви= -- безногие, безглазые, и обычно подземные. От
дождевых до огромных пещерных, способных проглотить лошадь и не
поморщиться.

Под землёй ни ментальная атака, ни яркий свет, ни громкий звук червю
не страшны -- сенсоров для них попросту нет. Утонуть тоже не
получится: к воде равнодушен. Зато огонь высушивает за минуту, а
кислота разъедает бескостное тело быстрее, чем оно успевает
регенерировать. В бою бьёт телом-хвостом, но двигается медленно.

Большие черви водятся в {hh1854Подземье{x, в {hh1841Мах'н-Торе{x и в
окрестных подземных туннелях. С ним лучше не сталкиваться без
проверенной верёвки и нескольких товарищей.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Черви= -- безногі, безокі, і зазвичай підземні. Від дощових
до величезних печерних, здатних проковтнути коня і не скривитися.

Під землею ні ментальна атака, ні яскраве світло, ні гучний звук
червʼякові не страшні -- сенсорів для них просто немає. Втонути
теж не вийде: до води байдужий. Зате вогонь висушує за хвилину,
а кислота розʼїдає безкісткове тіло швидше, ніж воно встигає
регенерувати. У бою бʼє тілом-хвостом, але рухається повільно.

Великі черви водяться в {hh1854Підземʼї{x, в {hh1841Махʼн-Торі{x
і в околишніх підземних тунелях. З ним краще не стикатися без
перевіреної мотузки і кількох товаришів.
</text>
  </help>
  <imm>mental light sound</imm>
  <nameFemale>самк|а|и|е|у|ой|е червя</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>черв|ь|я|ю|я|ём|е</nameMale>
  <nameMlt>черв|и|ей|ям|ей|ями|ях</nameMlt>
  <nameNeuter>черв|ь|я|ю|я|ём|е</nameNeuter>
  <off>tail</off>
  <parts>head tail scales</parts>
  <res>drowning</res>
  <size>tiny</size>
  <stats>
    <int>-3</int>
    <dex>-2</dex>
    <con>5</con>
    <cha>-7</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>fire acid</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">body light about waist float</wearloc>
</Race>
