<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc</act>
  <aff>flying</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">fly</affects>
  <det>invis hidden</det>
  <form>poison animal reptile dragon</form>
  <help id="303" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">виверн виверна виверны</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">віверн віверна віверни</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Wyverns= -- two-legged two-winged reptiles with a venomous
tail, distant kin of dragons and meaner of temperament. Large,
toothy, and unwelcoming.

Their own and foreign poison does no harm to a wyvern -- they
drip it from their sting themselves. Bright light, though, blinds
their sensitive eyes in an instant: during a daylight raid a
wyvern rapidly loses bearings. They see through invisibility
and concealment, fly through the air and are fast. In battle
they dodge and strike with the venomous tail.

The main hunting ground is {hh1835Wyvern Tower{x in the southeast.
Now and then they also turn up in {hh1441Midennir{x. Don't tangle
with this fellow without a good group.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Виверны= -- двуногие двукрылые рептилии с ядовитым хвостом,
дальние родственники драконов и более скверные характером. Большие,
зубастые, и неприветливые.

Собственный и чужой яд виверну не вредит -- сами капают им с жала.
Зато яркий свет чувствительные глаза слепит мгновенно: при дневном
налёте виверна стремительно теряет ориентацию. Видят сквозь
невидимость и сокрытие, в воздухе летают и быстры. В бою уклоняются
и бьют ядовитым хвостом.

Главное место охоты -- {hh1835Вивернова Башня{x на юго-востоке. Также
изредка попадаются в {hh1441Миденнире{x. С таким парнем без хорошей
группы лучше не связываться.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Віверни= -- двоногі двокрилі рептилії з отруйним хвостом,
дальні родичі драконів і гіршого характеру. Великі, зубаті, і
непривітні.

Власна й чужа отрута віверні не шкодить -- самі капають нею з
жала. Зате яскраве світло чутливі очі сліпить вмить: під час
денного нальоту віверна стрімко втрачає орієнтацію. Бачать крізь
невидимість і приховання, в повітрі літають і швидкі. У бою
ухиляються і бʼють отруйним хвостом.

Головне місце полювання -- {hh1835Вивернова Башта{x на південному
сході. Також зрідка трапляються в {hh1441Міденнірі{x. З таким
хлопцем без гарної групи краще не звʼязуватися.
</text>
  </help>
  <imm>poison</imm>
  <nameFemale>виверна</nameFemale>
  <nameMlt>виверн|ы||ам||ами|ах</nameMlt>
  <nameMale>виверн</nameMale>
  <off>dodge fast tail</off>
  <parts>head legs heart brains guts feet ear eye wings tail claws fangs scales</parts>
  <size>large</size>
  <stats>
    <str>3</str>
    <int>-2</int>
    <wis>1</wis>
    <dex>2</dex>
    <con>2</con>
  </stats>
  <vuln>light</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">neck_2 neck_1 light head legs about waist float tail</wearloc>
</Race>
