<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Race type="DefaultRace">
  <act>npc aggressive</act>
  <aff>slow</aff>
  <affects registry="skill">slow</affects>
  <det>life</det>
  <form>poison undead biped</form>
  <help id="322" level="-1" type="RaceHelp">
    <keyword l="en"></keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">зомби</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">зомбі</keyword>
    <text l="en">=Zombies= -- walking corpses under a grim necromancer's command or a curse. They shamble slowly, stink strongly, and in numbers can wear down even a seasoned hero.

A dead body is not subject to poison, disease, or drowning -- what's already rotting inside, you can't kill again. Charm doesn't work either, dark energy only feeds a zombie, cold and piercing weapons pass right through the decaying flesh. Fire, holy power, bright light, and silver, though, are an execution for a zombie: the body flares up or crumbles.

They sense the living from afar. In battle they parry with whatever's at hand and crush by mass, but move slowly -- that's their main weakness.

Main spawn points are {hh1446Old Midgaard{x, graveyards, and other places where a necro wanted some practice. Zombies in {hh2050Firetop Mountain{x are especially nasty, with baked-on bones.
</text>
    <text l="ru">=Зомби= -- ходячие трупы под мрачной командой некроманта или порчей. Шевелятся медленно, воняют сильно, и численностью способны вынести даже опытного героя.

Мертвое тело не подвластно ядам, болезням и утоплению -- что внутри гниет, того уже не убить. Очарование на них тоже не действует, темная энергия зомби только подкармливает, холод и колющее оружие проходят мимо разлагающейся плоти. Зато огонь, святая сила, яркий свет и серебро для зомби -- казнь: тело вспыхивает или рассыпается.

Чуют живое издалека. В бою парируют чем попало и крушат массой, но двигаются медленно -- это их главная слабость.

Основные точки появления -- {hh1446Старый Мидгаард{x, кладбища и прочие места, где некрос захотел практики. Зомби в {hh2050Огненной Горе{x -- особенно неприятные, с пропеченными костями.
</text>
    <text l="ua">=Зомбі= -- ходячі трупи під похмурою командою некроманта або порчею. Шевеляться повільно, смердять сильно, і кількістю здатні винести навіть досвідченого героя.

Мертве тіло не підвладне отрутам, хворобам і утопленню -- що всередині гниє, того вже не вбити. Очарування на них теж не діє, темна енергія зомбі тільки підгодовує, холод і колюча зброя проходять повз розкладану плоть. Зате вогонь, свята сила, яскраве світло і срібло для зомбі -- кара: тіло спалахує або розсипається.

Чують живе здалеку. У бою парирують чим попало і трощать масою, але рухаються повільно -- це їхня головна слабкість.

Основні точки появи -- {hh1446Старий Мідгаард{x, цвинтарі та інші місця, де некрос захотів практики. Зомбі в {hh2050Вогняній Горі{x -- особливо неприємні, з пропеченими кістками.
</text>
  </help>
  <imm>poison disease drowning</imm>
  <nameFemale>зомби</nameFemale>
  <nameMale>зомби</nameMale>
  <nameMaleUa>зомбі</nameMaleUa>
  <nameFemaleUa>зомбі</nameFemaleUa>
  <nameMltUa>зомбі</nameMltUa>
  <nameMlt>зомби</nameMlt>
  <nameNeuter>зомби</nameNeuter>
  <off>parry crush</off>
  <parts>head arms legs heart brains guts hands feet fingers ear eye</parts>
  <res>charm pierce cold negative</res>
  <size>medium</size>
  <stats>
    <str>4</str>
    <int>-6</int>
    <wis>-6</wis>
    <dex>-6</dex>
    <con>5</con>
    <cha>-8</cha>
  </stats>
  <vuln>fire holy light silver</vuln>
  <wearloc registry="wearlocation">finger_l second_wield neck_2 neck_1 finger_r wrist_r wrist_l body light shield head legs feet hands arms about waist wield hold float tattoo face</wearloc>
</Race>
