<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <affect type="DefaultAffectHandler">
    <removeObj>%1$^O1 теряет свое освящение.</removeObj>
  </affect>
  <beats>24</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="paladin">
      <level>55</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <dammsg mg="m"></dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">enchantment</group>
  <help id="806" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <keyword l="en">'bless weapon' blessed</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">&apos;освятить оружие&apos; освященное</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">'освятити зброю' освячене</keyword>
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%OBJ%_

With this prayer, paladins turn their weapons into a truly powerful
tool in the battle against evil, endowing it with =blessed= properties and increasing
accuracy. In {hh33good{x hands, blessed weapons deal more damage to evil opponents.
Moreover, only good characters can wield it.

This prayer cannot be cast on weapons with {hh96flags{x vampiric, dark, or
diabolic. The diabolic essence can be eradicated with a simple
{hh766blessing{x, but nothing can be done about vampirism and darkness. Some weapons
in the world already possess sacred properties and do not require this prayer.
The properties ({hh96flags{x) of a weapon can be seen during {hh1001identification{x.
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%OBJ%_

С помощью этой молитвы паладины превращают свое оружие в поистине мощный
инструмент в сражении со злом, наделяя его свойствами =освященного= и увеличивая
точность. В {hh33добрых{x руках освященное оружие наносит больше урона злым противникам.
Вдобавок, его смогут взять в руки только добрые персонажи.

Эту молитву нельзя наложить на оружие с {hh96флагами{x вампирическое, темное или
дьявольское. Дьявольскую сущность можно искоренить с помощью обычного
{hh766благословения{x, а вот с вампиризмом и темнотой поделать нечего. Некоторые оружия
в мире уже имеют священные свойства и не нуждаются в этой молитве.
Увидеть свойства ({hh96флаги{x) оружия можно при {hh1001идентификации{x.
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%OBJ%_

З допомогою цієї молитви паладини перетворюють свою зброю в по-справжньому потужний
інструмент у битві зі злом, наділяючи його властивостями =освяченого= і збільшуючи
точність. В {hh33добрих{x руках освячена зброя завдає більше шкоди злим противникам.
Більше того, її зможуть взяти в руки тільки добрі персонажі.

Цю молитву не можна накласти на зброю з {hh96флагами{x вампіричне, темне або
диявольське. Дияволічну сутність можна викоренити за допомогою звичайного
{hh766благословіння{x, а от з вампіризмом і темрявою нічого не можна вдіяти. Деяка зброя
у світі вже має священні властивості і не потребує цієї молитви.
Побачити властивості ({hh96флаги{x) зброї можна при {hh1001ідентифікації{x.
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>100</mana>
  <name l="en">bless weapon</name>
  <name l="ru">освятить оружие</name>
  <name l="ua">освятити зброю</name>
  <spell type="DefaultSpell">
    <damtype>none</damtype>
    <flags>prayer</flags>
    <position>stand</position>
    <target>obj_inv obj_equip</target>
    <type>none</type>
  </spell>
</skill>