<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <beats>12</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="ranger">
      <level>10</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="samurai">
      <level>20</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="warrior">
      <level>44</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <command type="SKILL(shoot)">
    <argtype>undef</argtype>
    <cat>fight</cat>
    <hint l="en">(rangers) shoot a bow</hint>
    <hint l="ru">(рейнджеры) выстрелить из лука</hint>
    <hint l="ua">(рейнджери) вистрілити з лука</hint>
    <name l="en">shoot</name>
    <name l="ru">стрелять</name>
    <name l="ua">стріляти</name>
    <order>player_only</order>
    <position>stand</position>
  </command>
  <dammsg mg="m">лук</dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">weaponsmaster</group>
  <hard>5</hard>
  <help id="810" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <extra l="en">crossbows quiver ranged</extra>
    <extra l="ru">арбалеты колчан пистолеты стрельба выстрелить залпы</extra>
    <extra l="ua">арбалети колчан пістолети стрільба вистрілити залпи</extra>
    <text l="en">To shoot at enemies at a distance, arm yourself with any bow or crossbow
(when {hh1001identified{x, the weapon type must be indicated as &quot;bow&quot;) and hold a quiver in hand
with arrows. The quiver holds 50 arrows, they can be crafted or bought from
a gunsmith in {hh1392Midgaard{x.

%FMT%  *%CMD%* _%DIR%_ _%CHAR%_

Sends an arrow at an enemy nearby -- the arrow can fly
across several squares in the chosen direction. The enemy hit at a distance,
of course, will get angry and run in your direction. The arrow may miss,
nimble foes might dodge it, but in most cases, it will remain on
the ground in the square where it hit the opponent. In a particularly lucky hit, the arrow
may remain stuck in the enemy's wound, reducing their agility and causing {hh541decay{x.

There are other ways to hit foes at a distance:
%A% {hh1361cast{x spells at a distance
%A% {hh699throw a spear{x

%SA% %H% {hh850make a bow{x, {hh537make arrows{x.</text>
    <text l="ru">Чтобы стрелять в противников на расстоянии, вооружись любым луком или арбалетом
(при {hh1001опознании{x должен быть указан тип оружия &quot;лук&quot;) и возьми в руки =колчан= со
стрелами. В колчан помещается 50 стрел, их можно изготовить или купить у
оружейника в {hh1392Мидгаарде{x.

%FMT%  *%CMD%* _%DIR%_ _%CHAR%_

Посылает стрелу в противника, находящегося неподалеку -- стрела может пролететь
несколько клеток в выбранном направлении. Пораженный на расстоянии противник,
разумеется, разозлится и побежит в твоем направлении. Стрела может промахнуться,
особые ловкачи могут от нее увернуться, но в большинстве случае она останется на
земле в той клетке, где поразила противника. При особо удачном попадании стрела
может остаться торчать в ране противника, снижая его ловкость и вызывая {hh541гниение{x.

Есть и другие способы поражать противников на расстоянии:
%A% {hh1361колдовать{x заклинания на расстоянии
%A% {hh699метнуть копье{x

%SA% %H% {hh850изготовить лук{x, {hh537изготовить стрелы{x.
</text>
    <text l="ua">Щоб стріляти в противників на відстані, озбройся будь-яким луком або арбалетом
(при {hh1001розпізнаванні{x повинен бути вказаний тип зброї "лук") і візьми в руку =колчан= зі
стрілами. У колчан вміщується 50 стріл, їх можна виготовити або купити у
збройовика в {hh1392Мідгаарті{x.

%FMT%  *%CMD%* _%DIR%_ _%CHAR%_

Посилає стрілу у противника, що знаходиться неподалеку -- стріла може пролетіти
кілька клітин у вибраному напрямку. Уражений на відстані противник,
звісно, розлютиться і побіжить у твоєму напрямку. Стріла може промахнутися,
особливі спритники можуть уникнути її, але в більшості випадків вона залишиться на
землі в тій клітині, де вразила противника. При особливо вдалому влученні стріла
може залишитися стирчати у рані противника, знижуючи його спритність і викликаючи {hh541гниття{x.

Є й інші способи вражати противників на відстані:
%A% {hh1361чаклувати{x заклинання на відстані
%A% {hh699кинути спис{x

%SA% %H% {hh850виготовити лук{x, {hh537виготовити стріли{x.
</text>
  </help>
  <mob>
    <bonus>100</bonus>
    <professional>true</professional>
  </mob>
  <move>20</move>
  <name l="en">bow</name>
  <name l="ru">лук</name>
  <name l="ua">лук</name>
  <raceBonuses registry="race">centaur elf</raceBonuses>
</skill>