<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <beats>12</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="anti-paladin">
      <level>10</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="warlock">
      <level>10</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="witch">
      <level>10</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <dammsg mg="p">горящие руки</dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">combat</group>
  <help id="839" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <extra l="en">burning palm hand flaming hands</extra>
    <extra l="ru">длани длань пылающая пылающий рука руки</extra>
    <extra l="ua">долоні долоню палаюча палаючий рука руки</extra>
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%VICT%_

A magic spell that deals damage to the victim nearby with fire depending on the level
of the spell. If the victim makes a {hh2035saving throw{x, the damage is reduced by half.

There is also a small chance to heat items in the victim&apos;s equipment to extremely high
temperatures, dealing damage for each heated item, and forcing the victim to
remove the heated items or even drop them on the ground.

A similar effect (but much stronger) is possessed by the prayer of {hh682heating{x.

%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%OBJ%_

If you throw a combustible item on the ground and use the spell on it, you can
quickly start a small {hh249fire{x.
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%VICT%_

Магическое заклинание, наносящее урон жертве вблизи огнем в зависимости от уровня
заклинания. Если у жертвы срабатывает {hh2035спасбросок{x, урон уменьшается вдвое.

Также есть небольшой шанс раскалить предметы в экипировке жертвы до сверхвысоких
температур, нанося повреждения за каждую раскаленную вещь, и заставляя жертву
снять раскаленные вещи или даже сбросить на землю.

Подобным эффектом (но гораздо сильнее) обладает молитва {hh682раскаления{x.

%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%OBJ%_

Если бросить горючий предмет на землю и использовать заклинание на него, можно
быстро развести небольшой {hh249костер{x.
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%VICT%_

Магічне заклинання, що завдає шкоди жертві поблизу вогнем залежно від рівня
заклинання. Якщо у жертви спрацьовує {hh2035рятувальний кидок{x, урон зменшується вдвічі.

Також є невеликий шанс розпечити предмети в екіпіровці жертви до надвисоких
температур, завдаючи пошкоджень за кожен розпечений предмет, і змушуючи жертву
зняти розпечені речі або навіть скинути їх на землю.

Подібним ефектом (але набагато сильнішим) володіє молитва {hh682нагріву{x.

%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%OBJ%_

Якщо кинути горючий предмет на землю і використати заклинання на нього, можна
швидко розвести невелике {hh249багаття{x.
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>40</mana>
  <mob>
    <professional>true</professional>
  </mob>
  <name l="en">burning hands</name>
  <name l="ru">горящие руки</name>
  <name l="ua">палаючі руки</name>
  <spell type="DefaultSpell">
    <damtype>fire</damtype>
    <flags>magic</flags>
    <position>fight</position>
    <ranged>false</ranged>
    <target>char_room obj_room</target>
    <tier>4</tier>
    <type>offensive</type>
  </spell>
</skill>
