<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <beats>12</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="cleric">
      <level>32</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="druid">
      <level>36</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="necromancer">
      <level>28</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="warlock">
      <level>28</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="witch">
      <level>24</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <dammsg mg="m"></dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">arcane</group>
  <help id="821" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <extra l="en">nocancel</extra>
    <extra l="ru">неотменять отменить</extra>
    <extra l="ua">не скасовувати скасувати</extra>
    <text l="en">A spell or prayer of cancellation removes the spell effects from the target.
You can cancel spells on yourself, an ally, or any player who doesn't have {y{hcsettings nocancel{x enabled.

Unlike {hh808dispel magic{x, cancellation is much more effective and is not considered
an aggressive action. The chance of successful magic and prayer dispelling depends on your own
{hh2036spell level{x and the level of the spell you are cancelling.
The longer a spell effect lasts on the target, the easier it is to cancel. Fresh buffs
are harder to remove. And permanent spells, such as {hh656sanctuary protection{x on a mob, are
the hardest to remove.

Cancellation and dispel spells do not distinguish between "good" and "bad" effects on
the target and cancel almost everything. However, not all effects can be cancelled
or dispelled: for example, {hh837poison{x or {hh614plague{x.
</text>
    <text l="ru">Заклинание или молитва отмены снимает эффекты заклинаний с цели.
Можно отменить заклинания на себе, союзнике или любом игроке, у которого не
включено {y{hcнастройки неотменять{x.

В отличие от {hh808развеивания чар{x, отмена гораздо эффективнее и не считается
атакующим действием. Шанс удачного рассеивания магии и молитв зависит от твоего
собственного {hh2036уровня заклинаний{x и уровня заклинания, которое ты отменяешь. 
Чем дольше эффект заклинания висит на цели, тем легче его отменить. Свежие баффы
снять сложнее. А постоянные заклинания, например {hh656защиту святилища{x у моба, снять
сложнее всего.

Заклинания отмены и развеивания не различают &quot;хороших&quot; и &quot;плохих&quot; эффектов на
цели и отменяют практически все подряд. Но не все эффекты могут быть отменены
или рассеяны: например, {hh837яд{x или {hh614чума{x. 
</text>
    <text l="ua">Закляття або молитва скасування знімає ефекти заклинань з цілі.
Можна скасувати заклинання на собі, союзнику або будь-якому гравцеві, у якого не
включено {y{hcналаштування не скасовувати{x.

На відміну від {hh808розсіювання чар{x, скасування набагато ефективніше і не вважається
атакуючою дією. Шанс успішного розсіювання магії і молитов залежить від твого
власного {hh2036рівня заклинань{x і рівня заклинання, яке ти скасовуєш.
Чим довше ефект заклинання висить на цілі, тим легше його скасувати. Свіжі бафи
зняти складніше. А постійні заклинання, наприклад {hh656захист святилища{x у моба, зняти
найскладніше.

Заклинання скасування і розсіювання не розрізняють "хороших" і "поганих" ефектів на
цілі і скасовують практично все підряд. Але не всі ефекти можуть бути скасовані
або розсіяні: наприклад, {hh837отрута{x або {hh614чума{x.
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>40</mana>
  <name l="en">cancellation</name>
  <name l="ru">отмена</name>
  <name l="ua">скасування</name>
  <spell type="DefaultSpell">
    <damtype>none</damtype>
    <flags>magic prayer</flags>
    <position>fight</position>
    <target>char_room</target>
    <type>defensive</type>
  </spell>
</skill>