<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <affect type="DefaultAffectHandler">
    <cancelled>true</cancelled>
    <removeCharSelf>Колючие ветви, сковавшие твои движения, наконец ослабляют свою хватку.</removeCharSelf>
  </affect>
  <beats>12</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="druid">
      <level>17</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="ranger">
      <level>26</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <dammsg mg="p">побеги терновника</dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">nature</group>
  <help id="835" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <text l="en">This spell allows you to surround the opponent with thorny thickets, preventing them from leaving the area, taking {hh60movement points{x and dealing damage. The successfully ensnared victim experiences a thorn reminiscent of the {hh852web{x spell -- the victim can break free after several attempts to move in some direction.

{hh153Cloud giants{x and other insubstantial or semi-substantial creatures can free themselves from the thickets more quickly.

This spell can only be used in certain {hh86types of terrain{x: forest, field, hills, or mountains. In city streets, unfortunately, thickets do not grow -- but, according to rumors, they can sometimes be found in city parks.

Wraps the {hh652grave{x in thickets, disturbing those who lie in it and forcing them to get out.</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT%  *%CAST%* *%SKILL%* _%CHAR%_

Это заклинание позволяет окружить противника колючим терновником, не давая
покинуть данную местность, отнимая {hh60очки движения{x и нанося повреждения. Успешно
сковавший жертву терновник по действию напоминает заклинание {hh852паутины{x -- жертва
может разорвать путы после нескольких попыток пройти в каком-то из направлений.

{hh153Облачные гиганты{x и другие нематериальные или полуматериальные существа могут
выпутаться из терновника быстрее.

Данное заклинание может использоваться только в определенных {hh86типах местности{x:
в лесу, поле, холмах или в горах. На улицах городов терновник, к сожалению, не
растет -- но, по слухам, иногда встречается в городских парках. 

%FMT%  *%CAST%* *%SKILL%* _%OBJ%_

Опутывает терновником {hh652могилу{x, тревожа тех, кто в ней лежит и заставляя их
выбраться наружу.
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT%  *%CAST%* *%SKILL%* _%CHAR%_

Це заклинання дозволяє оточити противника колючими тернами, не даючи
залишити цю місцевість, віднімаючи {hh60очки руху{x та наносячи пошкодження. Успішно
зв'язавший жертву терни нагадують за дією заклинання {hh852павутини{x -- жертва
може розірвати пута після кількох спроб пройти в якомусь з напрямків.

{hh153Хмарні гіганти{x та інші нематеріальні або напівматеріальні істоти можуть
вибратися з тернів швидше.

Це заклинання може використовуватися тільки в певних {hh86типах місцевості{x:
у лісі, на полі, на пагорбах або в горах. На вулицях міст, на жаль, терни не
ростуть -- але, за чутками, іноді зустрічаються в міських парках. 

%FMT%  *%CAST%* *%SKILL%* _%OBJ%_

Оплутує терном {hh652могилу{x, турбуючи тих, хто в ній лежить, і змушуючи їх
вибратися назовні.
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>40</mana>
  <mob>
    <professional>true</professional>
  </mob>
  <name l="en">entangle</name>
  <name l="ru">опутать терновником</name>
  <name l="ua">оплутати терном</name>
  <spell type="DefaultSpell">
    <damtype>pierce</damtype>
    <flags>magic</flags>
    <position>fight</position>
    <ranged>false</ranged>
    <target>char_room obj_room</target>
    <tier>4</tier>
    <type>offensive</type>
  </spell>
</skill>