<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <affect type="DefaultAffectHandler">
    <removeRoom>Прекрасная яблоневая роща вокруг тебя стремительно увядает и рассыпается в прах.</removeRoom>
  </affect>
  <align>neutral</align>
  <beats>32</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="druid">
      <level>35</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <dammsg mg="m"></dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">nature</group>
  <help id="190" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <extra l="en"></extra>
    <extra l="ru">яблоня яблоневая</extra>
    <extra l="ua"></extra>
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%SPELL%*

Creating an apple grove is one of the most fundamental skills of the druid class. The grove provides druids with food, water, shelter, and protection in peaceful times and a threat to enemies in battle. Of course, a grove can only be grown in nature, so it is unlikely to succeed in a city.

As with many other things, the strength of the grove depends on the druid&apos;s rank within their circle. And, notably, obtaining new ranks also seems to be somehow linked with this skill. There are legends that higher-ranking druids can somehow move between groves they have grown, but that surely sounds like an old wives&apos; tale!</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%SPELL%*

Создание яблоневой рощи -- одно из наиболее фундаментальных умений сословия
друидов. Роща наделяет друида пищей, водой, предоставляет друиду кров и защиту в
мирное время и угрозу противникам в бою. Разумеется, вырастить рощу можно только
на лоне природы -- в городе это вряд ли удастся.

Как и многое другое, сила рощи зависит от ранга друида в своем круге. И, что
характерно, получение новых рангов тоже кажется каким-то образом связано с этим
умением. Ходят легенды, что друиды высших рангов каким-то образом умеют
перемещаться между выращенными ими рощами, но это, право же, звучит как
бабушкины сказки!
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%SPELL%*

Створення яблуневого гаю -- одне з найбільш фундаментальних умінь стану
друїдів. Гай наділяє друїда їжею, водою, надає друїду кров і захист у
мирний час та загрозу противникам у бою. Звісно, виростити гай можна лише
на лоні природи -- у місті це навряд чи вдасться.

Як і багато іншого, сила гаю залежить від рангу друїда у своєму колі. І, що
характерно, отримання нових рангів теж, здається, якимось чином пов&apos;язане з цим
умінням. Існують легенди, що друїди вищих рангів якимось чином уміють
переміщуватися між вирощеними ними гаями, але це, справді, звучить як
бабусині казки!</text>
  </help>
  <mana>400</mana>
  <name l="en">grove</name>
  <name l="ru">роща</name>
  <name l="ua">гай</name>
  <spell type="DefaultSpell">
    <damtype>none</damtype>
    <flags>prayer</flags>
    <position>stand</position>
    <target>room</target>
    <type>defensive</type>
  </spell>
</skill>
