<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <beats>18</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="cleric">
      <level>26</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <dammsg mg="n">накаливание</dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">enchantment</group>
  <help id="682" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <extra l="en"></extra>
    <extra l="ru">накалить раскалить раскаливание &apos;жидкий металл&apos;</extra>
    <extra l="ua">розжарювати розпечити розжарювання &apos;рідкий метал&apos;</extra>
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%VICT%_

This powerful prayer allows you to heat items in the target's inventory and equipment to extremely high temperatures, causing high damage for each heated item and forcing the victim to strip off the heated items or even drop them on the ground. The prayer will affect items made of {hh1001metal or mineral{x, which are not protected by {hh867fireproof{x or {hh633high-temperature protection{x auras.

It is more difficult to heat stone and heavy items, but they retain heat longer and cause more severe burns to the victim. The ability to timely remove or drop the items depends on the agility and endurance of the victim. The spell will be less effective {hh1028in rain{x. Only a certain number of items can be heated at one time, depending on the level.

Heated items will continue to cause damage to the victim for some time afterward. They can be cooled faster by throwing them into water in {hh2128appropriate areas{x.

A similar effect (but much weaker) is also possessed by the {hh839burning hands{x spell.

%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%OBJ%_

An individual item can be heated separately -- of course, it must first be placed on the ground.
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%VICT%_

Эта мощная молитва позволяет раскалить предметы в инвентаре и экипировке жертвы
до сверхвысоких температур, нанося высокие повреждения за каждую раскаленную
вещь, и заставляя жертву снять раскаленные вещи или даже сбросить на землю.
Молитва подействует на вещи, сделанные из {hh1001металла или минерала{x, которые
не защищены аурами {hh867огнеупорности{x или {hh633защиты от высоких температур{x.

Каменные и тяжелые вещи сложнее раскалить, зато они дольше держат тепло и
нанесут более сильный ожог жертве. Шанс вовремя снять или сбросить вещи зависит
от ловкости и выносливости жертвы. Под {hh1028дождем{x заклинание сработает хуже.
За раз можно раскалить только определенное количество вещей, зависит от уровня.

Раскаленные вещи продолжат наносить урон жертве еще какое-то время спустя.
Остудить их быстрее можно бросив их в воду в {hh2128соответствующих местностях{x.

Подобным эффектом (но гораздо слабее) также обладает заклинание {hh839горящих рук{x.

%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%OBJ%_

Можно раскалить отдельно взятую вещь -- разумеется, сначала ее надо будет
положить на землю.
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%VICT%_

Ця потужна молитва дозволяє розжарити предмети в інвентарі та екіпіруванні жертви до надвисоких температур, завдаючи високі пошкодження за кожну розжарену річ, і змушуючи жертву зняти розжарені речі або навіть скинути їх на землю. Молитва подіє на речі, зроблені з {hh1001металу або мінералу{x, які не захищені аурами {hh867вогнестійкості{x або {hh633захисту від високих температур{x.

Кам'яні та важкі речі складніше розжарити, зате вони довше тримають тепло і завдадуть сильнішого опіку жертві. Шанс вчасно зняти або скинути речі залежить від спритності та витривалості жертви. Під {hh1028дощем{x заклинання спрацює гірше. За раз можна розжарити тільки певну кількість речей, залежить від рівня.

Розжарені речі продовжать наносити шкоду жертві ще деякий час потому.
Остудити їх швидше можна, кинувши їх у воду в {hh2128відповідних місцевостях{x.

Подібним ефектом (але набагато слабшим) також володіє заклинання {hh839палаючих рук{x.

%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%OBJ%_

Можна розжарити окремо взяту річ -- звичайно, спершу її треба буде покласти на землю.
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>40</mana>
  <mob>
    <professional>true</professional>
  </mob>
  <name l="en">heating</name>
  <name l="ru">раскалить</name>
  <name l="ua">розжарити</name>
  <spell type="DefaultSpell">
    <damtype>fire</damtype>
    <flags>prayer</flags>
    <position>fight</position>
    <ranged>false</ranged>
    <target>char_room obj_room</target>
    <tier>5</tier>
    <type>offensive</type>
  </spell>
</skill>