<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <beats>12</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="anti-paladin">
      <level>9</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="cleric">
      <level>12</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="druid">
      <level>11</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="necromancer">
      <level>13</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="ninja">
      <level>1</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="paladin">
      <level>12</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="ranger">
      <level>8</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="samurai">
      <level>2</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="thief">
      <level>5</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="vampire">
      <level>4</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="warlock">
      <level>13</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="warrior">
      <level>5</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="witch">
      <level>13</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <command type="DefaultSkillCommand">
    <aliases l="en">kick</aliases>
    <aliases l="ru">пнуть</aliases>
    <aliases l="ua">вдарити</aliases>
    <argtype>string</argtype>
    <cat>class</cat>
    <hint l="en">kick a character or item</hint>
    <hint l="ru">пнуть персонажа или предмет</hint>
    <hint l="ua">вдарити персонажа або предмет</hint>
    <name l="en">kick</name>
    <name l="ru">пинок</name>
    <name l="ua">удар</name>
    <order>fight_only</order>
    <position>fight</position>
  </command>
  <dammsg mg="m">пинок</dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">fightmaster</group>
  <help id="807" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <extra l="en">football kicking</extra>
    <extra l="ru">футбол пинать</extra>
    <extra l="ua">футбол бити</extra>
    <keyword l="en">kick</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">кик</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">удар</keyword>
    <text l="en">You can kick almost anything in our world: characters, balls, swords -- give it a try!

%FMT% *%CMD%* _%VICT%_	  
%FFF% *%CMD%*

Kicks with feet and hooves can inflict additional damage in battle, and if lucky -- knock the opponent to the ground. The chance and damage depend on {hh39strength{x, {hh26size{x, {hh62body parts{x, weight of shoes or {hh670horseshoes{x and other factors. However, after an unsuccessful blow, you might lose balance. Wearing a shield helps against enemy kicks, but sometimes comes with its own risks. Warrior classes and especially agile ones will kick more effectively.

Centaurs can kick simultaneously with {hh876both hind hooves{x. Samurai and ninja, thanks to their martial arts knowledge, can inflict high damage with kicks -- when not wearing shoes.

%FMT% *%CMD%* _%OBJ%_
%FMT% *%CMD%* _%OBJ%_ _%DIR%_

Besides characters, you can try to kick any item! Some items might gradually {hh1055break{x from kicks, while others -- fly off to neighboring locations. The flight range depends on the strength and size of the item. Elastic items with equal proportions fly better than hard, heavy, and elongated ones. The chance to damage items and boots depends on their {hh201materials{x. It's better not to kick items without shoes -- especially hard ones. But with enough strength and size, you can make almost anything fly!

{CFOOTBALL!{x
If you wish, you can play football with any suitable item instead of a ball and any large {hh1024container{x instead of goals. Just kick the ball towards the goals, and if lucky, it will fly in! The chance depends on {hh37dexterity{x, strength, and other factors. If you don't specify a direction, or mess up the kick, the ball will fly wherever. Any character, including mobs, can play as a goalkeeper and try to block the shot -- the chance depends on intelligence and other parameters. Good luck!
</text>
    <text l="ru">Пинать в нашем мире можно почти что угодно: персонажей, мячи, мечи -- попробуй!

%FMT% *%CMD%* _%VICT%_	  
%FFF% *%CMD%*

Удары ногами и копытами позволяют нанести дополнительные повреждения в бою, а
при удаче -- опрокинуть противника наземь. Шанс и урон зависят от {hh39силы{x, {hh26размера{x,
{hh62частей тела{x, веса обуви или {hh670подков{x и других факторов. Однако, после неудачного
удара можно потерять равновесие. Ношение щита помогает от вражеских пинков, но
иногда чревато последствиями. У {hh28воинских классов{x и, особенно, у ловкачей пинки
сработают чаще.

Кентавры умеют пинать одновременно {hh876двумя задними копытами{x. Самураи и ниндзя
благодаря знанию боевых искусств могут наносить высокие повреждения пинками --
когда не носят обуви.

%FMT% *%CMD%* _%OBJ%_
%FMT% *%CMD%* _%OBJ%_ _%DIR%_

Кроме персонажей, можно попытаться пнуть любой предмет! От пинка некоторые вещи
могут постепенно {hh1055разрушаться{x, а некоторые -- улетать в соседние местности.
Дальность полета вещи зависит от силы и размера вещи. Эластичные вещи с равными
пропорциями летают лучше твердых, тяжелых и продолговатых. Шанс повредить вещи и
ботинки зависит от их {hh201материалов{x. Без обуви вещи лучше не пинать -- особенно,
твердые. Но при достаточной силе и размере можно заставить летать почти все!

{CФУТБОЛ!{x
При желании можно сыграть в футбол любым подходящим предметом вместо мяча и
любым крупным {hh1024контейнером{x вместо ворот. Просто пни мяч по направлению к воротам,
и при удаче он в них залетит! Шанс зависит от {hh37ловкости{x, силы и других факторов.
Если не указать направление -- ну или налажать при ударе -- мяч полетит куда
получится. Любой персонаж, включая мобов, может выступить в качестве вратаря и
попробовать отразить удар -- шанс зависит от интеллекта и других параметров.
Удачи!
</text>
    <text l="ua">У нашому світі можна бити майже що завгодно: персонажів, м'ячі, мечі -- спробуй!

%FMT% *%CMD%* _%VICT%_	  
%FFF% *%CMD%*

Удари ногами і копитами дозволяють завдати додаткових пошкоджень у бою, а
при вдачі -- звалити противника на землю. Шанс і шкода залежать від {hh39сили{x, {hh26розміру{x,
{hh62частин тіла{x, ваги взуття або {hh670підков{x та інших факторів. Проте, після невдалого
удару можна втратити рівновагу. Носіння щита допомагає від ворожих ударів, але
іноді тягне за собою наслідки. У {hh28військових класів{x і, особливо, у спритних удари
працюватимуть частіше.

Кентаври вміють бити одночасно {hh876двома задніми копитами{x. Самураї та ніндзя
завдяки знанням бойових мистецтв можуть завдавати високих пошкоджень ударами --
коли не носять взуття.

%FMT% *%CMD%* _%OBJ%_
%FMT% *%CMD%* _%OBJ%_ _%DIR%_

Крім персонажів, можна спробувати вдарити будь-який предмет! Від удару деякі речі
можуть поступово {hh1055руйнуватися{x, а деякі -- відлітати в сусідні місцевості.
Дальність польоту речі залежить від сили і розміру речі. Еластичні речі з рівними
пропорціями літають краще твердих, важких і видовжених. Шанс пошкодити речі і
взуття залежить від їхніх {hh201матеріалів{x. Без взуття речі краще не бити -- особливо,
тверді. Але при достатній силі і розмірі можна змусити літати майже все!

{CФУТБОЛ!{x
При бажанні можна зіграти в футбол будь-яким підходящим предметом замість м'яча і
будь-яким великим {hh1024контейнером{x замість воріт. Просто вдар по м'ячу в напрямку до воріт,
і при вдачі він у них залетить! Шанс залежить від {hh37спритності{x, сили та інших факторів.
Якщо не вказати напрямок, або помилитися при ударі, м'яч полетить куди
вийде. Будь-який персонаж, включаючи мобів, може виступити як воротар і
спробувати відбити удар -- шанс залежить від інтелекту та інших параметрів.
Удачі!
</text>
  </help>
  <mob>
    <bonus>10</bonus>
    <dice>3</dice>
    <offense>kick</offense>
    <professional>true</professional>
  </mob>
  <move>20</move>
  <name l="en">kick</name>
  <name l="ru">пинок</name>
  <name l="ua">удар</name>
  <raceBonuses registry="race">centaur</raceBonuses>
</skill>