<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <affect type="DefaultAffectHandler">
    <removeCharSelf>Ты снова можешь попытаться пройти обряд очищения.</removeCharSelf>
  </affect>
  <beats>12</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="samurai">
      <level>25</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <command type="DefaultSkillCommand">
    <argtype>char_self</argtype>
    <cat></cat>
    <name l="en">misogi</name>
    <name l="ru">мисоги</name>
    <name l="ua">місогі</name>
    <order>never</order>
    <position>rest</position>
  </command>
  <dammsg mg="m"></dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">adventure</group>
  <help id="211" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%CMD%*

{x  Misogi is a purification ritual aimed at achieving renewal. In the heart of nature, near bodies of water, rivers, and waterfalls, a samurai can perform the ritual washing, and if successful, enters a trance during which the six elements comprising the being, the five senses, and the consciousness are cleansed and renewed.

{x  A special form of misogi is considered to be {hh743hara-kiri{x, the meaning of which is to wash away shame with blood.
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%CMD%*

{x  Мисоги представляет из себя ритуал очищения для достижения обновления.
На лоне природы, вблизи водоёмов, рек и водопадов, самурай может совершить
обряд омовения, и в случае успеха впадёт в транс, во время которого будут
очищены и обновлены шесть элементов из которых состоит существо, пять чувств 
и сознание.

{x  Особой формой мисоги считается {hh743харакири{x, смысл которого в смывании 
кровью позора.
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%CMD%*

{x  Місогі -- це ритуал очищення для досягнення оновлення. На лоні природи, поблизу водойм, річок і водоспадів, самурай може здійснити обряд омовіння, і в разі успіху впаде в транс, під час якого будуть очищені і оновлені шість елементів, з яких складається істота, п&apos;ять відчуттів і свідомість.

{x  Особливою формою місогі вважається {hh743харакірі{x, сенс якого у змиванні сорому кров&apos;ю.
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>40</mana>
  <move>100</move>
  <name l="en">misogi</name>
  <name l="ru">мисоги</name>
  <name l="ua">місогі</name>
</skill>
