<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <affect type="DefaultAffectHandler">
    <removeCharSelf>Твоя трансформация завершается, и ты возвращаешься в свою обычную форму.</removeCharSelf>
  </affect>
  <align>neutral evil</align>
  <beats>18</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="druid">
      <level>20</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <command type="DefaultSkillCommand">
    <aliases l="en">shapeshift form</aliases>
    <aliases l="ru">форма</aliases>
    <aliases l="ua">форма</aliases>
    <argtype>string</argtype>
    <cat></cat>
    <hint l="en">Druids can transform into a bear, wolverine, or lizard</hint>
    <hint l="ru">(друиды) превратиться в медведя, росомаху или ящера</hint>
    <hint l="ua">(друїди) перетворитися на ведмедя, росомаху або ящірку</hint>
    <name l="en">shape</name>
    <name l="ru">перекинуться</name>
    <name l="ua">перекинутися</name>
    <order>player_only</order>
    <position>fight</position>
  </command>
  <dammsg mg="m"></dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">nature</group>
  <help id="185" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <extra l="en">form bear lizard wolverine</extra>
    <extra l="ru">форма медведь ящер росомаха</extra>
    <extra l="ua">форма ведмідь ящірка росомаха</extra>
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%CMD%* _bear_
%FMT% *%CMD%* _lizard_
%FMT% *%CMD%* _wolverine_

During combat, druids can use a special ritual that allows them to
enter a trance and assume the form of one of the sacred animals until the {hh184channeling{x
is interrupted. A druid can use this ability no more than three times a day,
so it's not worth interrupting the ritual unnecessarily.

During the transformation, the druid retains all equipment worn, except for weapons,
shield, and items held in hand -- because sharp claws grow instead of fingers.
Like other druid skills, the transformation depends on the druid's rank in the circle.
The lizard form helps the druid survive better, while the bear and especially the wolverine form
will allow to tear the opponent to shreds in seconds.
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%CMD%* _медведь_
%FMT% *%CMD%* _ящер_
%FMT% *%CMD%* _росомаха_

Во время боя друиды могут использовать специальный ритуал, который позволяет им
входить в транс и принимать форму одного из сакральных животных пока {hh184ченнелинг{x
не прервется. Использовать это умение друид может не более трех раз в день,
поэтому не стоит прерывать ритуал понапрасну.

Во время трансформации друид сохраняет всю экипировку надетой, кроме оружия,
щита и зажатого в руке -- ведь вместо пальцев у него отрастают острые когти. 
Как и другие умения друида, трансформация зависит от ранга друида в круге.
Форма ящера помогает друиду лучше выживать, а формы медведя и особенно росомахи
позволят разорвать противника на клочки в считанные секунды.
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%CMD%* _ведмідь_
%FMT% *%CMD%* _ящірка_
%FMT% *%CMD%* _росомаха_

Під час бою друїди можуть використовувати спеціальний ритуал, що дозволяє їм
увійти в транс і прийняти форму одного зі сакральних тварин, поки {hh184ченнелинг{x
не перерветься. Використовувати це вміння друїд може не більше трьох разів на день,
тому не варто переривати ритуал даремно.

Під час трансформації друїд зберігає всю екіпіровку, крім зброї,
щита і предметів у руці - адже замість пальців у нього виростають гострі кігті.
Як і інші вміння друїда, трансформація залежить від рангу друїда в колі.
Форма ящірки допомагає друїду краще виживати, а форма ведмедя і особливо росомахи
дозволять розірвати супротивника на шматки за кілька секунд.
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>40</mana>
  <move>80</move>
  <name l="en">shapeshift</name>
  <name l="ru">перекинуться</name>
  <name l="ua">перекинутися</name>
</skill>