<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <affect type="DefaultAffectHandler">
    <cancelled>true</cancelled>
    <dispelled>true</dispelled>
    <removeCharOthers>Движения %1$C2 становятся быстрее.</removeCharOthers>
    <removeCharSelf>Твои движения приобретают прежнюю быстроту и легкость.</removeCharSelf>
  </affect>
  <beats>12</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="cleric">
      <level>38</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="necromancer">
      <level>29</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="paladin">
      <level>28</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="vampire">
      <level>28</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="warlock">
      <level>23</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
    <node name="witch">
      <level>28</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <dammsg mg="m"></dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">maladictions</group>
  <help id="705" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%VICT%_

This spell significantly slows the target's metabolism and reaction speed.
Under the effect of slow, the target will deal fewer attacks in combat and will evade
enemy hits worse, with all skill delays increasing. Many combat skills work worse and less frequently under slow.

Slowed metabolism also has its pleasant sides: your health and mana will
recover faster, and {hh837poison{x will spread through the veins more slowly.
And when the slow effect wears off, your body will be filled with {hh99combat enthusiasm{x for one {hh16combat round{x.

The {hh739speed{x and slow effects cancel each other out. For instance, if
you cast speed on yourself over slow, the slow effect will wear off.
And if in such a situation you wear an item with speed, the slow effect will
still remain in the {hh997list{x, but won't do anything harmful anymore.
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%VICT%_

Это заклинание сильно замедляет метаболизм и скорость реакции цели.
Под воздействием замедления цель будет наносить меньше атак в бою и хуже
избегать вражеских ударов, а все задержки от умений увеличатся. Многие боевые
умения работают хуже и реже под замедлением.

Замедленный метаболизм имеет и приятные стороны: твои очки здоровья и маны будут
восстанавливаться быстрее, а {hh837яд{x будет медленнее распространяться по жилам.
А когда замедление пройдет, твое тело нальется {hh99боевым задором{x на один {hh16боевой раунд{x.

Аффекты {hh739ускорения{x и замедления отменяют действие друг друга. Например, если
наложить на себя ускорение поверх замедления, то аффект замедления спадет.
А если в такой ситуации надеть вещь с ускорением, то аффект замедления будет
по-прежнему висеть в {hh997списке{x, но ничего плохого уже не сделает.
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%SPELL%* _%VICT%_

Це заклинання значно уповільнює метаболізм і швидкість реакції цілі.
Під впливом уповільнення ціль завдаватиме менше атак у бою і гірше
ухилятися від ворожих ударів, а всі затримки від умінь збільшаться. Багато бойових
умінь працюють гірше і рідше під уповільненням.

Уповільнений метаболізм має і приємні сторони: твої очки здоров'я і мани будуть
відновлюватися швидше, а {hh837отрута{x повільніше поширюватиметься по жилах.
А коли уповільнення пройде, твоє тіло насититься {hh99бойовим азартом{x на один {hh16бойовий раунд{x.

Афекти {hh739прискорення{x та уповільнення скасовують дію одне одного. Наприклад, якщо
накласти на себе прискорення поверх уповільнення, то афект уповільнення зникне.
А якщо в такій ситуації одягти річ із прискоренням, то афект уповільнення буде
як і раніше висіти в {hh997списку{x, але нічого поганого вже не зробить.
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>40</mana>
  <mob>
    <professional>true</professional>
  </mob>
  <name l="en">slow</name>
  <name l="ru">замедление</name>
  <name l="ua">уповільнення</name>
  <spell type="DefaultSpell">
    <damflags>water</damflags>
    <damtype>drowning</damtype>
    <flags>magic prayer</flags>
    <position>fight</position>
    <ranged>false</ranged>
    <target>char_room</target>
    <tier>3</tier>
    <type>offensive</type>
  </spell>
</skill>