<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <beats>18</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="warrior">
      <level>40</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <command type="DefaultSkillCommand">
    <argtype>char_fight</argtype>
    <cat>class</cat>
    <hint l="en">Strike the head with a fist or weapon (warriors)</hint>
    <hint l="ru">(воины) врезать по голове кулаком или оружием</hint>
    <hint l="ua">(воїни) вдарити по голові кулаком або зброєю</hint>
    <name l="en">smash</name>
    <name l="ru">врезать</name>
    <name l="ua">вдарити</name>
    <order>player_only</order>
    <position>fight</position>
  </command>
  <dammsg mg="m">заход в бубен</dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">fightmaster</group>
  <help id="700" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <extra l="en">'punch in the face' 'bop on the head'</extra>
    <extra l="ru">&apos;удар в лицо&apos; &apos;заход в бубен&apos;</extra>
    <extra l="ua">'удар в обличчя' 'заход в бубен'</extra>
    <keyword l="en">smash</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">врезать</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">вдарити</keyword>
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%CMD%* _%VICT%_

Warriors - and many other creatures in the world - love to solve problems with a firm blow
to the opponent's head. A well-aimed bop on the head deals significant damage, 
{hh120stuns{x and slightly immobilizes the opponent, and can force an airborne enemy to
land.

The success of the attack and its effect depend on the strength, size, length, and weight of your weapon or
plate gloves (if you decide to engage in hand-to-hand combat), as well as other factors.

When striking with a weapon or glove, their condition will worsen based on
the damage inflicted on the opponent.

You can also take {hh95a bottle{x or other appropriate vessel and smash it over
the opponent's head in battle - with an effect similar to this skill.

%SA% %H% {hh676knock down{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%CMD%* _%VICT%_

Воины -- и многие другие существа в мире -- любят решать проблемы крепким ударом
в голову противника. Хорошо взвешенный заход в бубен наносит серьезный урон, 
{hh120ошеломляет{x и слегка обездвиживает противника, а летучего врага может
заставить приземлиться.

Успех атаки и ее эффект зависят от силы, размера, длины и веса твоего оружия или
латных рукавиц (если решить заняться рукоприкладством), а также других факторов.

При ударе оружием или перчаткой их состояние ухудшится в зависимости от
нанесенного противнику урона.

Можно также взять в руки {hh95бутылку{x или другой подходящий сосуд и разбить ее об
голову противника в бою -- с эффектом, аналогичным этому умению.

%SA% %H% {hh676сбить{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%CMD%* _%VICT%_

Воїни -- і багато інших істот у світі -- люблять вирішувати проблеми міцним ударом
по голові противника. Добре прорахований захід в бубен завдає серйозної шкоди, 
{hh120оглушає{x і трохи знерухомлює противника, а летючого ворога може
змусити приземлитися.

Успіх атаки і її ефект залежать від сили, розміру, довжини і ваги твоєї зброї або
пластинчастих рукавичок (якщо вирішити зайнятися рукопашним боєм), а також інших факторів.

При ударі зброєю або рукавичкою їх стан погіршиться в залежності від
завданої противнику шкоди.

Можна також взяти {hh95пляшку{x або іншу підходящу ємність і розбити її об
голову противника у бою -- з ефектом, схожим на цю вміння.

%SA% %H% {hh676збити{x
</text>
  </help>
  <mob>
    <bonus>10</bonus>
    <dice>3</dice>
    <professional>true</professional>
  </mob>
  <move>40</move>
  <name l="en">smash</name>
  <name l="ru">врезать</name>
  <name l="ua">вдарити</name>
</skill>