<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <affect type="DefaultAffectHandler">
    <removeCharSelf>Рана на твоей шее затягивается.</removeCharSelf>
  </affect>
  <beats>12</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="vampire">
      <level>10</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <command type="SKILL(bite)">
    <argtype>undef</argtype>
    <cat>class</cat>
    <hint l="en">Bite the victim's neck (vampires).</hint>
    <hint l="ru">(вампиры) укусить жертву за шею</hint>
    <hint l="ua">(вампіри) вкусити жертву за шию</hint>
    <name l="en">bite</name>
    <name l="ru">кусать</name>
    <name l="ua">кусати</name>
    <order>player_only</order>
    <position>stand</position>
  </command>
  <dammsg mg="m">укус вампира</dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">vampiric</group>
  <help id="626" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <text l="en">Vampires do not consume regular food and are unfamiliar with thirst and hunger: they are tormented only by {rthirst for blood{x. This can be satisfied by drinking blood from the necks of victims or simply by killing them.

%FMT% *bite* _victim_

To bite a victim, you must first put them to sleep with {hh769vampiric touch{x.
If the vampire is very hungry, he bites into the victim's throat with all his might, thereby waking her from sleep and initiating a fight. Otherwise, there is a chance not to awaken the victim and just make two neat little holes through which you can {hh697drink blood{x.

The bite restores the vampire's health and mana.
Vampire bite wounds can fester with some probability.

%SA% %H% {hh539bloodletting{x, {hh836vampire form{x
</text>
    <text l="ru">Вампиры не питаются обычной пищей, им незнакома жажда и голод: их терзает
только {rжажда крови{x. Ее можно удовлетворить, выпивая кровь из шеи жертв или
просто убивая их.

%FMT% *кусать* _жертва_

Чтобы укусить жертву, ее надо сначала усыпить {hh769вампирским прикосновением{x.
Если вампир очень голоден, он со всей силы впивается в горло жертвы, тем самым
пробуждая ее ото сна и начиная битву. В противном случае, есть шанс не разбудить
жертву, а сделать всего две  аккуратные дырочки, через которые можно {hh697пить кровь{x. 

Укус восстанавливает вампиру здоровье и ману.
Раны от укуса вампира с некоторой вероятностью могут {hh541загноиться{x.

%SA% %H% {hh539кровопускание{x, {hh836форма вампира{x
</text>
    <text l="ua">Вампіри не харчуються звичайною їжею, їм невідомі спрага та голод: їх мучить
лише {rспрага до крові{x. Її можна задовольнити, випиваючи кров з шиї жертв або
просто вбиваючи їх.

%FMT% *кусати* _жертва_

Щоб вкусити жертву, її потрібно спершу приспати {hh769вампірським дотиком{x.
Якщо вампір дуже голодний, він з усієї сили впивається в горло жертви, тим самим
пробуджуючи її від сну і починаючи битву. В іншому випадку, є шанс не розбудити
жертву, а зробити всього дві акуратні дірочки, через які можна {hh697пити кров{x. 

Укус відновлює вампіру здоров'я та ману.
Рани від укусу вампіра з певною ймовірністю можуть {hh541загноїтися{x.

%SA% %H% {hh539кровопускання{x, {hh836форма вампіра{x
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>40</mana>
  <mob>
    <bonus>20</bonus>
    <dice>2</dice>
    <professional>true</professional>
  </mob>
  <move>40</move>
  <name l="en">vampiric bite</name>
  <name l="ru">укус вампира</name>
  <name l="ua">укус вампіра</name>
</skill>