<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<skill type="GenericSkill">
  <beats>12</beats>
  <classes>
    <node name="ninja">
      <level>18</level>
      <maximum>100</maximum>
      <rating>1</rating>
    </node>
  </classes>
  <command type="SKILL(vanish)">
    <argtype>undef</argtype>
    <cat>class</cat>
    <hint l="en">(ninja) disappear in a cloud of smoke</hint>
    <hint l="ru">(ниндзи) скрыться в облаке дыма</hint>
    <hint l="ua">(ніндзя) зникнути у хмарі диму</hint>
    <name l="en">vanish</name>
    <name l="ru">исчезнуть</name>
    <name l="ua">зникнути</name>
    <position>fight</position>
  </command>
  <dammsg mg="m"></dammsg>
  <group registry="skillGroup">adventure</group>
  <help id="742" level="-1" type="SkillHelp">
    <keyword l="en">kidnap abduction</keyword>
    <keyword l="ru">похитить похищение</keyword>
    <keyword l="ua">викрасти викрадення</keyword>
    <text l="en">%FMT% *%SKILL%*

Using special chemicals, ninjas can create a bright flash in the room to distract 
attention and quickly disappear, moving to a random room within the same zone. 
You can vanish right from the fight, but this will be harder to execute. 
There are some rooms you can't reach this way, and conversely, some places 
from which you can't disappear.

%FMT% *%SKILL%* _%VICT%_

With the same trick, ninjas can =abduct= their victims away from loving pets, 
{hh15followers{x and mercenaries for one-on-one encounters. Success depends on the 
{hh37agility{x of the ninja, the {hh39strength{x and the {hh26size of the victim{x, 
as well as other factors.
</text>
    <text l="ru">%FMT% *%SKILL%*

С помощью специальных химикатов ниндзя умеют создавать яркую вспышку в комнате 
для отвлечения внимания и быстро исчезать, перемещаясь в случайную комнату в
этой же зоне. Можно скрыться прямо из боя, но провернуть это будет сложнее.
В некоторые комнаты таких образом нельзя попасть и, наоборот, из некоторых мест
нельзя исчезнуть.

%FMT% *%SKILL%* _%VICT%_

С помощью этого же трюка ниндзя умеют =похищать= своих жертв от любящих петов,
{hh15последователей{x и наемников, чтобы разделаться с ними один на один. Успех зависит
от {hh37ловкости{x ниндзя, {hh39силы{x и {hh26размера жертвы{x, а также других факторов.
</text>
    <text l="ua">%FMT% *%SKILL%*

За допомогою спеціальних хімікатів ніндзя вміють створювати яскравий спалах у кімнаті
для відволікання уваги і швидко зникати, переміщуючись у випадкову кімнату в
цій же зоні. Можна зникнути прямо з бою, але провернути це буде важче.
У деякі кімнати таким чином не можна потрапити і, навпаки, з деяких місць
не можна зникнути.

%FMT% *%SKILL%* _%VICT%_

Завдяки цьому ж трюку ніндзя вміють =викрадати= своїх жертв від люблячих петов,
{hh15послідовників{x і найманців, щоб розібратися з ними один на один. Успіх залежить
від {hh37спритності{x ніндзя, {hh39сили{x і {hh26розміру жертви{x, а також інших факторів.
</text>
  </help>
  <mana>20</mana>
  <move>100</move>
  <name l="en">vanish</name>
  <name l="ru">исчезновение</name>
  <name l="ua">зникнення</name>
</skill>